<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:blogChannel="http://backend.userland.com/blogChannelModule" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Daily Kos</title>
<link>http://www.dailykos.com</link>
<description>News Community Action</description>
<copyright>Copyright 2005 - Steal what you want</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 04:55:33 UTC</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 04:55:33 UTC</lastBuildDate>
<managingEditor>Daily Kos rss@dailykos.com (Daily Kos)</managingEditor>
<webMaster>Daily Kos rss@dailykos.com (Daily Kos)</webMaster>

<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/dailykos/index" /><feedburner:info uri="dailykos/index" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site, subject to copyright and fair use.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
<title>Open thread for night owls: The 'inadequate' defense budget? Compared with when? With whom?</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/a40QUS31wfY/-Open-thread-for-night-owls-The-inadequate-defense-budget-Compared-with-when-With-whom</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/8694/large/Tyto-Albas-sawhet-owl.jpeg?1350856561" alt="Night Owls" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
If all national security-related spending requested for fiscal year 2015 were taken into account the U.S. defense budget would be more than a trillion dollars. The budget discussed below is Pentagon spending only and does not include many items that a reasonable reading of "defense" would encompass, including care and maintenance of the nation's nuclear arsenal, various elements of caring for veterans of past wars and the interest on money borrowed to pay for those past wars. Even so, the defense budget, though it has declined since 2009 (mostly due to less spending in Iraq and Afghanistan) is gargantuan, far, far higher when adjusted for inflation than it was during the Cold War.
&lt;p&gt;Winslow Wheeler writes &lt;a href="http://www.pogo.org/our-work/straus-military-reform-project/defense-budget/2014/an-inadequate-defense-budget.html"&gt;An Inadequate Defense Budget? Compared to Whom? Compared to When?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width="96%" align="center" style="background-color:rgb(249,246,234);border_collapse: collapse; border: 1px dashed black;" defang_cellpadding="5%"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Many Republicans and numerous Democrats, especially on the House and Senate Armed Services Committees, have been characterizing the US defense budget as inadequate. They propose to release the Pentagon from the statutory spending caps set by the Budget Control Act of 2011 and its "sequestration," which would keep some, but not all, Pentagon spending in the neighborhood of $500 billion, annually, for several years. The Joint Chiefs of Staff, the Secretary of Defense and any other Pentagon official near a microphone have been cheering them on.
&lt;p&gt;There is a major mismatch between the actual size of the US defense budget and the characterization of inadequacy given to it. &amp;nbsp;The enormity of the US defense budget, even under sequestration, is readily apparent in both relative and absolute terms.That we today declare ourselves inadequately funded at a far higher level of spending than we budgeted against a much larger, much more hostile threat is remarkable. &amp;nbsp;More money in the face of lesser threats is not quite the penury so many claim. [...]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79800/large/dod-budget-1945-2015-575px-1.jpg?1398386121" alt="budget" width="550" height="335" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;This graph shows the Pentagon's post-World War Two budgets in dollars adjusted for inflation. Note how today's so-called "inadequate" spending compares to average annual spending during the Cold War (the dashed, horizontal line, which occurs at the $355 billion level).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
That we today declare ourselves inadequately funded at a far higher level of spending than we budgeted against a much larger, much more hostile threat is remarkable. More money in the face of lesser threats is not quite the penury so many claim.
&lt;p&gt;Second, we should listen closely when today's political and military leaders asset they cannot manage at the spending levels they face under the Budget Control Act. They are quite correct to say they are unable to do so. Recent history proves that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Our military hardware is outrageously expensive, but much of it is a step backwards in performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Since the mid-1990s Congress has increased money for DOD pay and benefits but huge portions of it has been for indiscriminant, across-the-board military pay raises, double pensions for many armed service retirees, bigger benefits for the survivors of World War Two veterans and much else that is intended to buy off political constituencies rather than address real security problems, let alone the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Under the full-on spigot of the post-9/11 era, the Pentagon's civilian and military leadership has bloated itself to historically unprecedented levels of overhead, including military staff, civilian government employees and contracted-out personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• In their ultimate malfeasance, none of our national security leaders have bothered to fundamentally understand the dimension of the overspending problem as the Pentagon remains unaudited and un-auditable twenty-four years after the passage of the Chief Financial Officers Act of 1990-intended to require the Pentagon to understand and report what it does with its money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship of US defense spending to that of presumed threat nations and the girth of contemporary defense spending compared to a time of greater threat does not call into question the adequacy of the size of today's US defense budget; it calls into question the competence of current US political and military leadership, both in the Pentagon and in Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2006/04/24/204743/-We-Need-You-to-Save-the-Internet"&gt;Blast from the Past&lt;/a&gt;. At Daily Kos on this date in &lt;b&gt;2006&lt;/b&gt;—&lt;i&gt;We Need You to Save the Internet!&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width="96%" align="center" style="background-color:rgb(249,246,234);border_collapse: collapse; border: 1px dashed black;" defang_cellpadding="5%"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sounds hyperbolic, no? It's not. The House Commerce Committee is likely to vote as early as Wednesday on legislation that would essentially hand over the keys to the Internet to the giant telcos, AT&amp;amp;T, Verizon, Time Warner, and Comcast.
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to imagine that the Internet, that vast free-flowing world of entertainment, enlightenment, education, and interaction could be fettered, but under this legislation it very well could be. Internet service provision in the U.S. is covered by telecommunications law, and has operated under the idea of "network neutrality." In it's early years, telephone companies provided most Web service, and carried most of the traffic. Because of the nature of laws regulating phone service, Web traffic was handled just like phone traffic, each "call" being equal. That means every page you surf to on the Internet is served up just like any other, as far as your ISP is concerned. You can go from Amazon.com to Aunt Harriet's family history blog equally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what's at stake with this legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width="96%" align="center" style="background-color:rgb(400,300,200);border_collapse: collapse; border: 1px dashed black;" defang_cellpadding="5%"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The nation's largest telephone and cable companies— including AT&amp;amp;T, Verizon, Comcast and Time Warner—want to be Internet gatekeepers, deciding which Web sites go fast or slow and which won't load at all.
&lt;p&gt;They want to tax content providers to guarantee speedy delivery of their data. They want to discriminate in favor of their own search engines, Internet phone services, and streaming video—while slowing down or blocking their competitors. ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Internet, consumers are in ultimate control—deciding between content, applications and services available anywhere, no matter who owns the network. There's no middleman. But without net neutrality, the Internet will look more like cable TV. Network owners will decide which channels, content and applications are available; consumers will have to choose from their menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Wolfrum"&gt;Tweet of the Day&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Wolfrum/status/459371330430054400"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/444095453341048832/Irc24DLN_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I got 100% smarter once I decided that any fact that disagrees with my opinions is a lie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/Wolfrum"&gt;@Wolfrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2800002/height/200/width/250/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="200" width="250" scrolling="no" defang_allowfullscreen="" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
On &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294370/-Daily-Kos-Radio-s-KITM-podcast-Bundy-implosion-Occupy-vs-Moral-Mondays-Are-we-an-oligarchy-yet"&gt;today's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show&lt;/a&gt;, Cliven Bundy, ladies and gentlemen! &lt;strong&gt;Greg Dworkin&lt;/strong&gt; parses Kaiser polling on healthcare in four southern states, and then sets the agenda for the day with Harold Pollock's "Pre-Occupied with Medicaid Expansion." Did Occupy "accomplish" anything? Was it a thing that could be measured by that metric? Is the drive for concrete results what sets the "Moral Mondays" movement apart from it? &lt;em&gt;Are&lt;/em&gt; they set apart from one another? Also: NC Gop Senate field all deny climate change. And about that "US is an oligarchy" thing, let's take another look at that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294324/-High-Impact-Posts-April-23-2014"&gt;High Impact Posts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1290170/-Top-Comments-the-O-Winston-Link-edition"&gt;Top Comments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=a40QUS31wfY:IMoTU8rmKaM:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/a40QUS31wfY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Meteor Blades)</author>
<category>Defense budget</category>
<category>Open Thread for Night Owls</category>
<category>Pentagon</category>
<category>Winslow Wheeler</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294476</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 03:30:16 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294476/-Open-thread-for-night-owls-The-inadequate-defense-budget-Compared-with-when-With-whom</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Economics Daily Digest: Legal challenges are changing the intern economy</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/iZzxHTqgQxk/-Economics-Daily-Digest-Legal-challenges-are-changing-the-intern-economy</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/12380/large/EconomicsDailyDigest_(1).jpg?1355365637" alt="Economics Daily Digest by the Roosevelt Institute banner" width="550" height="100" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By Rachel Goldfarb, originally published on &lt;a href="http://www.nextnewdeal.net/daily-digest-april-25-legal-challenges-are-changing-intern-economy"&gt;Next New Deal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://rooseveltinstitute.us1.list-manage2.com/subscribe?u=5044841afea7ba83dc11db61f&amp;amp;id=e4428ba350"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to receive the Daily Digest via email.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Colleges, Employers Rethink Internship Policies&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304049904579517671151334870?mg=reno64-wsj"&gt;WSJ&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel Feintzeig and Melissa Korn report that while unpaid internship lawsuits work through the courts, many companies are changing their programs by adding pay or eliminating internships altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Losing Their Unemployment Benefits Didn't Help These People Find Work&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/04/22/unemployment-extension_n_5192990.html"&gt;HuffPo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam Stein and Arthur Delaney find that without long-term unemployment insurance, which Congress failed to extend in December, workers' job searches didn't change, but their ability to pay the bills did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Your Government Owes You a Job&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/179476/your-government-owes-you-job?utm_content=buffere0c16&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer"&gt;The Nation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raúl Carrillo calls for a job guarantee as a matter of justice and economic security for all. He says such a program would have similar costs to current anti-poverty programs, but provide more opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Here’s Why This City’s Businesses Love Its Paid Sick Days Law&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/economy/2014/04/23/3429827/seattle-paid-sick-leave-audit/"&gt;ThinkProgress&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bryce Covert looks at a new audit of Seattle's paid sick leave law, which went into effect in September 2012. People are happy: costs were lower than expected, and business, wage, and job growth were all up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Rich Live Longer: So How Much Money 'Buys' 1 More Year of Life?&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2014/04/how-much-do-you-have-to-earn-to-buy-1-more-year-of-life/361078/"&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek Thompson uses data on life expectancy and income to determine the cost of an extra year of life. He says the actual numbers here are less important than the fact that inequality has life-and-death costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Politicians from the Hungriest Counties Voted to Cut Food Stamps&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.msnbc.com/msnbc/humphreys-zavala-americas-hungriest-counties"&gt;MSNBC&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The congressmen, both Democrats, claim to have voted for the recent Farm Bill that cut food stamps in some states as a compromise on larger cuts, says Ned Resnikoff, but the GOP strategy will keep chipping away at the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;F.C.C., in a Shift, Backs Fast Lanes for Web Traffic&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/technology/fcc-new-net-neutrality-rules.html?smid=tw-share&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Communications Commission announced new proposed rules that allow companies to pay Internet service providers for faster access to their content, reports Edward Wyatt. Some call this the end of net neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=iZzxHTqgQxk:S0cL8k2eNuY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/iZzxHTqgQxk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Roosevelt Institute)</author>
<category>Economic Inequality</category>
<category>Economy</category>
<category>Jobs</category>
<category>Labor</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294261</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 12:07:18 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294261/-Economics-Daily-Digest-Legal-challenges-are-changing-the-intern-economy</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Wage theft hits software engineers as well as fast food workers</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/K1OW5qi6CDQ/-Wage-theft-hits-software-engineers-as-well-as-fast-food-workers</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79304/small/snapshot-wage-theft-04-02-2014a.png?1398181526" alt="Bar graph showing value of wage theft in 2012 -- $280 million -- vs. value of street, bank, gas station, and convenience store robberies -- $139 million." width="250" height="355" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
A &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; editorial points out that software engineers and fast food workers are &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/22/opinion/wage-theft-across-the-board.html?_r=0"&gt;more similar than we might think&lt;/a&gt;: Both groups are affected by wage theft.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;In the days ahead, a settlement is expected in the antitrust lawsuit pitting 64,613 software engineers against Google, Apple, Intel and Adobe. The engineers say they lost up to $3 billion in wages from 2005-9, when the companies colluded in a scheme not to solicit one another’s employees. The collusion, according to the engineers, kept their pay lower than it would have been had the companies actually competed for talent. [...]
&lt;p&gt;The case essentially alleges white-collar wage theft. The engineers were not victimized by the usual violations of labor law, but by improper hiring practices against their interests. The result, however, was the same: Money that would have flowed to workers in the form of wages went instead into corporate coffers and from there to executives and shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The software engineers presumably made a decent living despite being cheated by their employers, which can't be said of fast food workers forced to work off the clock or not being paid overtime when they work more than 40 hours a week. But their case highlights something middle-class Americans would do well to remember: The corporate race to the bottom on wages and working conditions is coming for you, too. In fact, it probably already has, in the form of the decline of the pension and stagnant wages except at the very top. And when you fail to give a damn about the fast food worker, unless they trot out &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/the-medias-strange-approach-to-low-wage-workers/2014/03/19/a5155256-aefe-11e3-a49e-76adc9210f19_story.html"&gt;a convincing enough tale&lt;/a&gt; of noble poverty or dismiss the public worker's struggle for the pension they earned with "well, I don't have a pension, why should a janitor?" or scoff at the idea that software engineers and fast food workers share a common interest against the massive corporations that employ them, you're inviting that race to the bottom to hit you sooner and harder.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=K1OW5qi6CDQ:DiEL-6yt0Ds:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/K1OW5qi6CDQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>KETI program</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Wage Theft</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293765</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 16:02:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293765/-Wage-theft-hits-software-engineers-as-well-as-fast-food-workers</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>A year after Texas fertilizer explosion, safety regulations are no stronger</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/8tK6xPUyYKg/-A-year-after-Texas-fertilizer-explosion-safety-regulations-are-no-stronger</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/28741/large/RTXYQA4.jpg?1366388902" alt="The remains of a fertilizer plant burn after an explosion at the plant in the town of West, near Waco, Texas early April 18, 2013. The deadly explosion ripped through the fertilizer plant late on Wednesday, injuring more than 100 people, leveling dozens o" width="550" height="315" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
A year after a fertilizer plant explosion in West, Texas, killed 14 and destroyed a good chunk of the town, the U.S. Chemical Safety Board has released preliminary findings from an investigation that &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/23/us/lack-of-oversight-and-regulations-blamed-in-texas-chemical-explosion.html?ref=us&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;should serve as a major wake-up call&lt;/a&gt; for how the United States—and Texas in particular—regulates dangerous chemicals:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Tiny white pellets of ammonium nitrate were stored in a wooden warehouse in wooden bins, inside a building without a sprinkler system. No federal regulations exist preventing a company from storing the chemical in such a way. The volunteer firefighters who rushed to the plant to fight a fire that broke out there before the explosion were largely unaware of the dangers of ammonium nitrate, and a local emergency planning committee had not adopted an emergency response plan for the plant. Even if they had, Texas has no statewide fire code that would have established a minimum set of standards to hold industrial sites accountable for the safe handling of chemicals.
&lt;p&gt;Ammonium nitrate is stored at more than 1,300 facilities around the country, but there are no zoning regulations at any level of government to prevent such plants from being located near residential areas, officials said on Tuesday. Other countries have more rigorous standards covering both the storage of the chemical and the proximity to other buildings. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agency officials said that no other single chemical has caused more widespread harm to the public in preventable accidents than ammonium nitrate. Nevertheless, fertilizer-grade ammonium nitrate is not classified as an explosive in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Want to bet that if the question was a Middle Eastern guy buying a whole lot of fertilizer-grade ammonium nitrate, the feds would not be like "it's not an explosive, nothing to see here"? But when it comes to the safety of homes and schools next to fertilizer plants, pfft, whatever.
&lt;p&gt;And over the past year, &lt;a href="http://www.aflcio.org/Blog/Political-Action-Legislation/One-Year-After-15-Died-in-Preventable-Texas-Fertilizer-Blast-Safety-Rules-Stalled"&gt;nothing has changed&lt;/a&gt; to prevent future such explosions in Texas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=8tK6xPUyYKg:I49F87sPBLw:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/8tK6xPUyYKg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Regulations</category>
<category>Texas</category>
<category>West Texas</category>
<category>Workplace Safety</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293857</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 20:41:30 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293857/-A-year-after-Texas-fertilizer-explosion-safety-regulations-are-no-stronger</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Crist: 'Obamacare is great'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/mnKnDdiHqNg/-Crist-Obamacare-is-great</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/68304/large/RTR38DBF.jpg?1391791482" alt="Former Governor of Florida Charlie Crist answers a question during the University of Southern California's Schwarzenegger Institute for State and Global Policy inaugural Symposium in Los Angeles, California, September 24, 2012. REUTERS/Gus Ruelas (UNITED " width="550" height="391" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Pundits everywhere are going to have to hang up the supposed narrative of the cycle—that Democrats are running scared on Obamacare. It's just not happening. From Sens. &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293835/-Landrieu-on-Obamacare-The-benefits-that-people-have-received-are-worth-fighting-for"&gt;Mary Landrieu&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/11/1291254/-This-exceptional-new-ad-from-Alaska-shows-how-Democrats-everywhere-should-be-running-on-Obamacare"&gt;Mark Begich&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293757/-Running-on-Obamacare-in-nbsp-Pennsylvania"&gt;Rep. Allyson Schwartz&lt;/a&gt;, Democrats are on offense on the Affordable Care Act. But Florida's Charlie Crist, running to get the governor's seat back, &lt;a href="http://www.miamiherald.com/2014/04/22/4073895/crist-wont-back-down-from-health.html"&gt;beats them all&lt;/a&gt; in his enthusiasm for the law.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Crist appeared at the Capital Tiger Bay Club and almost immediately brought up the attack ads being run by the political committee backing Scott's re-election, which show video of Crist talking about the health care overhaul and saying, "I think it's been great."
&lt;p&gt;"I'm going to tell you what's great. 'Obamacare's' great," Crist said one minute into his 29-minute speech. "My opponent has spent about $6 million showing me say what's great ... Affordable health care—I think it's incredibly important and I don't back away from it, I do support it because it is great."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
That's pretty smart in a state where &lt;a href="http://www.theledger.com/article/20140223/NEWS/140229653"&gt;about 1 million&lt;/a&gt; people are denied health care, where &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/09/1290855/-Meet-the-late-Charlene-Dill-sentenced-to-death-by-Republican-Obamcare-obstruction"&gt;they are dying&lt;/a&gt; prematurely because of Republican politics. Out of spite.
&lt;p&gt;Yes, for the people who now, finally, have health insurance they can afford and that can't be taken away from them, Obamacare is great. That's a message no Democrat should be afraid to deliver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=mnKnDdiHqNg:QiEMSJfuzyU:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/mnKnDdiHqNg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Charlie Crist</category>
<category>FL-Gov</category>
<category>Florida</category>
<category>Health Insurance</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294104</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 19:51:40 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294104/-Crist-Obamacare-is-great</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>NFL cheerleaders join the fight against wage theft, suing over minimum wage violations</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/7cMIz3OtQ0k/-NFL-cheerleaders-join-the-fight-against-wage-theft-suing-over-minimum-wage-violations</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79529/large/BuffaloJills2010_cropped.jpg?1398263239" alt="Buffalo Bills cheerleaders, 2010" width="550" height="220" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/03/27/1287845/-New-York-Domino-s-workers-to-get-448-000-wage-theft-settlement"&gt;Fast food workers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293765/-Wage-theft-hits-software-engineers-as-well-as-fast-food-workers"&gt;Software engineers&lt;/a&gt;. NFL cheerleaders. These are just a few of the groups of American workers who are suing over forms of wage theft, the umbrella term for the long list of ways employers cheat workers out of money they've earned. In recent months, NFL cheerleaders—most recently four former cheerleaders for the Buffalo Bills—have been filing lawsuits alleging that they were misclassified as independent contractors rather than employees, then paid amounts that worked out to below minimum wage.
&lt;p&gt;Independent contractors are, by definition, supposed to be able to exercise at least some independence; one of the key measures of &lt;a href="http://dpeaflcio.org/programs-publications/issue-fact-sheets/misclassification-of-employees-as-independent-contractors/"&gt;misclassification&lt;/a&gt; is how much control the employer exerts over the worker. The former Bills cheerleaders' lawsuit reports the team and the management companies it retained to oversee the cheerleading program &lt;a href="http://deadspin.com/suit-bills-cheerleaders-were-taught-how-to-wash-intim-1566239771"&gt;exerting extensive control&lt;/a&gt; over every aspect of their appearance and behavior while on the job:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;z65. In addition to the rules previously cited, defendants also provided the Jills with rules regarding general hygiene and body maintenance (a list of 17 rules), appearance etiquette (17 rules), conversation starters for appearances and general etiquette, etiquette for formal dining (25 rules), and rules for communicating with people with disabilities (17 rules).
&lt;p&gt;66. The extensive rulebook set forth by defendants includes, inter alia, rules on how much bread to eat at a formal dinner, how to properly eat soup, how much to tip restaurant waiters, wedding etiquette, how to properly wash "intimate areas," and how often to change tampons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Following these rules, showing up for appearances, allowing themselves to be groped and harassed, was not exactly a ticket to wealth:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Jills were not paid for working game days. Neither were they paid for the mandatory biweekly practice sessions that usually lasted eight hours in total, according to the suit. On average, the cheerleaders involved in the suit averaged only a few hundred dollars per season, the highest amount being $1,800, the lowest $150. Not surprisingly, the lady who made $150 didn't cheer the next year.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The Bills are the &lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/sports/2014/04/23/3429712/buffalo-bills-cheerleaders-allege-minimum-wage-violations-in-lawsuit-against-team/"&gt;third NFL team&lt;/a&gt; to face such a lawsuit; the Oakland Raiders and Cincinnati Bengals have similarly been sued for paying cheerleaders amounts that worked out to well below minimum wage. And remember, this all is going on in an incredibly profitable industry that &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/09/25/1241265/-Wait-the-NFL-is-a-non-profit-organization"&gt;rakes in huge public subsidies&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="update"&gt;&lt;a name="20140424092347" href="/story/2014/04/23/1294007/-NFL-cheerleaders-join-the-fight-against-wage-theft-suing-over-minimum-wage-violations#20140424092347"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thu Apr 24, 2014 at  9:23 AM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; The lawsuit has had one &lt;a href="http://www.buffalonews.com/sports/bills-nfl/buffalo-jills-suspend-all-activities-20140424?fb_action_ids=10100616605125255&amp;amp;fb_action_types=og.recommends"&gt;immediate effect&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The director of the Buffalo Jills has suspended all activities for the Buffalo Bills cheerleaders until further notice, after five former Jills sued the Bills and her company, which manages the Jills.
&lt;p&gt;Stephanie Mateczun, president of Stejon Productions Corp., based in West Seneca, said she has no idea how long the suspension will last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
We'll see if this lasts until football season, of course.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=7cMIz3OtQ0k:XnqyCqA9_OA:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/7cMIz3OtQ0k" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Buffalo Bills</category>
<category>Cincinnati Bengals</category>
<category>Football</category>
<category>Labor</category>
<category>NFL</category>
<category>Oakland Raiders</category>
<category>Sports</category>
<category>Wage Theft</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294007</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 14:28:51 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294007/-NFL-cheerleaders-join-the-fight-against-wage-theft-suing-over-minimum-wage-violations</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>North Carolina GOP Senate hopeful doesn't understand the meaning of the world 'false'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/c5uRHgZsYH4/-North-Carolina-GOP-Senate-hopeful-doesn-t-understand-the-meaning-of-the-world-false</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://img.youtube.com/vi/SPUY5vv5W-Q/0.jpg' style='display:none;' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='dkimg-c'&gt;&lt;iframe width='550' height='309' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/SPUY5vv5W-Q?rel=0' frameborder='0' defang_allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The ad at the top of this post takes North Carolina House Speaker and GOP senate candidate Thom Tillis to task for having not one but two of his top staffers—one of whom was his roommate—involved in sexual affairs with married lobbyists and then using taxpayer dollars to reward their service before announcing their resignations.
&lt;p&gt;It's a pretty tough ad, but it's accurate. Nonetheless, Tillis is crying foul, putting up an ad of his own accusing Democrats of launching a "false" and "sleazy" ad. But as the &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;'s Glenn Klessler &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/fact-checker/wp/2014/04/23/a-claim-of-false-when-the-ad-is-basically-true/"&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt;, the facts aren't on Tillis's side because everything in the ad that has him so upset is basically true: His staffers did have the affairs with lobbyists, one of them was his roommate, and when he announced their resignations, he also authorized paying them one month of salary—something that he was not required to do under North Carolina law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Kessler notes, Tillis defended those payments at the time:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“I recognized that their jobs and careers were forever affected by their choices,” Tillis said in a statement quoted in the Raleigh News &amp;amp; Observer, “and that serious family obligations still existed for each of them. I stand by my decision to accept their resignation while recognizing the difficult transition period they are now entering.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
But now he says it's "false:"&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Seen those ads attacking Thom Tillis? They’re false. Tillis fired the staffers.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
But that's not the issue. The issue is whether he used taxpayer dollars to effectively give a parting bonus to a pair of disgraced staffers. And in his own words, that's exactly what he did. So the only thing "false" here is is Tillis's claim to have been wronged.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=c5uRHgZsYH4:DLehd9DTphI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/c5uRHgZsYH4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>NC-Sen</category>
<category>Thom Tillis</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294145</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:30:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294145/-North-Carolina-GOP-Senate-hopeful-doesn-t-understand-the-meaning-of-the-world-false</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Election on 34th Street: A guide to the 2014 Congressional elections in New York </title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/aYD9IZ7YgYM/-Election-on-34th-Street-A-guide-to-the-2014-Congressional-elections-in-New-York</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79486/large/RTXUQ0E.jpg?1398223605" alt="U.S. Representative Charlie Rangel (D-NY) gestures as he speaks to the members of the media in front of his House office on Capitol Hill in Washington, November 16, 2010. Rangel said he walked out of the proceedings yesterday when he was denied an attorney to be present with him. He asked for " defang_due="" defang_in="" defang_his="" defang_ethics="" defang_trial.="" defang_kang="" defang_states="" defang_tags:="" defang_crime="" defang_law="" width="550" height="292" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Democratic Rep. Charlie Rangel, a potential primary victim&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
With 27 House seats, there are a lot of races to watch in New York. Some will be resolved in the June 24 primary, while others will be hard fought all the way until November. What follows is a guide to New York's House races. Any race that Daily Kos Elections rates as anything but safe for the incumbent is featured. We also have a few races where the incumbent faces a credible primary challenge.
&lt;p&gt;To start out, here is a chart of all 27 seats. The state has a &lt;a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/218999312/Filings-for-June-2014-Federal-Primary"&gt;complete list of candidates here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;iframe width='560' height='33' frameborder='0' src='https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?key=0AiM4wFocfBQUdDFicVU4OG1WZm1sNUJESVdNVVE0OFE&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;gid=4&amp;amp;range=A1%3AF1&amp;amp;output=html'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;iframe width='560' height='300' frameborder='0' src='https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?key=0AiM4wFocfBQUdDFicVU4OG1WZm1sNUJESVdNVVE0OFE&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;gid=0&amp;amp;range=A2%3AF28&amp;amp;output=html'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Head below the fold for a look at the races that will be worth watching this year.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=aYD9IZ7YgYM:FXl-mpxIS8M:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/aYD9IZ7YgYM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Darth Jeff)</author>
<category>Aaron Woolf</category>
<category>Adriano Espaillat</category>
<category>Bill Owens</category>
<category>Bruce Blakeman</category>
<category>Charlie Rangel</category>
<category>Chris Gibson</category>
<category>Claudia Tenney</category>
<category>Domenic Recchia</category>
<category>Elise Stefanik</category>
<category>George Demos</category>
<category>Kathleen Rice</category>
<category>Kevan Abrahams</category>
<category>Lee Zeldin</category>
<category>Martha Robertson</category>
<category>Matt Doheny</category>
<category>Michael Grimm</category>
<category>Michael Walrond</category>
<category>Nan Hayworth</category>
<category>New York</category>
<category>New York 2014</category>
<category>NY-01</category>
<category>NY-04</category>
<category>NY-11</category>
<category>NY-13</category>
<category>NY-21</category>
<category>NY-22</category>
<category>NY-23</category>
<category>Richard Hanna</category>
<category>Sean Eldridge</category>
<category>Sean Patrick Maloney</category>
<category>Tim Bishop</category>
<category>Tom Reed</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293031</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 18:22:44 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1293031/-Election-on-34th-Street-A-guide-to-the-2014-Congressional-elections-in-New-York</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Army general provides a case study in how not to handle sexual assault charges</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/Xvd_a2l799Y/-Army-general-provides-a-case-study-in-how-not-to-handle-sexual-assault-charges</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79534/large/Senior_leader_visit.jpg?1398266440" alt="Maj. Gen. Michael T. Harrison (center), commander of U.S. Army Japan &amp;amp; I Corps (Forward), visits with the deployable assessment team chief, Col. Frank Clark (left), while touring exercise Sapporo Epicenter, a humanitarian assistance and disaster relief exercise held at Camp Sapporo, Hokkaido, Jan. 23-27, 2013, with Lt. Gen. Kiyofuni Iwata (right), commander of Northern Army, Japan Ground Self Defense Force." width="550" height="365" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Maj. Gen. Michael T. Harrison (center)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The military has so far succeeded at keeping decisions about sexual assault prosecution in the hands of its own commanders. Here's a crystal-clear example of &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/army-general-disciplined-over-mishandling-of-sexual-assault-case-in-japan/2014/04/22/6339f268-ca2b-11e3-a75e-463587891b57_story.html"&gt;why that's a terrible idea&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The sexual misconduct complaints piled up on the desk of Maj. Gen. Michael T. Harrison Sr., the commander of U.S. Army forces in Japan. A colonel on his staff had been accused of having an affair with a subordinate, of drunken and inappropriate behavior with other women at a military club and lastly, of sexual assault.
&lt;p&gt;But Harrison let most of the complaints slide or reacted with leniency, according to the Army. He had known the colonel for two decades and said he didn’t believe some of the allegations. In March 2013, when a Japanese woman accused the colonel of sexually assaulting her, Harrison waited months to report it to criminal investigators — a clear violation of Army rules, &lt;a href="http://apps.washingtonpost.com/g/page/world/report-of-investigation-by-the-army-inspector-general-into-maj-gen-michael-t-harrison-sr/961/"&gt;according to an internal investigation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Oh, it gets better. Harrison was eventually suspended and officially reprimanded—but only because the Japanese woman went outside the chain of command with her complaint. And despite the reprimand, Harrison was made director of program analysis and evaluation for an Army deputy chief of staff at the Pentagon. Some punishment for grievously mishandling a series of sexual assault and misconduct complaints! Harrison will retire soon, and according to the Army, all this shows that he was totally punished very severely, and we should all chill about it because they are handling things.
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; what passes for punishment of a general who puts the man he knows above the women that man mistreated and "boys will be boys" above justice. But that's something the military needs to be fixing. And the fact that they keep not doing so is just one more piece of evidence for why Congress needs to step in and force them to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=Xvd_a2l799Y:HZ5-NIs9ZXs:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/Xvd_a2l799Y" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Army</category>
<category>Military</category>
<category>Sexual Assault</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294025</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 15:22:43 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294025/-Army-general-provides-a-case-study-in-how-not-to-handle-sexual-assault-charges</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Ta-Nehisi Coates is not surprised</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/kSu1jdzg5L4/-Ta-Nehisi-Coates-is-not-surprised</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/78226/large/RTR3KZO5.jpg?1397683866" alt="Rancher Cliven Bundy (back 2nd L) talks on stage beside Clark County Sheriff Douglas Gillespie (back 3rd L) in Bunkerville, Nevada, April 12, 2014. Gillespie announced the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) was ceasing its cattle roundup operation. Armed U.S" width="550" height="394" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
And neither is any other &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2014/04/cliven-bundy-wants-to-tell-you-all-about-the-negro/361152/"&gt;clear thinking person&lt;/a&gt; in America:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A few days ago Jonathan Chait asserted that modern conservatism is "doomed" because it is "rooted in white supremacy." &amp;nbsp;The first claim may or may not be true, but there's little doubt about the second. Whether it's the Senate minority leader claiming that America should have remained legally segregated, &amp;nbsp;a beloved cultural figure fondly recalling how happy black people were living under lynch law, a presidential candidate calling Barack Obama a "food-stamp president" or a campaign surrogate calling Barack Obama "a subhuman mongrel," the preponderance of evidence shows that modern conservatism just can't quit white supremacy.
&lt;p&gt;This is unsurprising. White Supremacy is one of the most dominant forces in the history of American politics. In a democracy, it would be silly to expect it to go unexpressed. Thus anyone with a sense of American history should be equally unsurprised to discover that rugged individualist Cliven Bundy is the bearer of some very interesting theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Of course it isn't surprising. White supremacy is at the very foundation of Conservatism, and at thus at the foundation of the Republican Party. This isn't a freak accident of some ideological disagreement. There are great number of people of color who agree with much of the conservative theories. Nor is it some class-based social result. There are plenty of poor Republicans who agree with Bundy.
&lt;p&gt;Republicans will run from Bundy only because he says out loud what they really think. Some are better at discretion than Bundy, who is obviously too honest for good company. But make no mistake, he's not that far off from where the great majority of Republicans are. In fact, they'll be more offended by his manners than by the substance of what he says. They wouldnt be the first white folks to confuse racism with bad etiquette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lets all express some well deserved outrage at Bundy's &lt;em&gt;comments&lt;/em&gt;. Free speech and all that. But think about the real racism at work here, which are not his opinions: that a heavily armed group of white people can openly disobey federal laws and court orders without consequence for 20 years under the threat of violence to law enforcement. Now imagine if blacks did the same thing. There's the REAL racism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=kSu1jdzg5L4:L2-Q4E7CGVI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/kSu1jdzg5L4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (brooklynbadboy)</author>
<category>Cliven Bundy</category>
<category>ordinary prejudice</category>
<category>Racism</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Republicans</category>
<category>Ta-Nehisi Coates</category>
<category>White Supremacy</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294278</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 13:39:14 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294278/-Ta-Nehisi-Coates-is-not-surprised</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Now the Republican problem with Obamacare is that it doesn't cover enough people?</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/0Xi9MKD9HME/-Now-the-Republican-problem-with-Obamacare-is-that-it-doesn-t-cover-enough-nbsp-people</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/58752/large/RTX14L53.jpg?1385141537" alt="U.S. House Majority Leader Eric Cantor (R-VA) (L) and House Speaker John Boehner (R-OH) (R) stand together at a news conference at the Republican National Committee offices on Capitol Hill in Washington October 23, 2013. REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst" width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Flail.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294067/-With-Obamacare-losing-juice-Senate-Republicans-officially-flailing?detail=hide"&gt;Republicans flailing&lt;/a&gt; to find a message now that Obamacare is working is kind of a blast to watch. Are they going to completely abandon Obamacare and make the election all about Harry Reid? They can't do that, they've invested way too much into convincing the tea party crazies that they'll fight this law to the end.
&lt;p&gt;But now they can't keep up the fiction that it's doomed to fail. They can't call it socialism because too many regular Americans are now paying money to private insurance companies to pay for it, and they can't really call those people socialists. In their zeal to find something, anything, to attack the law, they're making a damned good case for something like Medicare for all. First we've got the Kochs &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294095/-Kochs-reverse-course-start-attacking-Obamacare-from-the-left"&gt;telling voters&lt;/a&gt; that it's horrible that Democrats worked with evil insurance companies to design the law, and now Jonathon Cohn reports, &lt;a href="http://www.newrepublic.com/article/117494/gop-hypocrisy-obamacare-uninsured-medicaid"&gt;they're complaining&lt;/a&gt; that the law isn't actually universal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gopwhip/status/458323679534141441"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/428903276952567808/awRjAOup_normal.png" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The President's health care law continues to fall short of covering the uninsured, but he still claims it's "working" &lt;a href="http://t.co/gISlIzmbPp"&gt;http://t.co/...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/GOPWhip"&gt;@GOPWhip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Remember, House Republicans have voted to repeal Obamacare 50 times. They have voted on serious Obamacare alternatives exactly zero times. They haven’t even made a serious attempt to get a bill out of committee, let alone hold a floor debate. A few Republican lawmakers have crafted proposals on their own, as have some conservative intellectuals. But GOP leaders have made it very clear &lt;a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2014/02/lonely-death-of-the-republican-health-plan.html"&gt;they want nothing to do with these plans.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, a major reason the Affordable Care Act isn’t reaching more people is that Republicans have done their best to limit the law’s reach—primarily, by blocking expansions of Medicaid in states where conservative Republicans hold sway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
If they're really, really worried about making sure everyone gets access to health care, there's a solution. But as they've demonstrated time and time again, solutions aren't what they're after. They can only offer mindless, knee-jerk "Obamacare bad" diatribes that make less and less sense.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=0Xi9MKD9HME:Pr4dehAKjvQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/0Xi9MKD9HME" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Republicans</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294151</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 22:51:43 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294151/-Now-the-Republican-problem-with-Obamacare-is-that-it-doesn-t-cover-enough-nbsp-people</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cartoon: Back to business</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/baHYEYbAutI/-Cartoon-Back-to-business</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79613/large/Kos-Earth-tease.jpg?1398290783"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79612/large/Kos-Earth.jpg?1398290764" alt="Matt Wuerker" height="508" width="550" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(Click for larger image)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=baHYEYbAutI:43KFT9Z62oY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/baHYEYbAutI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (MattWuerker)</author>
<category>Energy</category>
<category>Environment</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294137</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 21:50:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294137/-Cartoon-Back-to-business</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Arkansas Democrats use Medicaid expansion to rally women</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/fowSJWUeO14/-Arkansas-Democrats-use-Medicaid-expansion-to-rally-women</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Nice message, Arkansas Democrats!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79696/large/cotton_PO_women.PNG.jpeg?1398359833" alt="Image tweeted out by Arkansas Democrats showing 155,567 people, 61 percent women, have coverage in the state's Medicaid expansion, and that Tom Cotton would take that insurance away." width="550" height="274" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
That's Democrats &lt;a href="http://www.arktimes.com/ArkansasBlog/archives/2014/04/23/democrats-use-private-option-to-rally-female-base-voters-in-cotton-pryor-race"&gt;reminding voters&lt;/a&gt;, particularly women, that Republican Tom Cotton, who is running for Senate, wants to take their insurance away from them by repealing Obamacare. And, so far, he hasn't put forward &lt;a href="http://www.arktimes.com/ArkansasBlog/archives/2014/04/13/tom-cotton-avoids-taking-stance-on-private-option" defang_suggestions=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for how those 155,567 people, who have coverage through the state's private option Medicaid expansion, will get replacement coverage.
&lt;p&gt;That's a pretty good message for motivating women, and anyone who cares about people having health care, to get to the polls in November.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=fowSJWUeO14:xxM-OtDQCDY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/fowSJWUeO14" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>AR-Sen</category>
<category>Arkansas</category>
<category>Mark Pryor</category>
<category>Medicaid</category>
<category>Tom Cotton</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294360</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 17:25:09 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294360/-Arkansas-Democrats-use-Medicaid-expansion-to-rally-women</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cuomo defends stymying corruption commission: 'Because I could'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/Ly7RJWYHyBA/-Cuomo-defends-stymying-corruption-commission-because-I-could</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/77326/large/12076034366_94ab34318d_b.jpg?1397108014" alt="January 21, 2014-Albany- Governor Cuomo delivers his 2014 Executive Budget address, " width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;If part of the equation for good government is "trust", NY Gov. Andrew Cuomo has blown that away.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo promised to clean up New York's rampant corruption in the state capitol in Albany. Then when the commission he appointed, the Moreland Commission, got close to his patrons, his office &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/10/nyregion/us-attorney-criticizes-cuomos-closing-of-panel.html"&gt;squashed&lt;/a&gt; those investigations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;[W]atchdog groups raised concerns about the panel’s credibility after reports about interference by the governor’s office, which leaned on the commission to limit the scope of its investigations, influence which subpoenas it would issue, and in some cases, stop the commission from issuing subpoenas to groups with ties to Mr. Cuomo.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
And when that wasn't enough, he simply shut the commission down. So much for cleaning up Albany.
&lt;p&gt;But a federal prosecutor has taken over the commission's files and blasted the governor, and the New York press is starting to dig further. So how does Cuomo &lt;a href="http://www.crainsnewyork.com/article/20140424/BLOGS04/140429924"&gt;respond&lt;/a&gt; to this growing mess?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“It’s not a legal question. The Moreland Commission was my commission,” Mr. Cuomo explained. “It’s my commission. My subpoena power, my Moreland Commission. I can appoint it, I can disband it. I appoint you, I can un-appoint you tomorrow.
&lt;p&gt;"So, interference? It’s my commission. I can’t 'interfere' with it, because it is mine. It is controlled by me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Seriously, admitting that it was kabuki from day one? Admitting that every promising corruption lead followed by the commission was squashed by him because it was controlled by him?
&lt;p&gt;The Moreland Commission scandal has already killed Cuomo's national ambitions. This response is just icing on the cake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=Ly7RJWYHyBA:PjXb0ph34CE:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/Ly7RJWYHyBA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (kos)</author>
<category>Andrew Cuomo</category>
<category>Ethics</category>
<category>Governor</category>
<category>New York</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294412</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 20:23:20 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294412/-Cuomo-defends-stymying-corruption-commission-because-I-could</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Sean Hannity calls Bundy comments 'repugnant, despicable'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/SUPtxrj60WE/-Sean-Hannity-calls-Bundy-comments-repugnant-despicable</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/78192/large/RTR3L0EB.jpg?1397667337" alt="Eric Parker from central Idaho aims his weapon from a bridge as protesters gather by the Bureau of Land Management's base camp, where cattle that were seized from rancher Cliven Bundy are being held, near Bunkerville, Nevada April 12, 2014. The U.S. Burea" width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;But the pointing guns at federal agents part Sean was fine with.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Welp, pack it in, fellas. Cliven Bundy &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/hannity-bundy-slavery-repugnant?utm_content=buffer2aca0&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer"&gt;has lost Sean Hannity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Bundy's comments "are beyond repugnant to me. They are beyond despicable to me. They are beyond ignorant to me," Hannity said during his radio show.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
And Hannity knows the real problem here, which is that no matter how much Hannity agreed with the general premise of pointing a crapload of weapons at federal agents trying to enforce a law that Cliven Bundy doesn't personally want to abide by, &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; Bundy is making conservatives look bad.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"They want to say that conservatives are racist. Conservatives hate women," Hannity said. "Conservatives want old people to die, granny over the cliff. They want the young people to fend for themselves. They want to poison the air and poison the water."
&lt;p&gt;"People that for the right reasons saw this case as government overreach now are branded because of the ignorant, racist, repugnant, despicable comments of Cliven Bundy," he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Yeah, wow. It's simply amazing how often that keeps happening. You find yourself a nice, heavily armed conservative hero who has conspiracy theories as to why the United States government doesn't actually exist, and the guy turns out to be a total wacko. What are the odds?&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=SUPtxrj60WE:iLXYccmq4UE:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/SUPtxrj60WE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Hunter)</author>
<category>Cliven Bundy</category>
<category>Conservatives</category>
<category>Fox News</category>
<category>Media</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Sean Hannity</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294411</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 20:00:21 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294411/-Sean-Hannity-calls-Bundy-comments-repugnant-despicable</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Christie lawyer condemns revolting attack ad released by Christie</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/dPcGN-11ceY/-Christie-lawyer-condemns-revolting-attack-ad-released-by-Christie</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://img.youtube.com/vi/nf0-KN5Ijkk/0.jpg' style='display:none;' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='dkimg-c'&gt;&lt;iframe width='550' height='309' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/nf0-KN5Ijkk?rel=0' frameborder='0' defang_allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Christie heads the Republican Governors Association which aired this attack ad in South Carolina&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
How thoroughly disgusting is the Republican Governors' Association &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293760/-Republicans-continue-their-assault-on-criminal-defense-attorneys-with-revolting-new-campaign-ad"&gt;new ad&lt;/a&gt; attacking South Carolina State Sen. and Democratic gubernatorial candidate Vincent Sheheen for having represented criminals as a defense attorney? It's so disgusting that one of RGA Chairman Chris Christie's own lawyer's—hired to to represent him in the lane closure scandal—is &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/04/23/chris-christie-lawyer_n_5201486.html?view=print&amp;amp;comm_ref=false"&gt;condemning it&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"I did watch the ad and, wow, it's a disgrace," Robert D. Luskin, a partner at Patton Boggs, told The Huffington Post in an email. "The people who talk incessantly about American exceptionalism ought to demonstrate some understanding -- and some respect -- for what makes our system truly admirable: that includes the willingness of lawyers to stand up for their clients no matter how ugly the allegation. But a lawyer is only, ever an advocate; he's not a co conspirator or an enabler."&lt;/blockquote&gt;
As our own David Nir &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293760/-Republicans-continue-their-assault-on-criminal-defense-attorneys-with-revolting-new-campaign-ad"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I'm never one for Marquess of Queensberry rules when it comes to campaign trail fights. Politics is messy, after all. But these kinds of ads are a direct assault on the very notion of an adversarial system of justice, one of the foundations of our democracy.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The obvious irony here is that the blanket attack on criminal lawyers is coming from a group headed by a guy who may soon need a criminal defense lawyer. If that happens, you can bet your bottom dollar he's going to change his tune on the value of defense attorneys.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Former Republican AG of South Carolina &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CharlieCondon/status/459383536597078017"&gt;concurs&lt;/a&gt;—the ad is a disgrace and should be removed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=dPcGN-11ceY:eNjd5OXEJz0:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/dPcGN-11ceY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>2016</category>
<category>Chris Christie</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294317</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 20:00:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294317/-Christie-lawyer-condemns-revolting-attack-ad-released-by-Christie</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>How to make Fox shut up about deadbeat ranchers with armed militias</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/EyvBGJ75fkA/-How-to-make-Fox-shut-up-about-deadbeat-ranchers-with-armed-militias</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/78803/large/screenshotoffoxbundy.jpg?1397851784" alt="Fox News Sean Hannity program on April 15, 2014" width="550" height="273" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Before &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294262/-Conservative-hero-Cliven-Bundy-I-want-to-tell-you-one-more-thing-I-know-about-the-Negro"&gt;the news&lt;/a&gt; broke that Cliven Bundy is a raging racist asshole in addition to being a deadbeat rancher backed by an armed militia defending his right to stiff the federal government: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BuzzFeedAndrew/status/459408447109623808"&gt;458 mentions&lt;/a&gt; of the right's newest hero on Fox News in April, an average of 20 per day.
&lt;p&gt;And since then? &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BuzzFeedAndrew/status/459408447109623808"&gt;Two.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=EyvBGJ75fkA:56F549jurLs:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/EyvBGJ75fkA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>Cliven Bundy</category>
<category>Fox News</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294396</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 19:30:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294396/-How-to-make-Fox-shut-up-about-deadbeat-ranchers-with-armed-militias</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Midday open thread: Gender pay gap starts young, whistleblowers suffer, jobless comp claims rise</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/1jmivCf3mdg/-Midday-open-thread-Gender-pay-gap-starts-young-whistleblowers-suffer-jobless-comp-claims-rise</link>
<description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today's &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/blog/comics"&gt;comic&lt;/a&gt; by Ruben Bolling is &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1293991/-Cartoon-Lucky-Ducky-in-State-nbsp-of-nbsp-Denial"&gt;Lucky Duck in "State of Denial"&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1293991/-Cartoon-Lucky-Ducky-in-State-nbsp-of-nbsp-Denial?detail=hide"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79662/large/1185ckTEASER-lucky-ducky---state-of-denial.png?1398339175" alt="Cartoon by Ruben Bolling -- Lucky Ducky, in 'State of Denial'" width="500" height="280" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These Daily Kos community posts were the most shared on Facebook April 23:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dailykos/posts/10152367223589255"&gt;BREAKING: Jury awards $3 million in first fracking case&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;b&gt;TXsharon&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dailykos/posts/10152367753124255"&gt;IRS Targeted Progressive Groups MORE than Tea Party&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;b&gt;ericlewis0&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dailykos/posts/10152368275959255"&gt;Duke president says removing toxic ash would cost $10 billion and take decades which is "too much"&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;b&gt;HoundDog&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/read/information-isnt-free-how-whistleblowers-suffer-for-the-truth"&gt;Whistleblowers pay a big price&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;"Part of the purpose of doing what they've been doing for the last several years, is to destroy you," the ex-NSA mathematician and decorated Navy veteran Thomas Drake says in [the film] &lt;em&gt;Silenced&lt;/em&gt;. [...]
&lt;p&gt;f you become a whistleblower, "You have to mortgage your house, you have to empty your bank accounts," Drake says. The only work he could find, eventually, was as an Apple store clerk. Though every single one of the major charges were eventually dropped—following a piece on Drake in the &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt; segment, it should be noted—the toll of his whistleblowing was clear. Drake estimated that the charges had cost him over a million dollars in legal fees and lost work. He was ostracized and condemned by his peers. It was emotionally devastating, too; the charges, Drake implies, led to a painful separation with his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wonkwire.rollcall.com/2014/04/24/housing-prices-vary-across-country/"&gt;Mapping the hourly wage needed to cover modest housing&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;Emily Badger and Christopher Ingraham show "what you’d need to earn per hour, working a 40-hour week, to cover the kind of housing that the federal government considers modest in your county."
&lt;p&gt;“Mapped in finer detail than by state, several geographic patterns are clearer. No single county in America has a one-bedroom housing wage below the federal minimum wage of $7.25 (several counties in Arkansas come in at $7.98).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://grist.org/business-technology/apple-announces-big-clean-energy-progress/"&gt;Apple says 94 percent of its corporate facilities are now powered by clean energy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/economy/2014/04/23/3430025/gender-gap-allowance/"&gt;Even allowances are plagued by gender gap&lt;/a&gt;. Seventy percent of boys vs. 60 percent of girls say they get an allowance.
&lt;blockquote&gt;But unfortunately, it’s not likely because boys do more chores. One study found that girls do two more hours of housework a week than boys, while boys spend twice as much time playing. The same study confirmed that boys are still more likely to get paid for what they do: they are 15 percent more likely to get an allowance for doing chores than girls. A 2009 survey of children ages 5 to 12 found that far more girls are assigned chores than boys.
&lt;p&gt;And it’s not just that boys are more likely to be paid by their parents, but they also get more money. One study found that boys spent just 2.1 hours a week on chores and made $48 on average, while girls put in 2.7 hours to make $45. A British study found that boys get paid 15 percent more than girls for the same chores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dol.gov/opa/media/press/eta/eta20140666.pdf"&gt;Compensation claims rise eight percent&lt;/a&gt;: For the week ending April 19, seasonally adjusted initial claims for unemployment compensation rose to 329,000, up 24,000 from the previous week's revised level. For the comparable week of 2013, the number was 343,000. The less volatile four-week running average rose to 316,750. For the week ending April 5, the total number of people claiming compensation was 2,922,187, down 85,245 from the previous week. For the comparable week in 2013, 5,065,908 persons claimed compensation from state and federal programs. Most of that one-year decrease is a consequence of the failure of Congress to renew the federal emergency unemployment compensation program in December.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2014/04/23/massive-iceberg-six-times-the.html"&gt;Giant iceberg breaks away from Antarctica&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;One of the largest icebergs on the planet, about six times the size of Manhattan, has separated from an Antarctic glacier and is floating out towards open ocean. The iceberg is named B-31, and is roughly 255 square miles (660 square km). Its estimated maximum thickness is 1,600 feet (487 meters). Last Fall, it broke off from the Pine Island Glacier. Researchers have been watching it drift away since then, via satellite.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/business/vermont-will-require-labeling-of-genetically-altered-foods.html?ref=us&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;Food industry says people won't eat GMO products if they're labeled&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;Big food manufacturers and the biotech industry that produces the seeds for genetically engineered crops contend that mandatory labeling of products containing ingredients derived from those crops — also known as genetically modified organisms, or G.M.O.s — will be tantamount to putting a skull-and-crossbones on them.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/morningenergy/0414/morningenergy13713.html"&gt;White House spokesman denies Rolling Stone claim on Keystone XL—sort of&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;The White House didn't offer an official response when POLITICO asked about yesterday's &lt;em&gt;Rolling Stone&lt;/em&gt; piece (&lt;a href="http://rol.st/1npFVAk"&gt;http://rol.st/...&lt;/a&gt; ) saying that two unnamed administration sources say President Barack Obama "all but decided to deny the permit for the pipeline." But White House spokesman Matt Lehrich later wrote on Twitter: "Tip for reporters: nobody who knows POTUS' thinking on Keystone is talking and nobody who is talking knows." He also offered the standard White House statement that the pipeline decision is in the hands of the State Department and will be "made on merits."&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294370/-Daily-Kos-Radio-s-KITM-podcast-Bundy-implosion-Occupy-vs-Moral-Mondays-Are-we-an-oligarchy-yet"&gt;today's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show&lt;/a&gt;, Cliven Bundy, ladies &amp;amp; gents! &lt;strong&gt;Greg Dworkin&lt;/strong&gt; parses the Kaiser polling, then sets the agenda for the day with Harold Pollock's "Pre-Occupied with Medicaid Expansion." It's Occupy vs. "Moral Mondays." And are we an oligarchy yet, or what?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2800002/height/45/width/500/theme/standard/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/no/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="45" width="500" scrolling="no" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=1jmivCf3mdg:_v1nASE0yAA:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/1jmivCf3mdg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Meteor Blades)</author>
<category>Midday Open Thread</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294284</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 19:00:16 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294284/-Midday-open-thread-Gender-pay-gap-starts-young-whistleblowers-suffer-jobless-comp-claims-rise</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>We have three weeks to save Net neutrality</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/mmVPLckbOl0/-We-have-three-weeks-to-save-Net-Neutrality</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/65104/large/dreamstime_s_7222971.jpg?1389724534" alt="net neutrality sign" width="550" height="356" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='375' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/785.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Federal Communications Commission will be &lt;s&gt;voting on&lt;/s&gt; considering a proposal that would &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294157/-FCC-to-consider-rule-gutting-Net-nbsp-Neutrality"&gt;kill Net neutrality&lt;/a&gt; next month. Basically, Chairman Tom Wheeler (former telecomm CEO and lobbyist) has decided that Internet service providers (like Comcast or Verizon) will be able to charge content providers (like Microsoft or Google) for preferential treatment.
&lt;p&gt;The big, rich companies can pay for high bandwidth, small companies like Daily Kos can't. We'll be left in the slow lane. The rules will say that ISP won't be allowed to deliberately slow down traffic from specific sites, but that's the only thing that would be left of the Net neutrality that has allowed the Internet to change the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving ISPs the power to demand pay-for-priority schemes would be disastrous for startups, nonprofits and small companies, not to mention everyday Internet users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/785"&gt;Help us stop the FCC from crushing Net neutrality. Please sign our petition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="update"&gt;&lt;a name="20140424150854" href="/story/2014/04/24/1294375/-We-have-three-weeks-to-save-Net-Neutrality#20140424150854"&gt;&lt;b&gt; 3:08 PM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Thanks to all the commenters who note that the final vote on the rule isn't on May 15. But the FCC commissioners will decide at that meeting whether to essentially accept the proposal and put it out for public comment, or sink it and make Wheeler go back to the drawing board. We need to nip this proposal in the bud now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=mmVPLckbOl0:6JwwgTjgkZs:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/mmVPLckbOl0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Federal Communications Commission</category>
<category>Net Neutrality</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Tom Wheeler</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294375</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 18:03:33 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294375/-We-have-three-weeks-to-save-Net-Neutrality</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Reince Priebus outraged by billionaire political spending?</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/ff52q4F6KIE/-Reince-Priebus-outraged-by-billionaire-political-spending</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Yet more evidence that Republican National Committee Chairman Reince Priebus is a lame troll:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Reince/status/459327148051148800"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/439488374005448704/9GtB4pmt_normal.png" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Retweet &amp;amp; Sign &lt;a href="http://t.co/fDdIgAzHBU"&gt;http://t.co/...&lt;/a&gt; Tell @BarackObama that jobs &amp;amp; energy security are more important than politics &amp;amp; a billionaire donor&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/Reince"&gt;@Reince&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Um, Reince, if you're going to feign outrage against Tom Steyer and President Obama's approach to Keystone XL, you're going to need to do better than that.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the president were making a purely political decision, he'd approve Keystone and do it before the election—the fact that he hasn't done so is a reflection of his policy views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If Reince wants to claim he's outraged over billionaires spending money in politics, then he probably shouldn't do it just 24 hours after &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294056/-Priebus-all-atwitter-about-SenatorReid"&gt;alleging&lt;/a&gt; Harry Reid was breaking the law for tweeting about the Koch Brothers and the GOP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And if Reince really wants to get rid of billionaire influence in politics, then why is it that under his leadership the GOP has systematically pushed to rollback campaign contribution limits, including coming out in favor of &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/reince-priebus-strike-down-all-campaign-finance-caps"&gt;banning campaign contribution caps&lt;/a&gt; altogether?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Reince truly wanted to help return democracy to the public, he'd find an eager partner in the Democratic Party, which is eager to support new disclosure rules and to find new ways to limit the outsize influence of big donors. But he doesn't want that—instead, he wants Democrats to tie one arm behind their back while the GOP goes to town with the Kochs. Well, sorry Reince. It ain't gonna' happen that way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=ff52q4F6KIE:P3sbUHYyUoc:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/ff52q4F6KIE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>Reince Priebus</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294343</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 18:01:03 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294343/-Reince-Priebus-outraged-by-billionaire-political-spending</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Must-see: Hannity attacks Jon Stewart. Stewart responds with epic smackdown.</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/wDU_xKh3M0k/-MUST-SEE-Hannity-attacks-Jon-Stewart-Big-mistake-Jon-responds-with-EPIC-smackdown</link>
<description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79675/large/Hannity-v-Stewart-Arby.jpg" width="550" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, Jon Stewart noted how &lt;a href="http://thedailyshow.cc.com/videos/o9sv2p/grazed-and-confused"&gt;Sean Hannity had attacked Jon&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293714/-MUST-SEE-Jon-Stewart-rips-into-Cliven-Bundy-and-his-demented-defenders"&gt;day before&lt;/a&gt; over Cliven Bundy. Jon had &lt;a href="http://thedailyshow.cc.com/videos/qjwxgb/grazed-and-confused---hannity-obsession"&gt;quite the response&lt;/a&gt; to Hannity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;And yet, you, the uber-American, this man is your cause?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;CLIVEN BUNDY (4/10/2014): I don't recognize the United States government as even existing.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
He doesn't recognize America's existence! He's a U.S.A.-theist! (&lt;i&gt;audience laughter&lt;/i&gt;) Cuz the federal government does exist. In fact, it was created by those guys and that document you love so, so much.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;SEAN HANNITY (2/5/2014): I love Washington because he gave up power. Amazing to me, when he could have held on to it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Washington. Now there's a Founding Father who could found the shit out of everyone. How do you think he would handle an armed group of federal government rejectionists who wouldn't pay their taxes? Well, we don't really need to speculate, because it was called the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whiskey_Rebellion"&gt;Whiskey Rebellion&lt;/a&gt;. And Washington, with his federal army, crushed it in 1794. I guess you would say, disproportionately. (&lt;i&gt;audience laughter&lt;/i&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;And the reason he was legally allowed to do that was because a man named &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Shays"&gt;Daniel Shays&lt;/a&gt; pulled the same shit in 1786 and 1787.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Video and full transcript below the fold.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=wDU_xKh3M0k:7nDSVHdYzAY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/wDU_xKh3M0k" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (BruinKid)</author>
<category>Fox News</category>
<category>Jon Stewart</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Sean Hannity</category>
<category>The Daily Show with Jon Stewart</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294263</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 13:30:17 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294263/-MUST-SEE-Hannity-attacks-Jon-Stewart-Big-mistake-Jon-responds-with-EPIC-smackdown</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cliven Bundy would 'appreciate' everybody forgetting his racism</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/xnRC8OiP13c/-Cliven-Bundy-would-appreciate-everybody-forgetting-his-racism</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://img.youtube.com/vi/FbnRnhrNFEY/0.jpg' style='display:none;' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='dkimg-c'&gt;&lt;iframe width='550' height='309' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/FbnRnhrNFEY?rel=0' frameborder='0' defang_allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Bundy continues to have very strange theories as to how the world works:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/igorbobic/status/459368587493666816"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/423288440034058240/h8EVAyyH_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Bundy says on Alex Jones radio show that he'd "appreciate" NYT retracting quotes: "I'm not racist."&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/igorbobic"&gt;@igorbobic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p&gt;Well sure, I bet he would. We can't have the militia movement and the vast majority of conservative talking heads &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294312/-Cliven-Bundy-s-racist-comments-force-some-Republican-supporters-to-back-off"&gt;thinking poorly of him&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But "retract" a statement &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294275/-Cliven-Bundy-wants-to-tell-you-about-the-Negro-I-want-to-tell-you-about-Cliven-Bundy"&gt;he made on tape&lt;/a&gt;, because it makes him look bad? How's that supposed to work?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=xnRC8OiP13c:nziF9vHt5W0:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/xnRC8OiP13c" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Hunter)</author>
<category>Cliven Bundy</category>
<category>Conservatives</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294346</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 16:55:45 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294346/-Cliven-Bundy-would-appreciate-everybody-forgetting-his-racism</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Washington Post's Jennifer Rubin is on to our dastardly (popular) agenda!</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/8xDcsjhH6gY/-Jennifer-Rubin-is-on-to-our-dastardly-popular-agenda</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/9585/large/RTR39X3H.jpg?1351993813" alt="U.S. Republican presidential nominee and former Massachusetts Governor Mitt Romney arrives at a campaign rally in Etna, Ohio, November 2, 2012. REUTERS/Jim Young" width="550" height="340" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;New rule: If you thought this guy was going to win, you can't call anyone else "deluded."&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/right-turn/wp/2014/04/23/tom-steyer-self-deluded-billionaire/"&gt;Jennifer Rubin&lt;/a&gt; headline:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Steyer, self-deluded liberal billionaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Funny for Rubin to call anyone "self-deluded" when it was she who &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/right-turn/post/romney-rising-obama-overwhelmed/2012/10/26/8086f09c-1f8b-11e2-9cd5-b55c38388962_blog.html"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt;, a week before the November 2012 elections:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Romney rising, Obama overwhelmed&lt;/strong&gt; [...]
&lt;p&gt;In sum, you have one camp where the message, the electorate and the news are all downers. On the other side, you have a positive message, new ad buys in the blue state of Minnesota and the potential for a huge turnout. Two campaigns, traveling in very different directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Ha, ha, ha, Minnesota! The same Minnesota President Barack Obama won by 10 points.
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, why is Tom Steyer deluded? It has something to do with Democrats being hypocritical because they criticize Koch brothers spending, but then Steyer is going to start spending his own money. Democrats should let conservative billionaires buy America, but no, they're being hypocritical by fighting back! Her argument is a bit of a mess, actually. (Never mind that Democrats would sign off on a Constitutional Amendment banning corporate money in politics &lt;i&gt;today&lt;/i&gt; given the opportunity.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, her coup de grâce is her assertion that just like the Koch brothers, who try to shape the agenda to suit their business interests, liberals also have a selfish agenda! And that agenda is THIS:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Democrats have cash from Hollywood, Manhattan and Silicon Valley liberal elites who would like pot and gay marriage to be legal and the internal combustion engine to disappear. Those people are just as “selfish” as the Koch brothers [...]&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Um, all of those are majority positions with the American people, and none &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt; benefit most liberal elite donors. Most aren't gay. So supporting equality isn't really selfish. All of them can already smoke pot if they want, but they want saner drug laws for others. It won't be them going to jail. So again, not selfish. And if they really want to ditch gas-powered cars, they can already buy a Tesla or Volt or BMW i3 or whatever. But more accessible electric vehicles (and clean power to fuel them)? Not selfish, unless it's "selfish" to pine for cleaner air for them and their children.
&lt;p&gt;So how is advocating for those issues akin to building a pipeline to carry Koch oil product to the Gulf Coast for export? Obviously, it's not. But if you're dumb enough to think Romney was competitive in Minnesota in 2012, then processing reality was never your strong suit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=8xDcsjhH6gY:JaS6MbIbIpw:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/8xDcsjhH6gY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (kos)</author>
<category>Energy</category>
<category>Environment</category>
<category>Gay Marriage</category>
<category>Jennifer Rubin</category>
<category>Marriage Equality</category>
<category>Media</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294338</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 16:55:32 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294338/-Jennifer-Rubin-is-on-to-our-dastardly-popular-agenda</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cliven Bundy's racist comments force some Republican supporters to back off</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/8wmCM7Nhe_s/-Cliven-Bundy-s-racist-comments-force-some-Republican-supporters-to-back-off</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79690/large/RTR3L0J8.jpg?1398355787" alt="Rancher Cliven Bundy gestures at his home in Bunkerville, Nevada April 12, 2014. U.S. officials ended a stand-off with hundreds of armed protesters in the Nevada desert on Saturday, calling off the government's roundup of cattle it said were illegally grazing on federal land and giving about 300 animals back to rancher Bundy who owned them. REUTERS/Jim Urquhart &amp;amp;nbsp; (UNITED STATES - Tags: POLITICS ANIMALS BUSINESS CRIME LAW CIVIL UNREST) - RTR3L0J8" width="550" height="375" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Gosh, who could have predicted that supporting Cliven Bundy would come back to bite some Republicans in the ass?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
When the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; asked a few of deadbeat rancher Cliven Bundy's prominent supporters &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/us/politics/rancher-proudly-breaks-the-law-becoming-a-hero-in-the-west.html?_r=1"&gt;what they thought&lt;/a&gt; of his comments beginning "I want to tell you one more thing I know about the Negro" and concluding that maybe slavery was better for black people, Sen. Dean Heller's office responded by saying that Heller "completely disagrees with Mr. Bundy’s appalling and racist statements, and condemns them in the most strenuous way." By contrast, Sen. Rand Paul's office said Paul wasn't available for comment. That started the clock. How long would it take Rand Paul to condemn the idea that there's a serious discussion to be had about whether slavery or freedom is better?
&lt;p&gt;We don't know exactly when a &lt;i&gt;Times&lt;/i&gt; reporter called Paul's office with that question, but we know that Paul's &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/cliven-bundy-racist-comments-slaves-ranch-2014-4"&gt;eventual statement&lt;/a&gt; distancing himself from Bundy—"His remarks on race are offensive and I wholeheartedly disagree with him"—didn't come until Thursday morning, nearly 10 hours after the story went online and after Bundy's remarks were already drawing wide notice. So basically, Paul's disagreement is wholehearted, but not something that could be expressed the first time his office heard what Bundy said. Duly noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of Bundy's other prominent supporters &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/post-politics/wp/2014/04/24/rand-paul-and-other-republican-leaders-back-away-from-bundy/"&gt;made excuses&lt;/a&gt;, with conservative talk radio host Dana Loesch writing that "I hope no one is surprised that an old man rancher isn’t media-trained to express himself perfectly." As if there's a more perfect, media-friendly way to suggest that it's a shame that the Negro of today never learned to pick cotton like they would have under slavery. Then there's Breitbart's John Nolte:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NolteNC/status/459337501086584832"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/418837108657102848/aBYCJCIg_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Remember how the Left backed away from Ted Kennedy's causes after he killed a woman? GOP should do same with Bundy's appalling racism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/NolteNC"&gt;@NolteNC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p&gt;First off, when you're relying on a single incident 45 years in the past to make your case, your case might be weak. Second, "Ted Kennedy's causes"? Like, "oh, damn, I supported health care reform, but it's one of Kennedy's causes, so I guess I better distance myself from it?" See, Ted Kennedy's causes were real causes. The point was getting more rights for more people, increasing equality, slowing a nuclear arms race ... big-picture stuff about which more could be said than "Ted Kennedy supports this." "Cliven Bundy shouldn't have to pay to graze his cattle on federal land, like all the other ranchers do" is a stark—and pitiful—contrast as far as "causes" go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sure is a shame that after so many Republicans praised a man for taking up arms against the federal government to avoid paying for his use of government land, they should have to deal with the fact that he's also a racist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=8wmCM7Nhe_s:HwrbUHby8YQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/8wmCM7Nhe_s" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Cliven Bundy</category>
<category>Dana Loesch</category>
<category>Dean Heller</category>
<category>John Nolte</category>
<category>Racism</category>
<category>Rand Paul</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294312</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 16:17:09 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294312/-Cliven-Bundy-s-racist-comments-force-some-Republican-supporters-to-back-off</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>When political punditry and math collide</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/DImw4wYUUxY/-When-political-punditry-and-math-collide</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79623/large/1889064_712851162092583_67506071_o.jpg?1398293428" alt="Mary Landrieu speaking at podium" width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;No, the Democratic Senate majority does not hinge on Mary Landrieu.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.pbs.org/newshour/updates/expansive-gun-law-test-democrats/"&gt;PBS&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Of all the Democrats running, Landrieu’s race may be the most important. In many ways, she’s a keystone. It’s hard to see Democrats holding the Senate if she loses, but it’s also hard to see them losing the Senate if she wins.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
It's hard to see Democrats holding the Senate if she loses?
&lt;p&gt;Republicans need to pick up six seats. Of the endangered Democratic incumbents, Landrieu currently sports &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/newsgraphics/2014/senate-model/"&gt;the worst numbers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it's very easy to see a scenario where Landrieu loses and the Democrats hold the Senate by winning every other contested seat. It's called "a smaller Democratic majority", but a majority nonetheless. So no, it's not the most important race of the cycle, and won't be unless it heads into a December runoff with Republicans already having picked off five seats.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=DImw4wYUUxY:aAscQyrMsQw:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/DImw4wYUUxY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (kos)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>Elections</category>
<category>Louisiana</category>
<category>Mary Landrieu</category>
<category>Senate</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294325</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 15:56:27 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294325/-When-political-punditry-and-math-collide</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Kochs trying to suppress vote in state they already supposedly won</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/ZC2m4gn9haI/-Kochs-trying-to-suppress-vote-in-state-they-already-supposedly-won</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79604/large/Natalie-tennant.jpg?1398287545" alt="Natalie Tennant campaign kickoff event." width="550" height="368" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;If Democratic Senate candidate Natalie Tennant is such a guaranteed loser, why are the Kochs trying to suppress her support?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Conventional wisdom is that Republicans are guaranteed a Senate pickup in West Virginia, where Sen. Jay Rockafeller's retirement has created an open-seat race in this reddening state. While I wouldn't peg the GOP's chances at 100 percent, it's certainly hard to see a legit path to Democratic victory.
&lt;p&gt;But if it's such a gimme, why are the Kochs working hard to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/04/23/west-virginia-voters-americans-for-prosperity_n_5198824.html?utm_hp_ref=politics"&gt;suppress the vote&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;West Virginia Secretary of State Natalie Tennant attacked Americans for Prosperity, a conservative nonprofit backed by billionaires Charles and David Koch, on Tuesday for distributing “misleading” and “confusing” voter registration mailings, according to the Associated Press.
&lt;p&gt;The leaflets, sent out to at least eight different counties, warned residents that if they did not update their voter registration before April 22, they could become ineligible to vote in the upcoming May 13 election. The mailer also included a voter registration card and prepaid envelope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Americans for Prosperity claims that it's just a generic non-partisan voter registration effort. Yet one of the counties mentioned, Marion, is among the more Democratic ones, giving Sen. Joe Manchin a 64-33 victory margin. And while President Barack Obama lost every county in the state in 2012, Marion's 42 percent was among his best showing.
&lt;p&gt;There's also Berkeley and Jefferson Counties, both part of the DC metro area, among the fastest-growing in the state, and among the state's most Democratic. In fact, Jefferson gave Obama his best showing in the state with 47 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So AFP is innocently trying to goose voter registration in the state's most Democratic regions? How helpful of them! And how full of shit, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a group of people so confident of victory, their actions betray their words. Even in West Virginia, Republicans aren't a lock to pick up the seat. Democrats have a legit candidate in Secretary of State Natalie Tennant. And with the national winds turning against them on Obamacare and other issues, they now feel the need to resort to voter suppression efforts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=ZC2m4gn9haI:Jne9nSEyWFY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/ZC2m4gn9haI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (kos)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>AFP</category>
<category>Americans For Prosperity</category>
<category>Elections</category>
<category>Koch Brothers</category>
<category>Natalie Tennant</category>
<category>Senate</category>
<category>West Virginia</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294115</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 15:30:26 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294115/-Kochs-trying-to-suppress-vote-in-state-they-already-supposedly-won</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cliven Bundy wants to tell you about 'the Negro.' I want to tell you about Cliven Bundy</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/7wW7myJALXA/-Cliven-Bundy-wants-to-tell-you-about-the-Negro-I-want-to-tell-you-about-Cliven-Bundy</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/78226/large/RTR3KZO5.jpg?1397683866" alt="Rancher Cliven Bundy (back 2nd L) talks on stage beside Clark County Sheriff Douglas Gillespie (back 3rd L) in Bunkerville, Nevada, April 12, 2014. Gillespie announced the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) was ceasing its cattle roundup operation. Armed U.S" width="550" height="394" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='353' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/775.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a 67-year-old white Republican &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294262/-Conservative-hero-Cliven-Bundy-I-want-to-tell-you-one-more-thing-I-know-about-the-Negro"&gt;begins a sentence&lt;/a&gt; with "I want to tell you one more thing I know about the Negro," you know the sentence is not ending well. But deadbeat rancher and domestic terrorist Cliven Bundy &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/us/politics/rancher-proudly-breaks-the-law-becoming-a-hero-in-the-west.html?_r=1"&gt;wasn't content to stop with mere racism&lt;/a&gt;, however undisguised. No, he went ahead and added a dose of flagrant hypocrisy to the mix:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“I want to tell you one more thing I know about the Negro ... because they were basically on government subsidy, so now what do they do?” he asked.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Oh! Basically on government subsidy. Well, a man who's been grazing his cattle on federal land for 20 years without even paying the ridiculously low (effectively: subsidized) rates he legally owed should know a thing or two about government subsidy. This is a man who sparked an armed standoff with the federal government in an effort to avoid paying the &lt;i&gt;more than $1 million&lt;/i&gt; he owes. And he's talking about how the effects of government subsidy on black people are that:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“They abort their young children, they put their young men in jail, because they never learned how to pick cotton. And I’ve often wondered, are they better off as slaves, picking cotton and having a family life and doing things, or are they better off under government subsidy? They didn’t get no more freedom. They got less freedom.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Does government subsidy somehow work differently for white ranchers with 14 children? Sorry! Stupid question, I realize. Cliven Bundy is a special snowflake to whom no rules apply, ever. He gets to illegally graze cattle on public land for decades and take up arms against the federal government, and then when the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; comes calling to write about them, he gets to hold forth about how the Negroes were better off under slavery and it not only doesn't make the headline, you have to read down 11 paragraphs to get to what would seem to be significant information about who this guy is. But apparently the &lt;i&gt;Times&lt;/i&gt; thought the more significant piece of information in the article was that Bundy "savors the audience that rallied to his side." What a piece of hard-hitting news &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; is—deadbeat on ego trip savors ego trip.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=7wW7myJALXA:CCnBjp9ftvk:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/7wW7myJALXA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Cliven Bundy</category>
<category>Racism</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294275</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 13:49:16 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294275/-Cliven-Bundy-wants-to-tell-you-about-the-Negro-I-want-to-tell-you-about-Cliven-Bundy</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Republicans 'repeal' agenda is fringe even in Southern red states</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/xNnJjSvqwew/-Republicans-repeal-agenda-is-fringe-even-in-Southern-red-states</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79624/large/1401913_729213463789686_935528257_o.jpg?1398293435" alt="Mary Landrieu speaking at podium" width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;On health insurance, Sen. Mary Landrieu is in sync with her state.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79617/small/NYtimes-kff.png?1398291925" alt="Poll results chart, showing less than a third of respondents in AR, LA, KY, and NC want government uninvolved in providing health insurance to middle-income people." width="250" height="402" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/upshot/health-laws-middle-ground-approach-leaves-it-unloved.html"&gt;analyzing&lt;/a&gt; its own poll:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Health Law’s Middle-Ground Approach Leaves It Unloved&lt;/blockquote&gt;
That's one way to look at it. But take a closer look at the results in the chart to the right. There are three options: 1) government should stay out of health insurance, 2) government should subsidize insurance, and 3) government should provide that insurance (single payer or public option).
&lt;p&gt;Option 1 is the Republican position. Option 3 is the liberal one. Option 2 is Obamacare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So sure, we see support split roughly three ways between the three options, hence, a "divided nation."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I'm more fixated on Option 1, the Republican position, full repeal. Because even in solidly red Arkansas, Kentucky and Louisiana, and purple North Carolina, the Republican position is held by only about a third of the electorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you have Republicans running around all four states screaming about Obamacare repeal, yet two-thirds of the voters favor government involvement in health care, or the Democratic position. THAT'S the corner they've painted themselves into. THAT'S what's going to ultimately kill them this year. And all of that despite the $100+ million the Kochs have spent over the past several years undermining the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've consistently argued that the Affordable Care Act will be a net positive for Democrats this year, and certainly Republicans are already flailing around looking for &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294067/-With-Obamacare-losing-juice-Senate-Republicans-officially-flailing"&gt;a Plan B&lt;/a&gt;. But numbers like this point to even bigger problems for Republicans than I ever dreamed. It's not just that they're trying to &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1293889/-Mitch-McConnell-wants-to-take-away-insurance-from-400-000-constituents"&gt;take away insurance&lt;/a&gt; from hundreds of thousands of their constituents. It's they're utterly and completely out of sync with the voters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if these Southern conservative states feel this way, what hope do Republicans have?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=xNnJjSvqwew:ZdHEyZE47KQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/xNnJjSvqwew" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (kos)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Arkansas</category>
<category>Elections</category>
<category>Health Care</category>
<category>Kentucky</category>
<category>Koch Brothers</category>
<category>Louisiana</category>
<category>North Carolina</category>
<category>Senate</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294138</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 14:30:36 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294138/-Republicans-repeal-agenda-is-fringe-even-in-Southern-red-states</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cartoon: Lucky Ducky, in 'State of Denial'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/-fugEG41Co4/-Cartoon-Lucky-Ducky-in-State-nbsp-of-nbsp-Denial</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79504/lightbox/1185ckCOMIC-lucky-ducky---state-of-denial.png?1398250774"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79504/large/1185ckCOMIC-lucky-ducky---state-of-denial.png?1398250774" alt="" width="550" height="724" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the INNER HIVE for early access to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/rubenbolling"&gt;@RubenBolling&lt;/a&gt;'s Tom the Dancing Bug comics and more fun stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"I used to spend 20 dollars a year on TOM THE DANCING BUG collections… Happy to support him and pass the word."&lt;/i&gt; -Neil Gaiman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href="http://tomthedancingbug.us5.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=4d6df9a3a43c24c46117fcdb4&amp;amp;id=653643a5fd"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt; for information.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=-fugEG41Co4:U4Jew3AP__c:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/-fugEG41Co4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (RubenBolling)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Cartoons</category>
<category>Comics</category>
<category>Health Care</category>
<category>hollingsworth hound</category>
<category>Lucky Ducky</category>
<category>Medicaid</category>
<category>Poverty</category>
<category>tom the dancing bug</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293991</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 13:50:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1293991/-Cartoon-Lucky-Ducky-in-State-nbsp-of-nbsp-Denial</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>FCC to consider rule gutting Net Neutrality</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/G2WPq-DeZww/-FCC-to-consider-rule-gutting-Net-nbsp-Neutrality</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/67000/large/RTX16FJ9.jpg?1391026006" alt="U.S. FCC Chairman Tom Wheeler testifies before the House Communications and Technology panel on Capitol Hill in Washington December 12, 2013. REUTERS/Gary Cameron (UNITED STATES - Tags: POLITICS TRANSPORT BUSINESS TELECOMS) - RTX16FJ9" width="550" height="369" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;FCC Chair Tom Wheeler&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Federal Communications Commission Chairman Tom Wheeler will propose a new set of rules issued in response to a January federal court decision that tossed out the agency's prior Open Internet rules, &lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/technology/fcc-new-net-neutrality-rules.html"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. It also reports that the proposed rules will essentially gut net neutrality, allowing Internet service providers what they've always wanted—the ability to charge content companies extra for preferential treatment. Pay, and you get more bandwidth, a bigger tube to send yourself out. Don't pay, you'll be last on the priority list for having your content distributed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The new rules, according to the people briefed on them, will allow a company like Comcast or Verizon to negotiate separately with each content company – like Netflix, Amazon, Disney or Google – and charge different companies different amounts for priority service.
&lt;p&gt;That, of course, could increase costs for content companies, which would then have an incentive to pass on those costs to consumers as part of their subscription prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents of net neutrality have feared that such a framework would empower large, wealthy companies and prevent small start-ups, which might otherwise be the next Twitter or Facebook, for example, from gaining any traction in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
That's not the only fear. It will also be a potential disaster for sites like this one, and for nonprofits, for small businesses, for any content provider that doesn't have the big bucks to pay for priority treatment. That in turn will hurt you, the consumer of information and services via the Internet.
&lt;p&gt;The rules will be considered by the commissioners for the next two weeks, before a vote on them on May 15. Stay tuned for our action to fight this proposed rule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=G2WPq-DeZww:zUIZTE1bXqs:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/G2WPq-DeZww" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Federal Communications Commission</category>
<category>Net Neutrality</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Tom Wheeler</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294157</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 23:09:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294157/-FCC-to-consider-rule-gutting-Net-nbsp-Neutrality</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Daily Kos Elections Morning Digest: NYT polls are positive for Democrats, but samples pose questions</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/c6Z1pfmzS4E/-Daily-Kos-Elections-Morning-Digest-NYT-polls-are-positive-for-Democrats-but-samples-pose-questions</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;a href="http://campaigns.dailykos.com/signup_page/electionsdigest"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images1.dailykos.com/i/user/73/Elections-MorningDigest.jpg" alt="Daily Kos Elections Morning Digest banner" height="100" width="550" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Want the scoop on hot races around the country? Get the digest emailed to you each weekday morning. &lt;a href="http://campaigns.dailykos.com/signup_page/electionsdigest"&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Leading Off&lt;/b&gt;:
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#1" id="1" name="1"&gt;•&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Senate&lt;/b&gt;: As part of the launch of their new data-focused site called &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/upshot/"&gt;The Upshot&lt;/a&gt; (which has already put out some interesting work), the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; has released &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2014/04/23/upshot/24upshot-south-poll.html"&gt;new polls in four Southern states&lt;/a&gt;, conducted in conjunction with the Kaiser Family Foundation. The results range from middling to very positive for Democrats, and we'll get to the toplines right away, but let me warn you that there are some &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; serious red flags with sample composition ahead.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;b&gt;AR-Sen&lt;/b&gt;: Mark Pryor (D-inc): 46, Tom Cotton (R): 36
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;AR-Gov&lt;/b&gt;: Mike Ross (D): 40, Asa Hutchinson (R): 41&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;KY-Sen&lt;/b&gt;: Alison Grimes (D): 43, Mitch McConnell (R-inc): 44; Grimes: 41, Matt Bevin (R): 35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;LA-Sen&lt;/b&gt;: Mary Landrieu (D-inc): 42, Bill Cassidy (R): 18, Paul Hollis (R): 5, Rob Maness (R): 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;NC-Sen&lt;/b&gt;: Kay Hagan (D-inc): 42, Thom Tillis (R): 40; Hagan: 41, Greg Brannon (R): 39&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
These numbers are all mostly in line with what we've seen lately, though that 10-point lead for Pryor is extremely gaudy. Of course, it's not the only double-digit edge he's sported recently, but &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/11/1291121/-Daily-Kos-Elections-Morning-Digest-Angus-King-threatens-to-reduce-the-GOP-s-magic-number-by-one?detail=hide#16"&gt;we had questions&lt;/a&gt; about that last poll, too. And boy do we have questions about all of these.
&lt;p&gt;Rather unusually, the &lt;i&gt;Times&lt;/i&gt; conducted a poll of all adults, then further broke down the results by registered voters—but only for certain questions. So while they asked respondents how they voted for president in 2012, they only reported the "all adults" results, and those numbers &lt;a href="http://grab.by/whM4"&gt;just made no sense&lt;/a&gt;. After a bit of a firestorm erupted over this quirky decision, the paper then released the breakdowns &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Nate_Cohn/status/458993171867762688/photo/1"&gt;among registered voters&lt;/a&gt;, but the problem is, they're still very strange:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;a href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Bl6r26QCAAA2kS3.png:large"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79551/large/Bl6r26QCAAA2kS3.png?1398272303" alt="Crosstabs of April 2014 NYT polls on Obama-Romney 2012 vote." width="550" height="210" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;(click for larger)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Romney carrying Arkansas by just 2 points? (He won by 24.) Obama &lt;i&gt;winning&lt;/i&gt; Louisiana by 4? (He lost by 17.) And 19 percent of Kentucky voters saying they didn't vote in 2012, but nevertheless plan to in a midterm? It's all hard to figure. Sensing a problem, the &lt;i&gt;Times&lt;/i&gt;' Nate Cohn &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/upshot/why-criticism-of-poll-is-misguided.html"&gt;quickly penned a defense&lt;/a&gt;, calling the polls' critics "misguided."
&lt;p&gt;Cohn argues that the surveys accurately measured Obama's vote share, but that many Romney supporters abandoned him as the loser, preferring instead to they didn't remember who they backed, or went with "someone else." Cohn says that these voters were "overwhelmingly white," which in the racially polarized South buttresses the notion that they were in fact Romney partisans. (Race is a very strong predictor of voting behavior in much of the southern U.S.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, other pollsters who ask this demographic question don't seem to have this issue. For instance, &lt;a href="http://www.publicpolicypolling.com/pdf/2014/PPP_Release_NC_408.pdf#page=3"&gt;a PPP poll&lt;/a&gt; of North Carolina earlier this month found 49 percent of respondents saying they voted for Romney and 47 for Obama (very close to the 2012 results), with just 4 percent saying they weren't sure or picked another candidate. Put another way, if someone released a Michigan poll showing Terri Lynn Land up 10 and Romney carrying the state by the same amount, we'd question those results sharply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, Cohn tries to offer a further sanity check by pointing out that Obama's approvals "look about right." Like the toplines, they do indeed mostly make sense. But it's a curious approach from Cohn, who castigated PPP for alleged methodological deficiencies while arguing that the firm's accuracy was largely beside the point. &lt;a href="http://www.newrepublic.com/article/114682/ppp-polling-methodology-opaque-flawed"&gt;Wrote Cohn&lt;/a&gt;: "Pollsters, though, tend to judge one another based more on methodology than record."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, though, political professionals judge pollsters on their results, and indeed, it's perfectly acceptable to point to those results to validate a survey, just as the &lt;i&gt;Times&lt;/i&gt; has tried to do here. Whether these results are in fact valid is a separate matter, though, and as the foregoing shows, there are still plenty of reasons for skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=c6Z1pfmzS4E:2Oja4AMWlRw:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/c6Z1pfmzS4E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Nir)</author>
<category>Adriano Espaillat</category>
<category>AK-Sen</category>
<category>Alison Grimes</category>
<category>American Crossroads</category>
<category>Americans For Prosperity</category>
<category>Angel Taveras</category>
<category>AR-Gov</category>
<category>AR-Sen</category>
<category>Asa Hutchinson</category>
<category>Bill Cassidy</category>
<category>Bill Clinton</category>
<category>Bob Beauprez</category>
<category>Bob Johnson</category>
<category>CA-33</category>
<category>Charlie Rangel</category>
<category>Clay Pell</category>
<category>CO-Gov</category>
<category>CO-Sen</category>
<category>Cory Gardner</category>
<category>David Brat</category>
<category>DKE Daily Digests</category>
<category>Elections</category>
<category>Eric Cantor</category>
<category>Fabrizio Lee</category>
<category>GA-01</category>
<category>GA-Sen</category>
<category>Gary Peters</category>
<category>Gina Raimondo</category>
<category>Greg Brannon</category>
<category>James Lankford</category>
<category>Jeanne Shaheen</category>
<category>Joe Miller</category>
<category>John Hickenlooper</category>
<category>John Kasich</category>
<category>Kaiser Family Foundation</category>
<category>Kay Hagan</category>
<category>Kevin Strouse</category>
<category>KY-Sen</category>
<category>Mark Burke</category>
<category>Mark Pryor</category>
<category>Mark Udall</category>
<category>Mary Landrieu</category>
<category>Matt Bevin</category>
<category>Matt Miller</category>
<category>MI-Sen</category>
<category>Mike Kopp</category>
<category>Mike Ross</category>
<category>Mitch McConnell</category>
<category>Monica Wehby</category>
<category>NC-Sen</category>
<category>New York Times</category>
<category>NH-Sen</category>
<category>NM-Gov</category>
<category>NY-13</category>
<category>OH-GOV</category>
<category>OK-Sen-B</category>
<category>Oklahomans for a Conservative Future</category>
<category>OR-Sen</category>
<category>PA-08</category>
<category>Paul Hollis</category>
<category>Phil Gingrey</category>
<category>Polls</category>
<category>Public Opinion Strategies</category>
<category>Public Policy Polling</category>
<category>Quinnipiac</category>
<category>RI-Gov</category>
<category>Rob Maness</category>
<category>Ron Johnson</category>
<category>Ron Kind</category>
<category>Russ Feingold</category>
<category>Scott Gessler</category>
<category>Scott Stringer</category>
<category>Scott Walker</category>
<category>susana martinez</category>
<category>T.W. Shannon</category>
<category>Thom Tillis</category>
<category>Tom Tancredo</category>
<category>VA-07</category>
<category>WI-Gov</category>
<category>WI-Sen</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294175</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 12:00:16 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294175/-Daily-Kos-Elections-Morning-Digest-NYT-polls-are-positive-for-Democrats-but-samples-pose-questions</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Conservative hero Cliven Bundy: 'I want to tell you one more thing I know about the Negro ...'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/XMa0-8T8w7s/-Conservative-hero-Cliven-Bundy-I-want-to-tell-you-one-more-thing-I-know-about-the-Negro</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/78437/large/RTR3KXCW.jpg?1397764231" alt="Rancher Cliven Bundy poses at his home in Bunkerville, Nevada, April 11, 2014. Armed U.S. rangers are rounding up cattle on federal land in Nevada in a rare showdown with Bundy, a rancher who has illegally grazed his herd on public lands for decades, as c" width="550" height="365" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;"I wish I was in the land of cotton, old times they are not forgotten ..."&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
What a surprise: It turns out that Cliven Bundy, the deadbeat cattle rancher who has become a &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/18/1293021/-Fox-News-primetime-lineup-is-obsessed-with-grazing-fee-disputes"&gt;hero&lt;/a&gt; to conservative politicians and pundits, is nothing but—well, besides that whole deadbeat cattle rancher thing—a &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/us/politics/rancher-proudly-breaks-the-law-becoming-a-hero-in-the-west.html?_r=0"&gt;racist&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“I want to tell you one more thing I know about the Negro ... because they were basically on government subsidy, so now what do they do?” he asked. “They abort their young children, they put their young men in jail, because they never learned how to pick cotton. And I’ve often wondered, are they better off as slaves, picking cotton and having a family life and doing things, or are they better off under government subsidy? They didn’t get no more freedom. They got less freedom.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Coming up next: Watching conservatives awkwardly distance themselves from the remarks themselves while still embracing their hero's "principles."
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="update"&gt;&lt;a name="20140424053602" href="/story/2014/04/24/1294262/-Conservative-hero-Cliven-Bundy-I-want-to-tell-you-one-more-thing-I-know-about-the-Negro#20140424053602"&gt;&lt;b&gt; 5:36 AM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; For more discussion, see &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294222/-Cliven-Bundy-want-to-tell-you-one-more-thing-I-know-about-the-negro"&gt;this diary&lt;/a&gt; from SamLoomis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=XMa0-8T8w7s:6c8wXRUQMwc:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/XMa0-8T8w7s" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Barbara Morrill)</author>
<category>Cliven Bundy</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294262</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 12:33:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294262/-Conservative-hero-Cliven-Bundy-I-want-to-tell-you-one-more-thing-I-know-about-the-Negro</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Daily Kos Radio is LIVE at 9am ET!</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/K4NUuVlECWA/-Daily-Kos-Radio-is-LIVE-at-9am-ET</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/blog/dailykosradio"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/4434/large/398x296_FacebookInStream.jpg?1346121562" alt="Daily Kos Radio logo" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Kos Radio's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show podcasts are now available through iTunes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen LIVE at 9:00 ET, here:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Daily Kos Radio Player&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-l"&gt;&lt;object classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" width="180" height="120" bgcolor="#FFFFFF"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/ffmp3-config.swf" /&gt;
&lt;param name="flashvars" value="url=http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls;;&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;codec=mp3&amp;amp;volume=20&amp;amp;buffering=5&amp;amp;skin=http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/skins/mcclean/ffmp3-mcclean.xml&amp;amp;title=NetrootsRadio&amp;amp;welcome=We%20are NetrootsRadio" /&gt;
&lt;param name="wmode" value="window" /&gt;
&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;
&lt;param name="scale" value="noscale" /&gt;
&lt;embed src="http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/ffmp3-config.swf" flashvars="url=http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls;;&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;codec=mp3&amp;amp;volume=20&amp;amp;buffering=5&amp;amp;skin=http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/skins/mcclean/ffmp3-mcclean.xml&amp;amp;title=NetrootsRadio&amp;amp;welcome=We%20are NetrootsRadio" width="180" scale="noscale" height="120" wmode="window" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls"&gt;Click this Link&lt;/a&gt; to Listen on your iTunes, Winamp or Windows Media Player
&lt;p&gt;Can't see the live stream and/or podcast players in these posts? Do you use NoScript or something similar to control Javascript? Want to? Remember to enable Libsyn and Shoutcastplayer, and you'll see our players every morning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or if you prefer, why not &lt;a href="http://landing.stitcher.com/?vurl=dailykos"&gt;download the Stitcher app&lt;/a&gt; on your favorite mobile device, and search for the Netroots Radio live stream? And hey, when you do, be sure to sign up with the promo code DAILYKOS, and earn Daily Kos Radio $1 in the Stitcher affiliate program!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do remember to "favorite" us while you're at Stitcher. We're bouncing up and down in the rankings these days, and the more of you who help us, the more listeners out there who'll find us on the Stitcher network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miss our last LIVE show? You can catch it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2798246/height/302/width/540/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="302" width="540" scrolling="no" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need more info on how to listen? Find it below the fold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=K4NUuVlECWA:9Qw22O_xg48:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/K4NUuVlECWA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Waldman)</author>
<category>Daily Kos Radio</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294209</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 12:30:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294209/-Daily-Kos-Radio-is-LIVE-at-9am-ET</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cheers and Jeers: Thursday</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/EMHTjV45HOI/-Cheers-and-Jeers-Thursday</link>
<description>&lt;div id="uimg_center"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images2.dailykos.com/i/user/8411/CheersAndJeers.jpg" alt="C&amp;amp;J Banner" height="100" width="550" title="C&amp;amp;J Banner" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the GREAT STATE OF MAINE…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;12 Weeks 'Til &lt;a href="http://www.netrootsnation.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Netroots Nation 2014!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your weekly update on all things Detroit, which I shall now read aloud with perfect diction while drinking this glass of water:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/78991/small/schol2.gif?1398016890" alt="Banner for Netroots nation/DFA scholarship competition 2014." width="200" height="30" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
• The annual Netroots Nation/Democracy for America &lt;a href="http://www.netrootsnation.org/apply-for-a-dfa-scholarship-to-nn14/" target="_blank"&gt;scholarship competition is going on now&lt;/a&gt; through May 12th. The five applicants with the most votes overall will automatically win a scholarship &lt;u&gt;covering the cost of registration and lodging&lt;/u&gt;. The remaining 25 spots will be chosen by a selection committee. For more details, &lt;a href="http://nn14.democracyforamerica.com/" target="_blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. (You can also nominate someone you believe is deserving of a scholarship at that link.)
&lt;p&gt;• This sounds very cool:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-l"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79589/small/Woolworth.jpg?1398278625" alt="1937 Woolworth sit-down strike" width="220" height="170" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;1937 Woolworth strikers&lt;br /&gt;
-&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Join the AFL-CIO and the Michigan Labor History Society on Wednesday, July 16 (the day before Netroots Nation kicks off) for a tour of some of Detroit’s historic sites: where Martin Luther King Jr. first delivered “I Have a Dream"…the last stop on the Underground Railroad…the site of the Woolworth’s sit-down strike of 1937…Cadillac Square…the newspaper strike of 1996. The tour starts at Cobo Center and will wrap up with a drink at the Anchor Bar with the organizers from the 1996 newspaper strike who will share their stories. The tour is free, but space is limited.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
To reserve your spot, &lt;a href="http://www.netrootsnation.org/take-a-social-and-economic-justice-tour-of-detroit/" target="_blank"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;• The list of the forty training sessions is up. They range from data and analytics to field organizing to mastering social media. &lt;a href="http://www.netrootsnation.org/nn14/?nn-agenda-filter-date=&amp;amp;nn-agenda-filter-type=training&amp;amp;nn-agenda-filter-timing=&amp;amp;nn-agenda-filter-orderby=alpha" target="_blank"&gt;Take a look&lt;/a&gt;. Coming soon: the list of panels and keynoters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Last June, regular NN attendee Chris Savage of the legendary Michigan-based &lt;i&gt;Eclectablog&lt;/i&gt; wrote about &lt;a href="http://www.eclectablog.com/2013/06/breaking-netroots-nation-conference-comes-to-detroit-in-2014-nn13-nn14.html" target="_blank"&gt;how and why the 2014 convention came to be&lt;/a&gt; in the Horseless Carriage City. The crux:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/59365/small/detroitskyline.jpg?1385585430" alt="Photo of Detroit skyline, NN banner" width="310" height="140" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;-&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Why Detroit? Because Michigan represents the future of our country if we don’t regain political control of our state governments. Michigan is a majority Democratic state that is run by Republicans due to gerrymandering and unethical political games that give them power they do not deserve to represent a citizenry that disagrees with them on most things. […]
&lt;p&gt;Because many of the issues that progressives are passionate about are in full display in Michigan in general and in Detroit in particular: Immigration. Women’s reproductive freedom. Collective bargaining and right to work. Marriage equality and civil rights for the LGBT community. Environmental concerns. All of these issues and more are playing out in sharp relief in Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
By the way, Eclectablog is hosting a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/273015872866852/" target="_blank"&gt;10th Blogiversary party on May 1&lt;/a&gt; in Ypsilanti with guest Lizz Winstead. Congrats on your first decade, Chris.
&lt;p&gt;• We hope you'll join us at the Daily Kos/C&amp;amp;J eat-'n-greet in Detroit on Wednesday evening, July 16th. To add your name to the RSVP list, &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/newthread/navajo" target="_blank"&gt;email Navajo&lt;/a&gt;. We'll keep you posted with updates by screeching into your driveway at 3am and hollering detauils through a bullhorn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Registration and Hotel info are &lt;a href="http://www.netrootsnation.org/register/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.netrootsnation.org/nn14/book-a-room/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Follow NN14 via &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Netroots_Nation" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synchronize your watches: the convention starts in 84 days. Bring comfortable shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers and Jeers starts below the fold... [Swoosh!!] RIGHTNOW! [Gong!!]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=EMHTjV45HOI:7jSDIy2DstQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/EMHTjV45HOI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Bill in Portland Maine)</author>
<category>Cheers and Jeers</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294032</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 12:18:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294032/-Cheers-and-Jeers-Thursday</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Abbreviated Pundit Round-up: 2014 and beyond</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/HZIMgG-i010/-Abbreviated-Pundit-Round-up-2014-and-beyond</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79685/large/400x444xmedicaid-enrollmentA.jpg?1398352938" alt="% increase in insured under poverty line via ACA" width="402" height="445" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;See Harold Pollack link below&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-fix/wp/2014/04/23/black-voters-could-decide-who-controls-the-senate-in-2015-heres-how/"&gt;Aaron Blake&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;Black voters played a huge role in delivering Barack Obama to the White House in 2008 and 2012. And in 2014, they will play a huge role in determining whether the president's party can stop Republicans from taking the Senate.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/post-partisan/wp/2014/04/23/defeating-obamas-kryptonite-with-the-black-vote/"&gt;Jonathan Capehart&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;The Post’s Aaron Blake has a terrific piece listing the four ways “black voters could decide who controls the Senate in 2015.” He writes that “[s]ix of the 16 states with the highest black populations are holding key Senate contests in 2014.” The key nugget in the Blake post: “Basically every black voter who stays home is a Democratic voter who stays home,” he writes. “Black voters generally vote more than 90 percent Democratic, so just about every drop in turnout among black voters pretty clearly comes at Democrats’ expense.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
More politics and policy below the fold.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=HZIMgG-i010:PMcxjS6mUlc:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/HZIMgG-i010" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Greg Dworkin)</author>
<category>Abbreviated Pundit Round-up</category>
<category>APR</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294142</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 11:30:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/24/1294142/-Abbreviated-Pundit-Round-up-2014-and-beyond</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Open thread for nightowls: 'Post-legal' America</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/WW2BKHastNM/-Open-thread-for-nightowls-Post-legal-America</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/8770/large/Blade-Runner-Owl-.jpeg?1350941429" alt="night owls " /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/179448/why-kidnapping-torture-and-perjury-are-no-longer-crimes-washington#"&gt;Tom Engelhardt&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;With Cartwright as a possible exception, the members of the national security state, unlike the rest of us, exist in what might be called &amp;nbsp;"post-legal” America. They know that, no matter how heinous the crime, they will not be brought to justice for it. The list of potentially serious criminal acts for which no one has had to take responsibility in a court of law is long, and never tabulated in one place. Consider this, then, an initial run-down on seven of the most obvious crimes and misdemeanors of this era for which no one has been held accountable.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2005/04/23/109079/-Extremist-Sunday"&gt;Blast from the Past&lt;/a&gt;. At Daily Kos on this date in &lt;b&gt;2005&lt;/b&gt;—&lt;i&gt;Extremist Sunday&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width="96%" align="center" style="background-color:rgb(249,246,234);border_collapse: collapse; border: 1px dashed black;" defang_cellpadding="5%"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tomorrow in Louisville Senator Frist and his allies will demonstrate a level of blatant extremism and hate that one thought had been removed from respectable discourse in our country. Now we find it embraced by the Republican Leader of the Senate. Frank Rich has some thoughts:
&lt;p&gt;The fraudulence of "Justice Sunday" begins but does not end with its sham claims to solidarity with the civil rights movement of that era. "The filibuster was once abused to protect racial bias," says the flier for tonight's show, "and now it is being used against people of faith." In truth, Bush judicial nominees have been approved in exactly the same numbers as were Clinton second-term nominees. Of the 13 federal appeals courts, 10 already have a majority of Republican appointees. So does the Supreme Court. &lt;b&gt;It's a lie&lt;/b&gt; to argue, as Tom DeLay did last week, that such a judiciary is the "left's last legislative body," and that Justice Anthony Kennedy, a Reagan appointee, is the poster child for "outrageous" judicial overreach. Our courts are as highly populated by Republicans as the other two branches of government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The "Justice Sunday" mob is also &lt;b&gt;lying&lt;/b&gt; when it claims to despise activist judges as a matter of principle. Only weeks ago it was desperately seeking activist judges who might intervene in the Terri Schiavo case as boldly as Scalia &amp;amp; Co. had in Bush v. Gore. The real "Justice Sunday" agenda lies elsewhere. As Bill Maher summed it up for Jay Leno on the "Tonight" show last week: " 'Activist judges' is a code word for gay." The judges being verbally tarred and feathered are those who have decriminalized gay sex (in a Supreme Court decision written by Justice Kennedy) as they once did abortion and who countenance marriage rights for same-sex couples. This is the animus that dares not speak its name tonight. To paraphrase the "Justice Sunday" flier, now it's the anti-filibuster campaign that is being abused to protect bias, this time against gay people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thenation"&gt;Tweet of the Day&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thenation/status/459050828746092545"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/556400632/Small_n_normal.png" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In the wealthiest country in history, almost 30 million people wish they had full-time work. &lt;a href="http://t.co/wKnrmIhCmC"&gt;http://t.co/...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/thenation"&gt;@thenation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2798246/height/200/width/250/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="200" width="250" scrolling="no" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
On &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294045/-Daily-Kos-Radio-s-KITM-podcast-Joan-Greg-ACA-roundup-Impeach-Nixon-Cheerleaders-wage-theft"&gt;today's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show&lt;/a&gt;: Trying to find the podcast? Congration You Done it! Cliven Bundy's got Marco Rubio Syndrome. &lt;strong&gt;Greg Dworkin&lt;/strong&gt; tells us Digby's won a Hillman, points to &lt;em&gt;NYT's&lt;/em&gt; 2014 analysis, and says Medicaid expansion's pretty popular. &lt;strong&gt;Joan McCarter&lt;/strong&gt; says birth control coverage's pretty popular, too. And so's the AR "private option." More of the Gop "no backsies!" theory of governance. ALEC goes Bundy &amp;amp; Grijalva pushes back. Nixon (a 3rd one) to face impeachment? Bill Cassidy imagines a pivotal historical role for himself. NFL cheerleaders join the fight against wage theft. And listener Gilbert Aquino takes a stab at answering our theological questions.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294074/-High-Impact-Posts-April-22-2014"&gt;High Impact Posts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1292550/-Top-Comments-Antisocial-Social-Security"&gt;Top Comments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=WW2BKHastNM:XTMoW-2ZW-0:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/WW2BKHastNM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Hunter)</author>
<category>National Security</category>
<category>Open Thread for Night Owls</category>
<category>Rendition</category>
<category>Torture</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294173</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 03:30:16 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294173/-Open-thread-for-nightowls-Post-legal-America</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Economics Daily Digest: Repealing health care reform gets harder every day</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/Ai9k4bw6qPY/-Economics-Daily-Digest-Repealing-health-care-reform-gets-harder-every-day</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/12380/large/EconomicsDailyDigest_(1).jpg?1355365637" alt="Economics Daily Digest by the Roosevelt Institute banner" width="550" height="100" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By Rachel Goldfarb, originally published on &lt;a href="http://www.nextnewdeal.net/daily-digest-april-23-repealing-health-care-reform-gets-harder-every-day"&gt;Next New Deal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://rooseveltinstitute.us1.list-manage2.com/subscribe?u=5044841afea7ba83dc11db61f&amp;amp;id=e4428ba350"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to receive the Daily Digest via email.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ted Cruz's Worst Nightmare Is Coming True&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2014/04/obamacares-success-changes-everything-105914.html?ml=m_t3_2h#.U1erf-ZdVpk"&gt;Politico&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Americans get used to having access to affordable health care, repeal will become less and less likely, writes Roosevelt Institute Senior Fellow Richard Kirsch. That's just as Senator Cruz predicted last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;AT&amp;amp;T Tries to Bully the Government&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.bloombergview.com/articles/2014-04-22/at-t-tries-to-bully-the-government"&gt;Bloomberg View&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roosevelt Institute Fellow Susan Crawford says the Federal Communications Commission should stand strong and limit how many spectrum licenses any one wireless carrier can buy at its upcoming auction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Elizabeth Warren is the Teacher&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.esquire.com/blogs/politics/elizabeth-warren-teacher-0514"&gt;Esquire&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles P. Pierce profiles Sen. Warren's work in academia and politics, framing her as an eternal educator. Today, she continues to educate on critical issues like financial reform—but also makes that reform happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Elizabeth Warren’s Needed Call for Student Loan Reform&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/katrina-vanden-heuvel-elizabeth-warrens-needed-call-for-student-loan-reform/2014/04/21/baaeb89c-c988-11e3-93eb-6c0037dde2ad_story.html"&gt;WaPo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With graduation season upon us, Katrina vanden Heuvel, a member of the Roosevelt Institute's board of directors, praises Sen. Warren's work on student debt, which she says is holding back the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The American Middle Class Is No Longer the World’s Richest&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/23/upshot/the-american-middle-class-is-no-longer-the-worlds-richest.html?rref=upshot&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data shows that middle-income people around the world have experienced greater gains over the past three decades than Americans, write David Leonhardt and Kevin Quealy. They tie this to rising income inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Waiter, Am I Subsidizing Your Pay?&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href="http://otherwords.org/subsidizing-pay-for-servers-tipped-minimum/"&gt;Other Words&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marjorie Elizabeth Wood argues that taxpayers are heavily subsidizing the restaurant industry, which takes advantage of tax loopholes for high CEO pay and doesn't pay its workers a living wage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Roosevelt Take:&lt;/b&gt; Roosevelt Institute Fellow and Director of Research Susan Holmberg and Roosevelt Institute | Campus Network alumna Lydia Austin discuss the performance pay loophole in their &lt;a href="http://rooseveltinstitute.org/policy-and-ideas/big-ideas/fixing-hole-how-tax-code-executive-pay-distorts-economic-incentives"&gt;white paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Revolt of the Cities&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;a href="http://prospect.org/article/revolt-cities"&gt;TAP&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harold Meyerson looks at the new wave of progressive mayors and city councils, elected primarily with labor community coalitions. He says this new city leadership is reshaping American liberalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=Ai9k4bw6qPY:qvcmKu0O_xI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/Ai9k4bw6qPY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Roosevelt Institute)</author>
<category>Economy</category>
<category>Financial Sector</category>
<category>Health Care</category>
<category>Telecommunications</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293994</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 12:13:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1293994/-Economics-Daily-Digest-Repealing-health-care-reform-gets-harder-every-day</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>New Daily Kos Elections interactive legislative maps of Washington, New Mexico, and New Jersey</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/K2L3e8ja6pE/-New-Daily-Kos-Elections-interactive-legislative-maps-of-Washington-New-Mexico-and-New-Jersey</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This week we have interactive state legislative district maps for Washington, New Mexico, and New Jersey. Each legislative chamber is mapped out using the &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/07/09/1220127/-Daily-Kos-Elections-2012-election-results-by-congressional-and-legislative-districts?detail=hide"&gt;presidential election results&lt;/a&gt; calculated by Daily Kos Elections, the legislative election results, and some info on each legislator. For maps of 21 other states' legislative chambers see the &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/03/19/1277349/-Daily-Kos-Elections-releases-new-interactive-maps-of-11-state-legislatures-with-tons-of-data"&gt;first&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/02/1285224/-New-Daily-Kos-Elections-interactive-state-legislative-maps-of-Ohio-New-Hampshire-and-Wyoming"&gt;second&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/09/1290324/-Daily-Kos-Elections-releases-new-interactive-state-legislative-maps-for-MI-RI-MN-and-SD"&gt;third&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/17/1291737/-New-Daily-Kos-Elections-interactive-legislative-maps-of-Wisconsin-Massachusetts-and-West-Virginia"&gt;fourth&lt;/a&gt; in this series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Districts in solid blue were carried by Obama and are represented by a Democrat, while those in solid red were won by Mitt Romney and are held by a Republican. Lighter red districts voted for Obama and a Republican legislator, while those in lighter blue went for Romney and a Democratic legislator. All vacant seats are assigned to the party that last won them. Note that the map displays use only the two-party vote to give you a more equivalent comparison between presidential and legislative results, but the diary and Daily Kos Elections' numbers include totals for third party candidates, though the differences are minor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="550" height="330" scrolling="no" defang_frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?q=select+col9+from+1OOLK8zmHCcB7GxJ2F74SKjnG95yHpbr_ZggFTbzj&amp;amp;viz=MAP&amp;amp;h=false&amp;amp;lat=47.30129573069118&amp;amp;lng=-120.88227699999999&amp;amp;t=1&amp;amp;z=6&amp;amp;l=col9&amp;amp;y=2&amp;amp;tmplt=3&amp;amp;hml=KML"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Washington &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/DataSource?docid=1OOLK8zmHCcB7GxJ2F74SKjnG95yHpbr_ZggFTbzj"&gt;State Senate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bipartisan commission drew Washington’s state legislative districts with an equal partisan split, but Democratic member Tim Ceis voted for the Republican plan that predictably benefited that party a modest amount. While Obama carried 34, Republicans hold nine. The GOP controls all 15 Romney districts. To make matters worse two renegade Democrats, SD-35's Tim Sheldon and SD-48's Rodney Tom (whose districts are colored in yellow), caucus with the 24 Republicans. This gives Team Red an effective majority of 26 over the remaining 23 Democrats. Sheldon is likely safe from losing to a real Democrat since the state's top-two system has all candidates run on the same primary ballot with top two vote winners advancing regardless of party. Sheldon also represents a swing district giving him some more room for error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, Rodney Tom is retiring in 2014. His seat went for Obama 62-36 and Democrats are favored to take it back, meaning the party would need to gain just one more seat for outright control of the chamber. While only half the seats are up each cycle, Republicans will be defending a lot of their 2010 gains this year, giving Democrats an excellent shot at retaking the Senate. However, the map still leans Republican with the median district voting for Obama just 54-43, putting it four points to the right of the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="550" height="330" scrolling="no" defang_frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?q=select+col9+from+1nD-HsjuBbkRwE0t8oMaU8T_ghYAGDyhlm9zqBXHD&amp;amp;viz=MAP&amp;amp;h=false&amp;amp;lat=47.30129573069118&amp;amp;lng=-120.88227699999999&amp;amp;t=1&amp;amp;z=6&amp;amp;l=col9&amp;amp;y=2&amp;amp;tmplt=3&amp;amp;hml=KML"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Washington &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/DataSource?docid=1nD-HsjuBbkRwE0t8oMaU8T_ghYAGDyhlm9zqBXHD"&gt;State House of Representatives Position 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="550" height="330" scrolling="no" defang_frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?q=select+col9+from+1gjMzqjOYCrJa1uRqjXjiY6vVaFeH_IqZhvBscLke&amp;amp;viz=MAP&amp;amp;h=false&amp;amp;lat=47.30129573069118&amp;amp;lng=-120.88227699999999&amp;amp;t=1&amp;amp;z=6&amp;amp;l=col9&amp;amp;y=2&amp;amp;tmplt=3&amp;amp;hml=KML"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Washington &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/DataSource?docid=1gjMzqjOYCrJa1uRqjXjiY6vVaFeH_IqZhvBscLke"&gt;State House of Representatives Position 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with just Idaho, Washington uses the same district map for both legislative chambers yet conducts two separate races for the lower house in each one. Obama won 68 seats to Romney's 30. Republicans hold 15 Obama seats while just two Romney seats elected Democrats, but Team Blue has a healthy 55 to 43 majority. The median seats are again the same as the Senate at 54-43 Obama, making it four percent more Republican than the state overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head below the fold to see maps for New Mexico and New Jersey.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=K2L3e8ja6pE:BTEpr_0QtAo:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/K2L3e8ja6pE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Stephen Wolf)</author>
<category>Elections</category>
<category>New Jersey</category>
<category>New Mexico</category>
<category>Pres-by-LD</category>
<category>Redistricting</category>
<category>Redistricting Resources</category>
<category>Washington</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293619</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 14:00:20 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1293619/-New-Daily-Kos-Elections-interactive-legislative-maps-of-Washington-New-Mexico-and-New-Jersey</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Federal judge rules Minnesota cannot bar purchases of coal-fired electricity from North Dakota</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/etQH7LiB9Hc/-Federal-judge-rules-Minnesota-cannot-bar-purchases-of-coal-fired-electricity-from-North-Dakota</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79151/large/LelandOldsStation_2.jpg?1398117051" alt="" width="500" height="313" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Leland Olds power station near Stanton, North Dakota.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
In a 48-page &lt;a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/219042218/Ruling-on-energy-law"&gt;ruling&lt;/a&gt; Friday, U.S. District Court Judge Susan Richard Nelson agreed with North Dakota plaintiffs and shot down a part of a 2007 Minnesota law designed to boost renewable energy. Democratic Gov. Mark Dayton has vowed to appeal and fight North Dakota's efforts to sell more coal-fired electricity to Minnesota.
&lt;p&gt;The law at issue is Minnesota's &lt;a href="http://www.house.leg.state.mn.us/hinfo/newlawsart2007-0.asp?storyid=608"&gt;Next Generation Energy Act&lt;/a&gt;, a key element of which was to reduce the state's use of fossil fuels by 15 percent of 2005 base levels by 2015, 30 percent by 2025 and 80 percent by 2050. Utilities were not to be allowed to buy more coal-fired electricity unless emissions were completely offset. North Dakota sued in 2011, saying the law violated the Constitution's interstate commerce clause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nelson wrote:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;If any or every state were to adopt similar legislation (e.g., prohibiting the use of electricity generated by different fuels or requiring compliance with unique, statutorily-mandated exemption programs subject to state approval), the current marketplace for electricity would come to a grinding halt. In an interconnected system like [the Midwest Independent System Operator], entities involved at each step of the process—generation, transmission, and distribution of electricity—would potentially be subject to multiple state laws regardless of whether they were transacting commerce outside of their home state. Such a scenario is “just the kind of competing and interlocking local economic regulation that the Commerce Clause was meant to preclude.”
&lt;p&gt;[...] For these reasons, the Court finds that, while the State of Minnesota’s goals in enacting [the statute] may have been admirable, Minnesota has projected its legislation into other states and directly regulated commerce therein. Accordingly, [the statute] constitutes impermissible extraterritorial legislation and is a per se violation of the dormant Commerce Clause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
North Dakota generates 79 percent of its electricity with coal and plans to build more coal-fired plants without emissions offsets.
&lt;p&gt;At least one environmental advocacy group, Fresh Energy, which promotes renewable energy, isn't majorly upset by Nelson's ruling. The group's executive director, Michael Noble, &lt;a href="http://www.mprnews.org/story/2014/04/18/federal-judge-strikes-down-part-of-minn-energy-law?refid=0"&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; Minnesota Public Radio: "The world is moving on from coal now. It's uneconomical, it's impractical. Consumers don't want any more coal." And they won't need it, he said, because installation of wind- and solar-generating facilities will provide all the new electricity that is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North Dakota's Republican Attorney General Wayne Stenehjem doesn't agree with that point of view: "We are continuing to look at the prospect of additional generation here because we're living in a nation that needs it. Most of our electricity does come from coal, and that's likely to be the case for a long time to come," he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stenehjem needs to catch up. The United States &lt;a href="http://www.eia.gov/electricity/monthly/epm_table_grapher.cfm?t=epmt_1_01"&gt;generated&lt;/a&gt; 39 percent of its total electricity with coal during the 12 months ending in January this year. In 2007, the year Minnesota's Next Generation law was enacted, coal generated 49 percent of the nation's electricity. Minnesota generated 46 percent of its electricity with coal in 2013, 21 percent with nuclear power and 15 percent with wind power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=etQH7LiB9Hc:hEmNQfsxC9I:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/etQH7LiB9Hc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Meteor Blades)</author>
<category>Coal</category>
<category>DK GreenRoots</category>
<category>Environment</category>
<category>Minnesota</category>
<category>North Dakota</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Renewable Energy</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293613</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 22:02:11 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/21/1293613/-Federal-judge-rules-Minnesota-cannot-bar-purchases-of-coal-fired-electricity-from-North-Dakota</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>How evil will a Republican be to deny a poor person health care? This evil.</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/SFjTM_JNFfY/-How-evil-will-a-Republican-be-to-deny-a-poor-person-health-care-This-evil</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/64704/large/RTR359FS.jpg?1389385669" alt="People wait to receive a wristband number for medical treatment at the Remote Area Medical (RAM) clinic in Wise, Virginia July 20, 2012. &amp;amp;nbsp;RAM clinics bring free medical, dental and vision care to uninsured and under-insured people across the country and a" width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Dozens wait the night for free medical treatment. Just what Republican like to see.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='353' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/687.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;Back in February, news broke of Georgia Gov. Nathan Deal's &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/02/24/1280085/-Republican-Gov-Deal-trying-to-kill-Medicaid-expansion-in-Georgia-forever"&gt;efforts&lt;/a&gt; to make sure that no governor of Georgia could ever decide to take Medicaid expansion, giving the legislature veto power over any future governor's decision to do so. But it's not just Deal. Kansas's Gov. Sam Brownback (R) is &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/dc/gop-bills-medicaid-expansion-democratic-governors?utm_content=bufferb52cf&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer"&gt;doing it too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Georgia and Kansas have left a combined 487,000 residents uncovered under Obamacare because they refused to expand Medicaid. And, though the law remains unpopular, a recent poll found that majorities of Georgians (54 percent) and Kansans (55 percent) support Medicaid expansion.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
One of the architects of the Affordable Care Act, Jonathon Gruber, &lt;a href="http://www.healthinsurance.org/blog/2014/04/08/reports-of-aca-demise-greatly-exaggerated/"&gt;told Harold Pollack&lt;/a&gt; that the Republican resistance to Medicaid expansion—leaving nearly 5 million people deliberately out of the system—is "almost awesome in its evilness." With Deal and Brownback, I think we can get rid of that "almost" qualifier.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=SFjTM_JNFfY:nWNan_QRGh8:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/SFjTM_JNFfY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Georgia</category>
<category>Kansas</category>
<category>Medicaid</category>
<category>Nathan Deal</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Sam Brownback</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293881</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 22:24:32 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293881/-How-evil-will-a-Republican-be-to-deny-a-poor-person-health-care-This-evil</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Louisiana may force doctors to give women disinformation about abortion</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/bi2h8ArPjpw/-Louisiana-may-force-doctors-to-give-women-disinformation-about-abortion</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/65282/large/Anti-abortion_protesters_outside_Red_River_Women's_Clinic_in_Fargo__N.D..png?1389810506" alt="Anti-abortion protesters outside Red River Women's Clinic in Fargo, N.D." width="550" height="298" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Fine candidates for the committee to write the Louisiana House's desired pamphlet scaring women away from abortion.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Louisiana House has passed a bill that would use false information to try to scare women away from abortion. &lt;a href="http://www.legis.la.gov/legis/BillInfo.aspx?i=225818"&gt;HB 1262&lt;/a&gt; would require that, at the beginning of the state's 24-hour waiting period, women be given a pamphlet about mental health risks that abortion opponents claim are associated with abortion. Or, as the bill puts it, women have "a right to know that undergoing an abortion may have serious psychological impacts, including severe emotional distress and mental and behavioral health afflictions." The &lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/health/2014/04/22/3429452/louisiana-abortion-risks-pamphelt/"&gt;small problem with this&lt;/a&gt; is that:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;... in reality, the research in the field has found that women who have abortions &lt;a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/id/45603029/ns/health-mental_health/t/abortion-doesnt-raise-mental-illness-risk/#.U1adxfmICFw"&gt;aren’t at any greater risk&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/2011/01/27/133237875/study-abortions-dont-cause-mental-health-issues"&gt;mental health issues&lt;/a&gt;. Although many women certainly do have mixed feelings after ending a pregnancy, they overwhelmingly say that it was the &lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/health/2013/08/06/2418181/study-abortion-emotions/"&gt;right decision for them&lt;/a&gt;. Ninety percent of women report that their primary emotion after having an abortion is relief — and when they do experience negative emotions, they’re often related to the &lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/health/2013/10/22/2814101/pushing-abortion-stigma/"&gt;societal stigma&lt;/a&gt; surrounding abortion, not because they regret their personal choice.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
But that information won't be making it into the Louisiana pamphlet, which will be put together by a committee including "Two Louisiana residents who provide pre-abortion or post-abortion counseling in association with a nonprofit organization that does not counsel for or provide abortion," which is to say an anti-abortion group; "Two attorneys licensed in Louisiana who specialize in advocacy for women and minor females who are at risk of being coerced into or psychologically harmed by abortion"; members of the state legislature who doubtless will be chosen on the basis of their enthusiasm for this offensive bill; and others who emphatically are in no way involved with any abortion provider. It's completely rigged to produce "information" that is actually disinformation.
&lt;p&gt;I'm just waiting for Louisiana to require that all women who become pregnant be informed that nine to 16 percent of postpartum women will face &lt;a href="https://www.apa.org/pi/women/programs/depression/postpartum.aspx?item=1"&gt;postpartum depression&lt;/a&gt;, which can "affect ability to function in everyday life and increase risk for anxiety, cognitive impairment, guilt, self blame, and fear" and "lead to a loss of pleasure or interest in life, sleep disturbance, feelings of irritability or anxiety, withdrawal from family and friends, crying, and thoughts of hurting oneself or one’s child." And that's according to the American Psychological Association, not a committee of people chosen to campaign against pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=bi2h8ArPjpw:3XTDRuEzhIA:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/bi2h8ArPjpw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Abortion</category>
<category>Louisiana</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293818</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 18:36:19 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293818/-Louisiana-may-force-doctors-to-give-women-disinformation-about-abortion</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Arkansas' Medicaid enrolled almost 70 percent of eligible residents</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/ASx8pN7ycC4/-Arkansas-Medicaid-enrolled-almost-70-percent-of-eligible-residents</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/77574/large/8565441685_7c12f1ecf9_b.jpg?1397232581" alt="Congressman Tom Cotton of Arkansas speaking at the 2013 Conservative Political Action Conference (CPAC) in National Harbor, Maryland." width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;What? Still no plan, Rep. Cotton?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
About 225,000 Arkansans are too poor to qualify for a subsidy to buy health insurance on the exchange, and too "wealthy" to qualify for the state's traditional Medicaid. But because the state expanded, using a "private option" to provide coverage, &lt;a href="http://www.arkansasmatters.com/story/d/story/most-arkansans-eligible-for-private-option-signed/58933/ojQ2LhYpNEqnEiQEg5xnow"&gt;155,567 of them now have insurance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"We now know that an overwhelming majority of Arkansans in the program would have likely gone without health insurance had the Legislature not passed the Private Option," said John Selig, director of the Arkansas Department of Human Services. "Clearly there was a real need in a lot of these families." […]
&lt;p&gt;Statewide, 61 percent of Arkansans in the program are women and 64 percent are ages 19 to 44 years old, a somewhat younger population than those getting coverage through the federal insurance marketplaces, said Arkansas Medicaid Director Andy Allison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The average age and sheer number of people in the Private Option will have a significant impact on competiveness and strength of the state’s insurance market moving forward," Allison said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
This is the program that Rep. Tom Cotton (R-AR), who is running for the Senate, &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/21/1293585/-A-portrait-of-a-Republican-Senate-candidate-in-Obamacare-nbsp-denial"&gt;doesn't have a position on&lt;/a&gt;. But he does know that he wants to repeal Obamacare, which someone should really tell him also means repealing Arkansas's private option Medicaid. And taking any hope of insurance coverage away from 155,567 Arkansans (and growing—there's no deadline for applying for the program).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=ASx8pN7ycC4:b6sxZDPIwCQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/ASx8pN7ycC4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Arkansas</category>
<category>Medicaid</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293869</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 21:16:30 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293869/-Arkansas-Medicaid-enrolled-almost-70-percent-of-eligible-residents</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Crowd goes wild after Jeb Bush announces he's 'thinking about' 2016</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/dWpTYmx8Ql8/-Crowd-goes-wild-after-Jeb-Bush-announces-he-s-thinking-about-2016</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/36632/large/RTX10NKK.jpg?1371236777" alt="Former Florida Governor Jeb Bush speaks during the Faith and Freedom Coalition Road to Majority Conference at the J.W. Marriott Hotel in Washington, June 14, 2013. REUTERS/Mary F. Calvert (UNITED STATES - Tags: POLITICS RELIGION) - RTX10NKK" width="550" height="366" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2014/04/jeb-bush-2016-election-105948.html"&gt;tells&lt;/a&gt; a New York crowd that he's "thinking about running for president" in 2016 and then:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;After his answer, the room went wild, and then someone said they hoped he would take the step.
&lt;p&gt;“Would you call and tell my mom?” Bush quipped, a reference to his mother Barbara Bush’s comments that there have been enough Bushes in the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I will say this about Jeb Bush: There's no question that he's got the ability to bring Democrats and Republicans together ... because they'd both love to see him at the top of the GOP ticket in 2016. And as long as the GOP is thinking about doing us favors, can I make a small request? Tap Ted Cruz for vice president. That'd be the perfect cherry on top.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=dWpTYmx8Ql8:ErEFvYYTDkw:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/dWpTYmx8Ql8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>2016</category>
<category>Jeb Bush</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294091</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:23 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294091/-Crowd-goes-wild-after-Jeb-Bush-announces-he-s-thinking-about-2016</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Kochs reverse course, start attacking Obamacare from the left</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/5OWXImmO0cI/-Kochs-reverse-course-start-attacking-Obamacare-from-the-left</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://img.youtube.com/vi/4jDvSNYPWmE/0.jpg' style='display:none;' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='dkimg-c'&gt;&lt;iframe width='550' height='309' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/4jDvSNYPWmE?rel=0' frameborder='0' defang_allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div class='dkimg-cap'&gt;Koch ad attacking Gary Peters for "standing with health insurance companies."&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Steve Benen picks up on a new trend in the right's attacks on Obamacare: they're &lt;a href="http://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow-show/when-the-right-attacks-the-aca-the-left"&gt;fighting it from the &lt;i&gt;left&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;[Tuesday], for example, Freedom Partners, a political operation that enjoys financial support from Charles and David Koch, launched a new attack ad in Michigan’s U.S. Senate race, targeting Rep. Gary Peters (D). The voice-over tells viewers: "Congressman Gary Peters says he’s standing up to health insurance companies. The truth? Peters voted for Obamacare, which will give billions of taxpayer dollars to health insurance companies." […]
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, this truly ridiculous pitch isn't just popping up in Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Earlier this month &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cytbeD0DhXE"&gt;in Iowa&lt;/a&gt;, the Koch-financed Freedom Partners condemned Rep. Bruce Braley (D) for supporting a health care reform law through which "health insurance companies stand to make billions."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* The same day, the Koch-financed Freedom Partners launched an attack ad &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eb3Y-sA-PPg"&gt;in Colorado&lt;/a&gt;: "Mark Udall worked with insurance companies to pass Obamacare. Now Udall claims he’s standing up to them."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* A day later, Freedom Partners launched an attack ad &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vXUGNzZCoEQ&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;in Alaska&lt;/a&gt; with the same message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Who could imagine that the right would start attacking Democrats from the left when Democrats "compromise" on a policy conservatives have been pushing? &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2011/05/24/978834/-GOP-plans-to-attack-Democrats-from-left-on-Medicare"&gt;That&lt;/a&gt; never &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/nrcc-alex-sink-social-security-cuts-bowles-simpson"&gt;happens&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;p&gt;But what this really reflects is the fact that the Kochs have &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/17/1292768/-Kochs-pissing-away-their-money"&gt;pissed away millions&lt;/a&gt; in 2014 on ads that haven't moved the needle in polling at all. The anti-Obamacare message they've been pushing so far, with all those &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/03/03/1281761/-Playing-Whack-a-mole-Obamacare-horror-stories"&gt;debunked "horror" stories&lt;/a&gt;, has failed. So now they think they can pick up the disgruntled left with this campaign? Good luck to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=5OWXImmO0cI:qH8RYtDNjtM:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/5OWXImmO0cI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Koch Brothers</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Senate</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294095</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 18:50:51 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294095/-Kochs-reverse-course-start-attacking-Obamacare-from-the-left</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Andrew Cuomo realizes he has a problem on his left</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/AP2mB_aYcPk/-Andrew-Cuomo-realizes-he-has-a-problem-on-his-Left</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/77328/large/12757318163_a5d3cdbe5d_b.jpg?1397108515" alt="February 24, 2014- Amherst- Governor Cuomo outlines his 2014-15 Executive Budget." width="550" height="366" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Cuomo.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Asshole Democrat and New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo is apparently wigged out at the Siena poll showing &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293777/-Challenge-from-Left-could-complicate-Andrew-Cuomo-s-reelection"&gt;substantial support&lt;/a&gt; to his left for a Working Families Party candidate. The poll is certainly emboldening the WFP party to &lt;a href="https://home.crainsnewyork.com/clickshare/authenticateUserSubscription.do?CSProduct=newyorkbusiness-metered&amp;amp;CSAuthReq=1:673534645178894:AID:A0EE549BCEE90BFBF828A9002BC906F6&amp;amp;AID=/20140423/BLOGS04/140429964&amp;amp;title=Poll%20emboldens%20WFP%20vs.%20Cuomo&amp;amp;CSTargetURL=http://www.crainsnewyork.com/article/20140423/BLOGS04/140429964"&gt;think big&lt;/a&gt;, either with a general election candidate that would seek to supplant the GOP as the state's #2 party (and its preferential place on the ballot and on commissions), or even by backing a Democratic primary challenge to Cuomo.
&lt;p&gt;After spending months gleefully shitting on liberals and rival elected Democrats (pretty much everyone not named "Cuomo"), the governor is suddenly on the defensive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CapitalTonight/status/459053696186613761"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/412592449299574784/Nrj70bq1_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cuomo gave a defense of his liberal street cred today &lt;a href="http://t.co/ZHpsJGfstA"&gt;http://t.co/...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/CapitalTonight"&gt;@CapitalTonight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CapitalTonight/status/459046837207719937"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/412592449299574784/Nrj70bq1_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cuomo says that if liberals want public financing, Dream Act, WEA passed, then work to elect people who support those measures&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/CapitalTonight"&gt;@CapitalTonight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CapitalTonight/status/459044863150133249"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/412592449299574784/Nrj70bq1_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cuomo on WFP challenge: "I don't know if there's a lot of space to my left."&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/CapitalTonight"&gt;@CapitalTonight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
There is as much space to Cuomo's left as there was to Joe Lieberman's left, which is to say quite a bit. Heck, on economic matters, he's a Republican.
&lt;p&gt;But he's particularly wrong on that second tweet above. He says liberals should work to elect people who want those great liberal policies. Fair enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was Cuomo who &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2012/03/16/1074782/-Daily-Kos-Elections-Morning-Digest-The-number-one-redistricting-villain-in-the-nation-Andrew-Cuomo"&gt;signed into law&lt;/a&gt; the extreme GOP gerrymander that gave Senate Republicans an unfair advantage in a state in which they can barely garner &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York_gubernatorial_election,_2010"&gt;a third&lt;/a&gt; of the vote statewide. He even supported the GOP gerrymander after spending a year pretending to fight to reform the redistricting process. Kind of like how he pretended to clean up corruption in Albany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And still, Democrats took over the State Senate in 2012, despite that extreme gerrymander. But did Cuomo celebrate that? No, he &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2012/12/05/1167396/-Renegade-Democrats-keep-NY-state-Senate-in-GOP-hands-Cuomo-complicit"&gt;tacitly supported&lt;/a&gt; a breakaway faction of Democrats that kept effective control of the chamber in Republican hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don't even get Bill de Blasio started on the ways the governor is sabotaging his initiatives, in a city in which three-quarters of the electorate voted for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So liberals have done their part to shape New York to their liking. The only impediment left is Andrew Cuomo himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=AP2mB_aYcPk:DpNnf5HZ8n4:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/AP2mB_aYcPk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (kos)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>Andrew Cuomo</category>
<category>Elections</category>
<category>Governor</category>
<category>New York</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>WFP</category>
<category>Working Families Party</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294102</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 20:00:41 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294102/-Andrew-Cuomo-realizes-he-has-a-problem-on-his-Left</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Spotlight on Green News &amp; Views: Bundy lied, Earth Day 2014, Nate Silver and climate change</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/zCM78CF2eTc/-Spotlight-on-Green-News-Views-Bundy-lied-Earth-Day-2014-Nate-Silver-and-climate-change</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-l"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79358/small/SolarCoin_logo.png?1398189177" alt="SolarCoin logo" width="150" height="150" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Many of the dozens of environmentally related posts that appear at Daily Kos each week don't attract the attention they deserve. So, in 2006, a new weekly feature was launched to highlight those diaries. Initially called Eco-Diary Rescue, the name was change to Green Diary Rescue after a couple of years. After nearly 17,000 green diaries had been rescued, the name was changed again to &lt;em&gt;Spotlight on Green News &amp;amp; Views&lt;/em&gt;. The spotlight appears twice a week, on Wednesdays and Saturdays. &lt;strong&gt;Inclusion of a diary in the Spotlight does not necessarily indicate my agreement with or endorsement of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/78207/large/Outstanding_Green_Diary_Turbine-banner-TEXT.jpg?1397676085" alt="" width="550" height="45" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/21/1293671/-Breaking-news-on-Bundy-Ranch"&gt;Breaking news on Bundy Ranch&lt;/a&gt;—by &lt;b&gt;nachtwulf&lt;/b&gt;: "It seems that all of his claims are apparently lies. He claims that his family has been using the land since the 1870s, from which his erroneous claims derive. His family actually bought the ranch in 1948, provably, and didn't get cattle until the 1950s. And they bought the water rights to their own property but no grazing rights to the Federal land. Imagine that."
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/59769/large/GDR-GreenDot-Divider_(1).jpg?1385928606" alt="green dots" width="78" height="8" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79524/small/Ocean-Wind-Farm-Badge-wTEXT.jpg?1398261896" alt="" width="250" height="164" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293694/--Working-to-Save-the-Amazon-Its-Communities-Ecuador-Chevron-The-Yasuni-ITT-Initiative-Pt-1"&gt;"Working to Save the Amazon &amp;amp; Its Communities": Ecuador, Chevron, &amp;amp; The Yasuni-ITT Initiative, Pt. 1&lt;/a&gt;—by &lt;b&gt;Randle Aubrey&lt;/b&gt;: "Even the most stalwart of proponents of corporate benevolence are occasionally forced to concede that no major multinational corporation is above a certain level of malfeasance, especially when it comes to the petroleum industry. The global demand for oil is so high that companies will go to disturbing lengths to obtain it, committing all manner of abuses while the general public largely turns a blind eye, easily swayed by multi-million dollar PR campaigns and the promise of cheap fuel for all. Nowhere in recent years has this been more apparent than in the nation of Ecuador, and few companies have committed more atrocities in the name of oil than industry titan Chevron has within Ecuador's borders, according to Flora Lu, professor of Environmental Studies at UC Santa Cruz, Nestor Silva, a PhD Anthropology Student at Stanford University, and Pablo Fajardo, the now-famous Ecuadorian attorney who won a landmark class action lawsuit against Chevron in 2011."
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/59769/large/GDR-GreenDot-Divider_(1).jpg?1385928606" alt="green dots" width="78" height="8" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1291983/-The-Daily-Bucket-Last-Whales-of-Autumn?showAll=yes"&gt;The Daily Bucket : Last Whales of Autumn&lt;/a&gt;—by &lt;b&gt;Wood Gas&lt;/b&gt;: "These Humpbacks are the last I saw in the fall, a group of three had passed traveling south earlier the same day, that was Sept. 5, 2013. I posted a picture in a comment on the Daily Bucket soon after. These are photos of the same pair, taken from my boat earlier that day. The first humpback I saw returning was sighted April 13, 2014. Clarence Straits, Alaska. [...] Viewing whales from a boat. Treat you neighbors respectfully, don't chase them, do not approach too closely. &amp;nbsp;Sitting still with motor idling so they can track you easily and letting the whales come to you is the best and safest way to observe closely. &amp;nbsp;They can and do avoid boats, but if you see a ring of bubbles immediately in front of the boat a little reverse might be in order, quickly."
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/77910/large/Wkale-9.jpg?1397443819" alt="feeding humpback whale" width="550" height="272" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;You can find more rescued green diaries below the sustainable squiggle.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=zCM78CF2eTc:KN2SAZQmuEM:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/zCM78CF2eTc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Meteor Blades)</author>
<category>spotlight on green news &amp; views</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294009</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 22:30:18 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294009/-Spotlight-on-Green-News-Views-Bundy-lied-Earth-Day-2014-Nate-Silver-and-climate-change</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cartoon: Scott Brown's New Hampshire adventure</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/znUgjEre6tc/-Cartoon-Scott-Brown-s-New-nbsp-Hampshire-nbsp-adventure</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79360/lightbox/bm140421-KOS.png?1398189642"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79360/large/bm140421-KOS.png?1398189642" alt="" width="550" height="440" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79360/lightbox/bm140421-KOS.png?1398189642"&gt;Click to enlarge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=znUgjEre6tc:dSuh56Za_b4:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/znUgjEre6tc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (BrianMcFadden)</author>
<category>Comics</category>
<category>New Hampshire</category>
<category>Scott Brown</category>
<category>Senate</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1293811</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 21:50:14 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1293811/-Cartoon-Scott-Brown-s-New-nbsp-Hampshire-nbsp-adventure</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Here's just how low the Kochs will go</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/KsaR5IQbpAA/-Here-s-just-how-low-the-Kochs-will-go</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79601/large/enhanced-9553-1398281126-17.jpg?1398284667" alt="Screenshot from ad by AFP lifted from photo of Sen. Mark Udall and President Obama following the Aurora shootings." width="550" height="304" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
They really are despicable. That picture up there? President Obama and Sen. Mark Udall looking dismayed and upset, ostensibly about Obamacare? That's a screenshot from an ad from the Kochs' Americans for Prosperity. Here's where &lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/evanmcsan/photo-of-obama-in-gop-attack-ad-is-photoshopped-from-hospita"&gt;they took that picture from&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The image is from a July 2012 appearance Obama made with Udall, Colorado Gov. John Hickenlooper, and other state officials at a hospital treating victims of the July 20, 2012, Aurora movie theater shooting.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Yep, that's about as classless as you can get, attacking the president and the senator with a picture taken when they were visiting victims of a mass shooting in the hospital.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="update"&gt;&lt;a name="20140423135352" href="/story/2014/04/23/1294113/-Here-s-just-how-low-the-Kochs-will-go#20140423135352"&gt;&lt;b&gt;1:53 PM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Some of the families of the victims of the Aurora shooting are demanding that AFP take the ad down. Via email, here's their statement:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"The use of an image taken from the President's visit to Colorado to meet with us after our children were killed in the Aurora Theater shooting is an utter disgrace. And to insinuate the somber expressions were for anything other than their compassionate response to our heartbreak is beyond unconscionable. Americans for Prosperity is exploiting our tragedy for political gain and this ad should be pulled from the air immediately. We hope Colorado television stations will exercise sound judgment and not air this ad until AFP removes the image."
&lt;p&gt;Theresa Hoover, mother of AJ Boik&lt;br /&gt;
Sandy and Lonnie Phillips, parents of Jessica Ghawl&lt;br /&gt;
Terry and Tom Sullivan, parents of Alex Sullivan&lt;br /&gt;
Caren and Tom Teves, parents of Alex Teves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=KsaR5IQbpAA:0HPkAMBt-VE:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/KsaR5IQbpAA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Aurora</category>
<category>Barack Obama</category>
<category>CO-Sen</category>
<category>Colorado</category>
<category>Koch Brothers</category>
<category>Mark Udall</category>
<category>Senate</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294113</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 20:25:41 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294113/-Here-s-just-how-low-the-Kochs-will-go</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Hannity takes break from defending domestic terrorist to defend his defense of domestic terrorist</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/G-cXRobmiIc/-Hannity-tries-to-change-the-subject-from-his-fomenting-of-nbsp-violence</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79552/large/Screen_Shot_2014-04-23_at_11.13.15_AM.png?1398273329" alt="Screenshot of Sean Hannity attacking Jon Stewart on his Fox News show. April 22,2014" width="550" height="323" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Thin-skinned, much? Sean Hannity, chief Cliven Bundy booster and &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/16/1292484/-Even-after-BLM-stands-down-Hannity-pushes-talk-of-violent-conflict-in-cattle-grazing-fee-dispute"&gt;armed rebellion instigator&lt;/a&gt;, doesn't like it when people point out that his champion is pretty much just a crook. Like &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/22/1293714/-MUST-SEE-Jon-Stewart-rips-into-Cliven-Bundy-and-his-demented-defenders?detail=hide"&gt;Jon Stewart did&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;So the law isn’t on Bundy’s side, the court isn’t on Bundy’s side, even the Nevada state constitution, which Bundy claims to abide, isn’t on his side—who the hell is on Bundy’s side? […] Hannity!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Hannity fires back (it was probably the bit about Hannity making Glenn Beck the voice of reason that sets him off). Note that Hannity doesn't respond with any, you know, substance. Just with a pure, mean-spirited &lt;a href="http://dyn.politico.com/printstory.cfm?uuid=6BC74136-D444-402E-B55A-93B47FDA8260"&gt;personal attack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Sean Hannity went after Jon Stewart on Tuesday night, accusing him of being a "comedic hack" and a shill for the Obama administration.
&lt;p&gt;The Fox News host said Stewart is "kind of obsessed with this program" and that he and those at Comedy Central "kind of are the chief apologists for the Obama administration."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
That's not new for Hannity. He's been trying to change the subject of his untenable support for Bundy by &lt;a href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/sean-hannity-fires-back-at-sharpton-buffoon-schultz/"&gt;attacking critics&lt;/a&gt;, like MSNBC's Al Sharpton and Ed Schultz in the same personal, nasty vein. Of course, personal attacks are pretty much all he's got for a defense of his asinine efforts to foment violence. He sure doesn't have truth, justice and the American way for back-up.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=G-cXRobmiIc:ZKPvwUiysV4:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/G-cXRobmiIc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Cliven Bundy</category>
<category>Fox News</category>
<category>Jon Stewart</category>
<category>Sean Hannity</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294066</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 17:16:54 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294066/-Hannity-tries-to-change-the-subject-from-his-fomenting-of-nbsp-violence</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Justice Dept. lays out criteria for clemency release of thousands of federal drug offenders</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/_oe2kWd0eQc/-Justice-Dept-lays-out-criteria-for-clemency-release-of-thousands-of-federal-drug-offenders</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.dailykos.com/images/79584/small/James_M._Cole.png?1398278248" alt="Deputy A.G. James M. Cole" width="250" height="305" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;James M. Cole&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Deputy Attorney General James Cole &lt;a href="http://www.justice.gov/iso/opa/dag/speeches/2014/dag-speech-140423.html"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; at a press conference Wednesday the parameters of the Department of Justice's new clemency initiative for federal prisoners. Only those who have served at least 10 years of their sentences, have not engaged in violence while incarcerated, are not drug kingpins or associated with gangs or cartels will be eligible for clemency.
&lt;p&gt;Given how difficult avoiding violence can be, the criteria for clemency sharply limit how many prisoners could be released. But they could still number in the thousands, many of whom are serving exceedingly long, even life, sentences. All told, there were, as of April 17, &lt;a href="http://www.bop.gov/about/statistics/population_statistics.jsp"&gt;216,265&lt;/a&gt; prisoners held in the federal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most inmates likely to be eligible under the criteria for clemency wound up imprisoned as a consequence of drug laws, the worst being the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1986. Among other outrageous things, that law assigned a 100:1 sentencing disparity to persons holding crack vs. powder cocaine. Getting caught and convicted for possessing five grams of crack put a person away for a five-year mandatory sentence, the same penalty meted out for getting convicted for having 500 grams of powder cocaine. The disparity had a tremendous negative impact on African Americans who, statistics show, are far more likely to be targeted by law enforcement for drug crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just cocaine or other hard drugs, either. For instance, a &lt;a href="https://www.aclu.org/files/assets/061413-mj-report-rfs-rel4.pdf"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; last year by the American Civil Liberties Union found that blacks are 3.73 times more likely to be arrested for marijuana possession than whites even though the rate of use is similar for both. But the cocaine law presented the most egregious disparity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After more than a decade and a half of attempts, that law was superseded with the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010. It did away with the mandatory five-year sentence for cocaine possession and reduced the disparity between crack and powder cocaine from 100:1 to 18:1. An improvement, without a doubt, but as long as we're stuck with morally criminal, draconian drug laws there is no excuse for not making the ratio 1:1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And no excuse for not making fair sentencing retroactive. There are, after all, thousands of people serving sentences under the old law who would have long since been released had they been convicted under the 2010 law. But such a change would take another act of Congress. That for now seems out of the question. The clemency initiative, part of Attorney General Eric Holder's &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/aug/12/eric-holder-smart-crime-reform-us-prisons"&gt;Smart on Crime&lt;/a&gt; reform, will go part of the way to make sane what Congress will not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below the fold, you can read about Justice's clemency criteria and additional analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=_oe2kWd0eQc:asGTK0_2-aI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/_oe2kWd0eQc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Meteor Blades)</author>
<category>Clemency</category>
<category>Criminal Justice</category>
<category>Drugs</category>
<category>Fair Sentencing Act of 2010</category>
<category>John Cole</category>
<category>Prison</category>
<category>Racism</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Smart on Crimes</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1294062</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 18:50:35 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/04/23/1294062/-Justice-Dept-lays-out-criteria-for-clemency-release-of-thousands-of-federal-drug-offenders</feedburner:origLink></item>
</channel>
</rss>
