<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:blogChannel="http://backend.userland.com/blogChannelModule" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Daily Kos</title>
<link>http://www.dailykos.com</link>
<description>News Community Action</description>
<copyright>Copyright 2005 - Steal what you want</copyright>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 01:19:00 UTC</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 01:19:00 UTC</lastBuildDate>
<managingEditor>Daily Kos rss@dailykos.com (Daily Kos)</managingEditor>
<webMaster>Daily Kos rss@dailykos.com (Daily Kos)</webMaster>

<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/dailykos/index" /><feedburner:info uri="dailykos/index" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site, subject to copyright and fair use.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
<title>Walmart could pay workers $14.89 an hour without raising prices</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/aIBeK1fJUkA/-Walmart-could-pay-workers-14-89-an-hour-without-raising-prices</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58240/large/Walmart_wages_hurt_America.jpg?1384878733" alt="Protesters with signs saying &amp;quot;Walmart wages hurt America&amp;quot;" width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Walmart can easily afford to raise pay for its low-wage workers by $5.83 an hour, to an average wage of $14.89, a new report from progressive think tank Demos concludes. All the retail giant has to do is &lt;a href="http://www.demos.org/sites/default/files/publications/A%20Higher%20Wage%20Is%20Possible.pdf"&gt;stop its massive stock buybacks&lt;/a&gt;—which only serve to enrich a shrinking pool of shareholders, not to improve productivity—and put that money toward its workers.
&lt;p&gt;Walmart spends $7.6 billion a year buying back shares of its own stock:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;... which reduces the number of shares traded on the market so that the same level of earnings are distributed over fewer owners, making each remaining share worth more. Those owners who keep their stake in the company see the value of their holdings increase even if the company’s performance does not change.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The main owners who have kept their own stake in the company are the Walton family, who now own more than 50 percent of the company. If you're of the "companies should only care about their shareholders" school of thought that's driving the race to the bottom on wages and jobs, consider this:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Even for investors, the intended beneficiaries of a share buyback, the value of this financial maneuver is often illusory. As a prominent business analyst explained to the &lt;i&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/i&gt; last year, "the evidence overwhelmingly shows that heavy buyback companies usually create less value for shareholders over time… Many managements have become so infatuated with how buybacks increase earnings per share that these distributions are crowding out sound business investments that create more value over time."&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Paying workers more or adding worker hours would be a sound business investment for Walmart by reducing worker turnover, which is predictably very high. Or by fixing the &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/03/27/1197345/-Walmart-s-squeeze-on-worker-hours-leaves-shelves-bare-and-customers-unhappy"&gt;problems with bare shelves&lt;/a&gt; that have left many customers unhappy. Or by turning the very large Walmart workforce from people who &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/18/1256461/-Ohio-Walmart-asks-its-workers-to-donate-Thanksgiving-food-for-their-coworkers"&gt;need food donations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/06/04/1213662/-Walmart-s-low-prices-and-big-profits-have-a-high-cost"&gt;government assistance&lt;/a&gt; into people who make a living wage and can afford to shop at Walmart.
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.salon.com/2013/11/19/wal_mart_could_pay_every_us_employee_14_89_just_by_not_buying_its_own_stock/"&gt;Via&lt;/a&gt; Salon)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=aIBeK1fJUkA:D_bJ7x_tbrY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/aIBeK1fJUkA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Low Wages</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Walmart</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256723</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 16:34:00 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256723/-Walmart-could-pay-workers-14-89-an-hour-without-raising-prices</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Secret court allowed NSA wider NSA surveillance even after finding abuses</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/nLR4-U2Wz-8/-Secret-court-allowed-NSA-wider-NSA-surveillance-even-after-finding-nbsp-abuses</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/42698/large/RTR2FXFC.jpg?1375298723" alt="Committee Chairman Senator Patrick Leahy (D-VT) (R) and ranking member Sen. Jeff Sessions (R-AL) (L) preside over the second day of U.S. Supreme Court nominee Elena Kagan&amp;amp;#x27;s confirmation hearings in front of the Senate Judiciary Commitee on Capitol Hill in" width="550" height="356" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='293' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/559.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;The latest &lt;a href="http://in.reuters.com/article/2013/11/19/usa-nsa-spying-idINDEE9AI0FS20131119"&gt;document dump&lt;/a&gt; from the the Office of the Director of National Intelligence includes an order from the FISA court that allowed the NSA to collect an "expanded amount" of data from people's emails, despite the court's displeasure with the NSA's overreach and over-collection in another program.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The judge on the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court recounted a litany of problems with the first, smaller program, including the NSA collecting more categories of information than had been approved by the court and sharing data more widely within the electronic eavesdropping agency than had been authorized. [...]
&lt;p&gt;The programs let the NSA search for Americans who had electronic contact with people who were in turn linked to people hostile to the United States. At times, however, analysts queried the database with names that had not been found to be terrorists or foreign agents, the judge found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSA was allowed to share criminal evidence with law enforcement agencies, but in other cases it was supposed to obscure email addresses to protect the identities of U.S. citizens because of the Fourth Amendment's protections against unreasonable searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, Judge John Bates wrote about the first bulk collection program, "NSA analysts made it a general practice to disseminate to other agencies intelligence reports containing U.S. person information," such as their email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
This isn't the &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/08/21/1232922/-Secret-FISA-Court-ruling-NSA-illegally-collected-tens-of-thousand-of-domestic-nbsp-communications"&gt;first FISC ruling&lt;/a&gt; by Judge Bates to show a high degree of frustration and concern over violations by the NSA of the court's own rules. One intelligence reform bill, Sen. Patrick Leahy's, would help address some of the problems with the court, including enforcing more transparency on the court by declassifying all of its key findings since 2003, and also by creating a public advocate that could advise the court in certain cases.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=nLR4-U2Wz-8:VQIdXJPtodY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/nLR4-U2Wz-8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Dianne Feinstein</category>
<category>FISC</category>
<category>National Security Agency</category>
<category>Patrick Leahy</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Surveillance</category>
<category>Wiretapping</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257117</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 21:25:42 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257117/-Secret-court-allowed-NSA-wider-NSA-surveillance-even-after-finding-nbsp-abuses</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Responsible gun owners are safe because they know what they're—oops! BLAM! GunFAIL XLIV</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/5s5uQigPcVc/-Responsible-gun-owners-are-safe-because-they-know-what-they-re-oops-BLAM-GunFAIL-XLIV</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58173/large/guns_Capture_2.JPG?1384819173" alt="Six of the 66 guns discovered at airports by TSA agents over the past two weeks." width="400" height="202" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Six of the 66 guns discovered at airports by TSA agents over the past two weeks.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Another unusually active week in the categories of home invasion shootings (five) cop-involved GunFAILs (four), and hunting accidents (five). And there were three accidental discharges in retail stores this week, though one was in a gun shop, so that's either a little less of a surprise (since lots of people bring guns to gun shops) or perhaps more (since they're supposed to know what they're doing), depending on how you look at it. But I'm pretty sure gunfire at a Target store and a GNC are mostly unexpected. The second of those two incidents deserves special mention this week, since it took place in the context of an impromptu Second Amendment rights discussion. I might be assuming too much, but I'm guessing the discussion included a bit about being a law-abiding citizen and Responsible Gun Owner&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;, which makes it all the more surprising that the story ends, after the accidental discharge, with the perpetrator exclaiming that he "could not go down for this," before fleeing the store.
&lt;p&gt;Topping the charts in the hunting accident category this week was the story of the 14-year-old Vermonter out for Youth Hunting weekend, and bagged himself a neighbor's Shetland pony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the late report of the September squirrel shooting in the Mountain City, TN Dollar General store, which doesn't count because it's so old, top CopFAILs for the week include the Wood County, WI sheriff's deputy who drove off having forgotten his AR-15 on the trunk of his squad car would perhaps have been the top CopFAIL this week, and the situation at Ball State University. A report of a man with a gun prompted a lockdown and search, and drew law enforcement personnel from the University, the city of Muncie, Delaware County sheriff's deputies, the Indiana State Police, homeland security, and local SWAT units. No gun or gunman was found, but while they were on site, one of the SWAT officers accidentally discharged his assault rifle into the street. So file that one under armed responders arguably making things worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The child victims of GunFAIL this week were ages 6, 10, 13, 14, 14, 16, and one juvenile of unreported age. On the bright-ish side, I only found two reports of firearms found in schools in the past week, in &lt;a href="http://www.memphisflyer.com/NewsBlog/archives/2013/11/12/gun-found-in-a-students-backpack-at-overton-high"&gt;Memphis, TN&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.vvdailypress.com/articles/grounds-43669-gun-school.html"&gt;Barstow, CA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below the fold, this week's complete list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=5s5uQigPcVc:noXLRKrL1XY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/5s5uQigPcVc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Waldman)</author>
<category>GunFail</category>
<category>Guns</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1254692</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 03:23:40 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1254692/-Responsible-gun-owners-are-safe-because-they-know-what-they-re-oops-BLAM-GunFAIL-XLIV</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cholesterol overhaul</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/il6kPAAX6GU/-Cholesterol-overhaul</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58292/lightbox/11-17-strip-KOS.png?1384889615"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58292/large/11-17-strip-KOS.png?1384889615" alt="" width="550" height="286" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58292/lightbox/11-17-strip-KOS.png?1384889615"&gt;Click to enlarge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=il6kPAAX6GU:yPsRRt0yiaU:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/il6kPAAX6GU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (BrianMcFadden)</author>
<category>Big Pharma</category>
<category>Cholesterol</category>
<category>Comics</category>
<category>Statins</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256784</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 22:50:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256784/-Cholesterol-overhaul</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Illinois makes it 16: Quinn signs marriage equality law</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/m-U_FykoFnw/-Illinois-makes-it-16-Quinn-signs-marriage-equality-law</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58455/large/Illinois_marriage.jpg?1384987542" alt="Illinois Gov. Pat Quinn holds up the state's newly signed marriage equality law." width="550" height="293" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Illinois Gov. Pat Quinn holds up the state's newly signed marriage equality law.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
It took a couple tries in the state House and a delay of several months, but Illinois became the 16th state to put marriage equality into law.
&lt;p&gt;"It's time to stop planning rallies and start planning weddings," said Lt. Gov. Sheila Simon at the signing ceremony. Calling the law's passage "a triumph of democracy," but noting that there was "unfinished business" in other states, Gov. Pat Quinn signed the bill into law Wednesday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quinn gave the moment some &lt;a href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/news/chi-illinois-gay-marriage-bill-signing-20131120,0,4464600.story"&gt;added historic resonance&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The Democratic governor has brought up the desk from Springfield that his administration says President Abraham Lincoln used to write his first inaugural address. That speech, delivered on March 4, 1861 as the Civil War was unfolding, called on Americans to heed “the better angels of our nature.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The law won't go into effect until June 1, 2014, though other legislation could move it to an earlier date.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=m-U_FykoFnw:hUvs3pZ70MA:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/m-U_FykoFnw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Gay Marriage</category>
<category>Illinois</category>
<category>Marriage Equality</category>
<category>Pat Quinn</category>
<category>Same Sex Marriage</category>
<category>Sheila Simon</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257119</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 22:47:06 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257119/-Illinois-makes-it-16-Quinn-signs-marriage-equality-law</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>The wingnut revolution is upon us. Oops, no, you missed it.</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/A0cCQW7P6_k/-The-wingnut-revolution-is-upon-us-Oops-no-you-missed-it</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58311/large/RWWKlaymanrally.jpg?1384897548" alt="Klayman rally sign: 'WAKE UP AMERICA AND SMELL THE TYRANNY ASK QUESTIONS: FT HOOD FAST AND FURIOUS BENGHAZI GUN CONTROL ? ? ? ? ? ?'" width="493" height="436" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Oh. Oh dear. (&lt;a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/larry-klayman-rally-overthrow-obama-draws-slightly-fewer-millions-expected"&gt;Right Wing Watch&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Oh, heavens, &lt;a href="http://www.usnews.com/news/articles/2013/11/19/conservative-activists-plan-to-elect-shadow-president-if-obama-doesnt-resign-by-black-friday"&gt;whatever shall become of our fair republic&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Approximately 100 conservative activists gathered in front of the White House on Tuesday for a kickoff of what organizers call "the second American revolution."
&lt;p&gt;The event could easily have been mistaken for a tea party rally, with American and Gadsden flags, a smattering of biker jackets and a few lawn chairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom Watch founder Larry Klayman, who emceed the event, told attendees if President Barack Obama does not resign by Nov. 29, conservative activists will meet in Philadelphia to elect a shadow government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Two people per state? That's not a revolution, that's a Senate. If this shadow government is going to contain a full House as well, they're going to have to start appointing pets and toasters.
&lt;p&gt;You have probably heard of Larry Klayman before. If not, no worries—but I should clarify that this is the loudmouthed neorevolutionary wingnut that has &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; been arrested for possession of hallucinogenic mushrooms, not &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adam_Kokesh"&gt;the one who has&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, it can get confusing. While the other revolutionary is all about being able to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/07/15/adam-kokesh-bond_n_3599079.html"&gt;carry guns wherever you want&lt;/a&gt; because you never know when the mushrooms will kick in, this one is still on the whole &lt;a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/larry-klaymans-five-reasons-overthrow-obama"&gt;Obama is possibly a Kenyan&lt;/a&gt; kick, plus also "Benghazi-gate" and the shutting down of our precious war memorials, etc., and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, so Mr. Klayman has said that if President Obama does not resign by the sacred date of Black Friday, he and other likeminded crackpots will immediately meet, perhaps on what shall henceforth be known as &lt;em&gt;Honky Saturday&lt;/em&gt;, to elect their own shadow government. One that is not from Kenya, and is not a secret Musslim and so forth:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Bishop Dan Johnson of the Heart of Fire Church in Louisville, Ky., prayed with ralliers, asking God to "cause [elected officials] to get on their knees, not to Allah, but to God almighty." In his prayer, Johnson denounced homosexuality, permissive parenting, pornography and welfare.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
In addition to a bewigged George Washington impersonator and the editor of conspiracy website World Net Daily Joseph Farah because, well, &lt;em&gt;duh&lt;/em&gt;, there was also a former congressman on hand to lend the proceedings another few shovelfuls of skin-crawling creepiness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"We have a scoundrel living in that building," [Former Rep. Bob Barr] said, pointing at the White House, "and need to do something about it."&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Ew, I thought that fellow had died. I suppose he might have, and his speech could have just been gas escaping—please get on that hypothesis, Mr. Farah, America demands an answer.
&lt;p&gt;So there you go: the revolution is upon us, at least once they decide between Denny's and Olive Garden for the ceremonies. Never have so few given so little to scream so loudly—true patriots, all. Someday each one of them will be commemorated on trading cards, a little paperboard sea of revolutionary flags and trucker hats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God speed, heroes, and remember to leave the 'shrooms at home.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=A0cCQW7P6_k:goydRHDbaRQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/A0cCQW7P6_k" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Hunter)</author>
<category>Conservative Conspiracy Theories</category>
<category>Conservatives</category>
<category>Larry Klayman</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Tea Party</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256828</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 21:51:28 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256828/-The-wingnut-revolution-is-upon-us-Oops-no-you-missed-it</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Another not-really-a-scandal Obamacare scandal</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/8I0-CEUoFlw/-Another-not-really-a-scandal-Obamacare-nbsp-scandal</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/27634/large/RTR23P6Q.jpg?1365695793" alt="US Senator Charles Grassley (R-IA) questions New York Federal Reserve Bank President Timothy Geithner, US President Barack Obama&amp;amp;#x27;s nominee for Treasury Secretary, during his confirmation hearing before the Senate Finance Committee on Capitol Hill in Washi" width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;This one&amp;#x27;s on him.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Useful idiot for the right, Ron Fournier, is back at it, clutching his pearls over yet another potential Obamacare "scandal."&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ron_fournier/status/403202429488865280"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/378800000193976270/54f09419d286b2302e5c5c53db23525f_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;WTF -- How do Dem Congressional leaders and the White House let this happen? Will be used against #ACA: &lt;a href="http://t.co/DzCBGAl68t"&gt;http://t.co/...&lt;/a&gt; #leadership&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ron_fournier"&gt;@ron_fournier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
"This" is &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/20/us/politics/for-lawmakers-a-gold-plated-insurance-exchange.html?pagewanted=print"&gt;this story&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt; that reminds us all that members of Congress are now buying their insurance, as are their staff members, from the D.C. health insurance exchange. That's because Republican senators Tom Coburn and Chuck Grassley thought it'd be a cute idea that would hurt the legislation as Democrats were trying to push it through. It didn't work, though, because Democrats enthusiastically embraced the whole idea.
&lt;p&gt;And now the &lt;i&gt;NYT&lt;/i&gt;, and Fournier, are agog that members and staff &amp;nbsp;"have access to 'in-person support sessions' like the ones being conducted at the Capitol and congressional office buildings," and that "the fact that lawmakers have a larger menu of “gold plan” insurance choices than most of their constituents have back home."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, in states where members of Congress and Republican officials haven't been able to shut that whole thing down, regular people &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; have access to one-on-one support sessions. They're called navigators; people hired specifically to do just that—help walk people through their options. Second, there are so many great plans on the D.C. exchange because there were a ton of great plans on its predecessor, the Federal Employees Health Benefits program, and they mostly just migrated to the exchange where they could continue to provide their great coverage, just like Coburn and Grassley wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Fournier really wants a congressional health care scandal to concern troll over, maybe he ought to do some research on the Office of the Attending Physician. If he &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; does want a gold-plated scandal, how about the fact that &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonmonthly.com/archives/individual/2009_09/020186.php"&gt;members of Congress can get every health concern addressed&lt;/a&gt; at a moment's notice for a measly $503 a year (as of 2009, but the fee hasn't changed significantly in years).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=8I0-CEUoFlw:mk6t2ARxQsY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/8I0-CEUoFlw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Congress</category>
<category>Health Insurance</category>
<category>Health Insurance Reform</category>
<category>Office of Attending Physician</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257071</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 18:35:32 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257071/-Another-not-really-a-scandal-Obamacare-nbsp-scandal</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Senate Democrats see choice between Obamacare and 'Cruz Care' (aka repeal)</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/-7Rq1r6ipC4/-Senate-Democrats-see-choice-between-Obamacare-and-Cruz-Care-aka-repeal</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/51233/large/RTR3FGJO.jpg?1380644734" alt="U.S. Senator Ted Cruz (R-TX) (C) departs the Senate floor after a late-night vote rejected budget legislation from the Republican-controlled House of Representatives at the U.S. Capitol in Washington, September 30, 2013. The U.S. government was on the edg" width="550" height="344" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;"Going down, please."&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Greg Sargent &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/plum-line/wp/2013/11/20/dems-try-going-on-offense-its-obamacare-versus-cruz-care/"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that the Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee is launching a campaign going after Republicans for offering nothing on health care reform except for repeatedly proposing to repeal Obamacare, a position it will call "Cruz Care":&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The “Cruz Care” campaign is grounded in a conviction that Republicans — and not a few D.C. pundits — are misreading public opinion on Obamacare. Dems believe that despite the law’s unpopularity, many voters don’t view the health care issue as a zero sum decision over whether Obamacare is good or bad. Rather, they can be persuaded to see this as choice — between fixing an admittedly imperfect reform and giving it a chance to work, and the GOP alternative, which is essentially to go back to the old system, where junk insurance and a lack of standards ”exposed people to financial and medical calamity.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
This goes back to the question of whether elections are referendums or choices: 2012 was clearly a choice election, but 2010 was a referendum election. Then as now, polls showed that most voters want to keep and strengthen Obamacare instead of repealing it, but 2014 differs from 2010 in one key respect: Obamacare won't be just a piece of paper, it will be real program delivering tangible benefits to millions of Americans.
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, if the administration's implementation of the law doesn't improve, the political equation won't be pretty for Democrats, but assuming that it does, it's equally obvious that Republicans will be in trouble, because their only response to Obamacare is to repeal it. Republicans are clearly rooting for it to fail, but most Americans want Obamacare to work—a &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257030/-CBS-poll-Good-news-for-Mitt-Romney-bad-news-for-Ted-Cruz"&gt;new CBS poll today&lt;/a&gt; showed that even as public frustration with the law's implementation is at it's peak, most people don't want to repeal it, they want to keep it in place and make it work better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine the lack of enthusiasm for repeal with the fact that things are &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256749/-Obamacare-enrollments-surging-HealthCare-gov-working-better"&gt;already starting to get better&lt;/a&gt;, there's reason to be optimistic not just that the political climate will improve for Democrats by next November, but more importantly, that the promise of Obamacare—affordable, quality health care insurance for all Americans—can still become a reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=-7Rq1r6ipC4:_5YaashzIZY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/-7Rq1r6ipC4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>DSCC</category>
<category>Ted Cruz</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257084</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 21:30:12 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257084/-Senate-Democrats-see-choice-between-Obamacare-and-Cruz-Care-aka-repeal</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Eighth senator signs on to Landrieu's 'keep your plan' bill</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/1amEMWZc3kw/-Eighth-senator-signs-on-to-Landrieu-s-keep-your-plan-bill</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58431/large/Tom_Udall.png?1384978336" alt="" width="550" height="395" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='353' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/569.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sen. Mary Landrieu's &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/13/1254861/-A-tale-of-two-keep-your-health-insurance-nbsp-bills"&gt;"keep your health plan"&lt;/a&gt; bill has one more cosponsor: Sen. Tom Udall (D-NM). Udall didn't release a statement explaining why he was joining the effort, &lt;a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/floor-action/healthcare/190863-udall-becomes-eighth-senate-dem-to-back-o-care-fix"&gt;but signed on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Udall joined the bill without issuing a formal statement, but Senate Democrats are becoming increasingly vocal about the need to change the law. When Sen. Mary Landrieu (D-La.) introduced the bill earlier this month, she said Democrats need to pass legislation to make good on their promise that Americans could keep their health insurance if they like it.
&lt;p&gt;"We said to people that if they have insurance they like, they can keep it," Landrieu said. "We didn't say that if they have insurance they like that doesn't meet the standards or that meets the minimum standards, they can keep it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
There are now eight co-sponsors for Landrieu's effort. Those who are up for re-election in 2014 are Kay Hagan (D-NC), Jeff Merkley (D-OR), Mark Pryor (D-AK.) and Udall. The others are Sens. Joe Manchin (D-WV), Dianne Feinstein (D-CA) and Joe Donnelly (D-IN). Senate leadership, so far, has taken the position that the administration's &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/14/1255572/-What-the-Obamacare-fix-does-and-how-it-could-be-nbsp-better"&gt;executive level fix&lt;/a&gt; to the problem of cancelled insurance policies is adequate, and hasn't announced any plans to bring the legislation to a vote.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=1amEMWZc3kw:4i2FlZ_otBs:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/1amEMWZc3kw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Health Insurance</category>
<category>Health Insurance Reform</category>
<category>Mary Landrieu</category>
<category>Tom Udall</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257098</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 20:15:10 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257098/-Eighth-senator-signs-on-to-Landrieu-s-keep-your-plan-bill</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>2016 watch: Rand Paul says Chris Christie is 'embracing Obamacare'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/IEuaXF4dFVg/-2016-watch-Rand-Paul-says-Chris-Christie-is-embracing-Obamacare</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;object id="flashObj" width="486" height="325" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1" /&gt;
&lt;param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /&gt;
&lt;param name="flashVars" value="videoId=2852832505001&amp;amp;playerID=1409164951001&amp;amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAETmrZQ~,EVFEM4AKJdRjek0MS21pRzf_GTDAM-xj&amp;amp;domain=embed&amp;amp;dynamicStreaming=true" /&gt;
&lt;param name="base" value="http://admin.brightcove.com" /&gt;
&lt;param name="seamlesstabbing" value="false" /&gt;
&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /&gt;
&lt;param name="swLiveConnect" value="true" /&gt;
&lt;param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /&gt;
&lt;embed src="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" flashvars="videoId=2852832505001&amp;amp;playerID=1409164951001&amp;amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAETmrZQ~,EVFEM4AKJdRjek0MS21pRzf_GTDAM-xj&amp;amp;domain=embed&amp;amp;dynamicStreaming=true" defang_base="http://admin.brightcove.com" name="flashObj" width="486" height="325" defang_seamlesstabbing="false" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" defang_swliveconnect="true" allowscriptaccess="always" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Sen. Rand Paul (R-KY) &lt;a href="http://transcripts.cnn.com/TRANSCRIPTS/1311/19/ebo.01.html"&gt;takes a question&lt;/a&gt; on CNN about two of his potential rivals for the 2016 Republican presidential nomination:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;ERIN BURNETT, CNN: Jeb Bush is in favor of comprehensive immigration reform. New Jersey Governor Chris Christie has said people should be able to marry whoever they want to marry.* Do those two gentlemen fit your definition of a conservative?
&lt;p&gt;SEN. RAND PAUL: You know, I don't think any one person gets on decide what is or is not conservative. On the case of the New Jersey governor, I think embracing Obamacare, expanding Medicaid in his state is very expensive and not fiscally conservative. Many Republican governors did resist expanding and accepting Obamacare in their states. I would say that fact, I would say, would lead you toward making the conclusion that it is not a very conservative proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
It's not a surprise that Paul's line of attack on Christie involves linking Christie to Obamacare, but it's also interesting that he completely ignores Jeb Bush. Obviously, Paul isn't too worried about Bush, either because he doesn't think Bush is going to run, or because he doesn't see Bush as a compelling candidate.
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, Paul is clearly focused on confronting Christie and doesn't seem to like him at all. We've still got about two years to go, but when they finally get on stage together and debate each other, it's going to be spectacular—not just because it will be fun to see the sparks fly between these two, but also because it will be enjoyable to watch a Republican debate in which Chris Christie defends one of the central elements of Obamacare, Medicaid expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*This actually isn't quite true: Christie &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/christie-on-gay-marriages-in-nj-i-m-happy-if-they-re-happy"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; he was happy for newly married same-sex couples if they were happy, but didn't change his opposition to same-sex marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=IEuaXF4dFVg:BlYWLhZCko8:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/IEuaXF4dFVg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>2016</category>
<category>Chris Christie</category>
<category>Rand Paul</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257051</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 20:30:12 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257051/-2016-watch-Rand-Paul-says-Chris-Christie-is-embracing-Obamacare</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Midday open thread: Pastor faces defrocking over marriage ceremony, Murdoch gets unhitched</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/nERK_8w1qPs/-Midday-open-thread-Pastor-faces-defrocking-over-marriage-ceremony-Murdoch-gets-unhitched</link>
<description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today's &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/blog/comics"&gt;comic&lt;/a&gt; by Matt Bors is &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256741/-Healthcare-dot-gov-fixing?showAll=yes"&gt;Healthcare dot gov fixing&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256741/-Healthcare-dot-gov-fixing?detail=hide"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58389/large/teaser_(67).png?1384951032" alt="Cartoon by Matt Bors - Healthcare dot gov fixing" width="500" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/11/albuquerque-abortion-ban-vote-100109.html"&gt;Albuquerque says no to ban of abortions after 20 weeks&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;The measure’s defeat Tuesday, by a vote of 55 percent to 45 percent, effectively keeps mid-to-late-term abortions available in New Mexico. Had the proposal passed, it would have halted abortions after 20 weeks at the state’s only two clinics providing them. Both are located in Albuquerque.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/11/19/rock-and-roll-heaven-photos_n_4305256.html"&gt;What music legends would look like today if they had lived&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/lgbt/2013/11/20/2972311/verdict-methodist-pastor-30-days-renounce-gay-children-defrocked/"&gt;Renounce kids or be defrocked, Methodist minister told&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;On Monday, the United Methodist Church convicted Rev. Frank Schaefer on two counts against the Church for officiating his son’s same-sex wedding. On Tuesday, the impaneled jury determined his sentence: Schaefer is suspended for 30 days, and if it at the end of that time he has not renounced his support for marriage equality, he will be defrocked.
&lt;p&gt;Schaefer, however, was unapologetic, refusing the invitation to “repent of your actions”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nbcwashington.com/news/local/Joe-Biden-Birthday-5-Memorable-Biden-Moments-232666371.html"&gt;On his 71st birthday, NBC offers five unforgettable moments in the political life of Joe Biden, &amp;nbsp;America's "most entertaining" VP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://americablog.com/2013/11/air-force-academy-doubles-defense-ex-gay-character-coach.html"&gt;Air Force defends hiring of "ex-gay" character coach&lt;/a&gt;. The Air Force hired Dr. Mike Rosebush, who boasts of two decades of experience “curing homosexuals,” to oversee the “Character and Leadership” coaching program at the academy. But they told John Aravosis that Rosebush will only be coaching cadets not counseling them:
&lt;blockquote&gt;Unfortunately, that explanation falls short of addressing the underlying problem. A man who has devoted the last twenty years of his life to “curing” gay people is now in charge of a mandatory program, that he designed, to help Air Force Academy cadets develop “character” and “leadership.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wonkette.com/534653/hey-ladies-scary-old-rupert-murdoch-is-about-to-be-single-again"&gt;Good news, single ladies: Rupert Murdoch's latest billion-dollar-plus divorce is being finalized&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rush Limbaugh trashes President Obama and Oprah Winfrey as liars. Also on today's &lt;a href="http://thisweekinblackness.com/projects/twibradio/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#TWiBRadio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: the tenets of &lt;a href="http://t.co/CaKYnAa1Nm"&gt;abstinence-only sexual education (24:20), George Zimmerman&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://t.co/zPIdOEsE2V"&gt;got arrested&lt;/a&gt;, again (44:03), &lt;a href="http://t.co/80gghv4FwO"&gt;the Bitcoin Assassination Fund&lt;/a&gt; (47:01), and &lt;a href="http://t.co/Q9vpuvACun"&gt;"selfie"&lt;/a&gt; won the Oxford Dictionary Word of the Year (54:19).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: none;" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2558644/height/45/width/500/theme/standard/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="45" width="100%" defang_allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/twib.fm-this-week-in-blackness/id302330739"&gt;Subscribe on iTunes&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://stitcher.com/s?eid=20773671&amp;amp;refid=stpr"&gt;Subscribe On Stitcher&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/twibiu/TWR_484.mp3"&gt;Direct Download&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://twibiu.libsyn.com/rss"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/didnt-read-the-most-important-climate-report-in-6-years-this-video-has-you-covered"&gt;The unofficial video version of the latest IPCC global warming report is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2559800/height/200/width/250/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="200" width="250" scrolling="no" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
On &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257094/-Daily-Kos-Radio-s-KITM-podcast"&gt;today's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show&lt;/a&gt;, lots of filibuster reform discussion today, right through our discussions with &lt;strong&gt;Greg Dworkin&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Joan McCarter&lt;/strong&gt;. Greg rounded up the day's ACA news, punditry &amp;amp; polling, and told us about the "forbidden words" in ACA reporting: wait and see. Joan covered the state of play on filibuster reform, what we were likely to see &amp;amp; when. And yes, we hedged a little bit when it came to the bottom line question of whether or not it would really happen. Then, an check-in on comments from &lt;strong&gt;jimstaro&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;enemy of the people&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/strong&gt;. Lastly, David Dayen's "JPMorgan's bait-and-switch: The ballyhooed settlement is just a scam!"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=nERK_8w1qPs:MSglDc8maVc:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/nERK_8w1qPs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Meteor Blades)</author>
<category>Midday Open Thread</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257017</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 20:00:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257017/-Midday-open-thread-Pastor-faces-defrocking-over-marriage-ceremony-Murdoch-gets-unhitched</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Oprah talks about race; Fox News freaks out</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/99JZaixKgmA/-Oprah-talks-about-race-Fox-News-freaks-nbsp-out</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58414/large/RTX15LYD.jpg?1384971529" alt="U.S. President Barack Obama presents the Presidential Medal of Freedom to entertainer Oprah Winfrey at a ceremony in the East Room of the White House in Washington, November 20, 2013. REUTERS/Jason Reed (UNITED STATES - Tags: POLITICS ENTERTAINMENT) - RTX15LYD" width="550" height="434" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Last week Oprah Winfrey &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/11/15/oprah-racists-die_n_4280460.html?utm_hp_ref=media"&gt;made the very naughty observation&lt;/a&gt; that racism still exists in America and that—gasp—president Obama probably faces some of it. Worse, she made the equally naughty and equally true observation that racism will likely only get better when older generations of racists die. Since black people are not allowed to talk about racism, this has resulted in a network-wide &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/11/19/fox-news-oprah_n_4304632.html"&gt;Fox News freakout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Bill O'Reilly &lt;a href="http://video.foxnews.com/v/2849428274001/oprah-winfrey-defending-president-obama-with-the-race-card/"&gt;talked about it&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Mark Levin &lt;a href="http://nation.foxnews.com/2013/11/19/mark-levin-explodes-oprah-winfrey-has-no-idea-what-it%E2%80%99s-live-country-brutally-racist"&gt;freaked out about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Five" went on &lt;a href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/the-five-hits-oprahs-race-remarks-way-more-wackos-on-the-left-than-the-right/"&gt;multiple rants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our favorite thing, though, is this "Hannity" commercial, which basically makes Oprah seem like the second coming of Freddy Krueger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Hannity, for his part, seems to be under the impression that Oprah threatened to personally knock off elderly racists one by one, which for a movement still convinced that Obama is secretly raising an army of black people is probably not much more of a stretch.
&lt;p&gt;This is just a thought, but it seems to me that people who were not racist are just not as prone to getting worked up about people talking about racism as racists are. Conversely, breaking out in network hives whenever someone brings the subject up is probably not the best way to show you understand the topic. The network push against Oprah might also have something to do with the White House awarding her the &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/click/2013/11/obama-honors-oprah-at-the-white-house-177969.html"&gt;Medal of Freedom&lt;/a&gt; for her achievements; it seems many in the network &lt;a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/music/news/fox-news-attacks-rapper-common-over-white-house-invite-20110510"&gt;get very worked up&lt;/a&gt; when &lt;a href="http://news.yahoo.com/blogs/cutline/fox-news-website-calls-obama-birthday-party-hip-214154301.html"&gt;black Americans&lt;/a&gt; visit the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just sayin', Fox News. Just sayin'.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=99JZaixKgmA:WDG-H7twt-Y:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/99JZaixKgmA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Hunter)</author>
<category>Barack Obama</category>
<category>Conservatives</category>
<category>Fox News</category>
<category>Oprah Winfrey</category>
<category>Racism</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257065</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 18:22:31 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257065/-Oprah-talks-about-race-Fox-News-freaks-nbsp-out</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Senate debate on military sexual assault begins; Gillibrand amendment picks up 52nd supporter</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/Wrj0HyzHQpM/-Senate-debate-on-military-sexual-assault-begins-Gillibrand-amendment-picks-up-51st-supporter</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/1946/large/chris_murphy_official_photo_govtrends_version.jpeg?1343158425" alt="Chris Murphy, connecticut congressman running for Senate in 2012" defang_width="" defang_height="" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Sen. Chris Murphy (D-CT), the 51st supporter of the Military Justice Improvement Act.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Debate about how to handle military sexual assault started on the Senate floor Wednesday morning, with Sen. Kirsten Gillibrand seeking 60 votes for her Military Justice Improvement Act. Connecticut Sen. Chris Murphy became the amendment's 51st public supporter in a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/notes/christopher-murphy/a-note-about-the-upcoming-senate-vote-to-address-sexual-assault-in-the-military/10151937717218961"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; concluding "Given the long history of sexual assault in the military, it is time for us to take a leap of faith and move forward with a new approach to solving this vexing and chronic problem." He was soon followed by Ohio Sen. Sherrod Brown &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SenGillibrand/status/403224937751523328"&gt;making it 52&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/floor-action/senate/190918-gillibrand-military-has-zero-accountability-for-assaults"&gt;Making the case&lt;/a&gt; for having decisions about prosecuting major crimes like sexual assault be made by military prosecutors, not military commanders:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Victims feel they will not get justice,” Gillibrand said on the Senate floor. “If you don’t create a transparent, accountable system outside of the chain of command your hope of victims reporting … it’s not there, the hope is not there.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Another amendment, from Democratic Sen. Claire McCaskill and Republican Sen. Kelly Ayotte, would seek to address sexual assault in the military while leaving prosecution decisions with commanders, tweaking a failed system around the edges rather than seeking major change. Gillibrand's amendment could get a vote as early as Wednesday evening, but could also be held up.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.endsexualassault.com/?code=dailykos"&gt;Tell Congress to protect victims of military sexual assault by supporting the Military Justice Improvement Act.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=Wrj0HyzHQpM:oKw5ubqwbbU:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/Wrj0HyzHQpM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Chris Murphy</category>
<category>Kirsten Gillibrand</category>
<category>Military</category>
<category>Military Justice Improvement Act</category>
<category>Military Sexual Assault</category>
<category>Sexual Assault</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257064</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 18:20:12 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257064/-Senate-debate-on-military-sexual-assault-begins-Gillibrand-amendment-picks-up-51st-supporter</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Sen. Jeff Merkley: GOP obstruction of judges is a 'pure assault'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/-0JSyu7a3wQ/-Sen-Jeff-Merkley-GOP-obstruction-of-judges-is-a-pure-assault</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/22396/large/Senator_Jeff_Merkley_D-Oregon.jpg?1362780113" alt="Sen. Jeff Merkley, D-Ore." width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='353' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/556.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Daily Kos spoke with Sen. Jeff Merkley (D-OR), a leader in the push for rules reform in the Senate, Wednesday morning to get his reaction to the news Tuesday evening that Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/20/us/politics/senate-democrats-consider-move-to-curb-filibusters.html?ref=politics&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;pagewanted=print"&gt;could move as soon as this week&lt;/a&gt; on rules reform for judicial nominees
&lt;p&gt;Merkley said that in the discussions the Democratic caucus has been holding, including one Tuesday afternoon which preceded the news from Reid's office, that "frustration is enormous" among Democrats over the filibuster of all three of President Obama's nominees. "This is a whole new strategy on the part of the minority to block these nominees," Merkley said. "It's not about qualifications, but about denying this president his nominees." The consensus in the caucus, he said, is that "the argument put forward by Republicans [that the court is underworked and doesn't need these additional nominees] has zero grounds of legitimacy. If that really was the reason for blocking these nominees, they would have opposed President Bush's nominees to the D.C. Circuit.... This is a pure assault on President Obama's constitutional right and responsibility to appoint justices."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than one senator, Merkley said, who had previously been opposed to rules reform spoke in Tuesday's meeting, telling the caucus they had changed their minds and why. While Merkley didn't want to divulge what happened in the private meeting, public reports from the meeting include Sens. Dianne Feinstein and Barbara Boxer. Merkley talked about the significance of Sen. Patrick Leahy reaching the conclusion that there was not alternative to going nuclear at this point. Leahy has long opposed this reform for judicial nominees on the grounds that he believed previous Republican concessions meant that a return to the norms and traditions of the Senate was possible. No longer, and Leahy's change of heart, Merkley said, was critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merkley deferred to leadership on the possible timing of the vote that will lead to the reform effort, as well as to the scope of this bill. Senate aides have told both &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/20/us/politics/senate-democrats-consider-move-to-curb-filibusters.html?ref=politics&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;pagewanted=print"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/plum-line/wp/2013/11/19/harry-reid-is-set-to-go-nuclear/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it could happen as soon as this week, after the Senate votes on the assault in the military amendment to the Defense Authorisation. These reports also say that Supreme Court justices would be excepted from the new rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked about whether Rep. Mel Watt's nomination to the Federal Housing and Finance Administration would be brought back up, Merkley said that was talked about in the conference and that the revote could lead to reform on executive nominations. He said that Republicans breaking the deal on executive nominees that was reached last July was a huge factor for Democrats coalescing behind the idea of rules reform, and the idea of revisiting the Merkley/Udall proposal for ending the filibuster on legislation at the beginning of the next congress in January, 2015. But he couldn't say how many votes there are in the Senate now, for breaking the filibuster on judicial nominees. That's a closely held secret, but from the outside, it seems unlikely Reid would be going public with this if he didn't feel he had the votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Merkley thanked the Daily Kos community for its long-standing support and agitation for rules reform. He said that his colleagues are both well aware of and astounded by the level of understanding and frustration their constituents have in the issue. He's assured that Senate Democrats understand that another concession by Democrats to Republicans, another "deal" in which Republicans promise they'll play nice next time just won't fly with the grassroots any more. That message has reached Democrats' ears. Now they just have to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=-0JSyu7a3wQ:3lvpdtTmHZk:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/-0JSyu7a3wQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Filibuster</category>
<category>Harry Reid</category>
<category>Jeff Merkley</category>
<category>U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257055</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 17:47:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257055/-Sen-Jeff-Merkley-GOP-obstruction-of-judges-is-a-pure-assault</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Republicans struggle to explain why they haven't acted on immigration reform</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/63vbkh-0Tqw/-Republicans-struggle-to-explain-why-they-haven-t-acted-on-immigration-reform</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/4964/large/eric-cantor-speaking.jpg?1346769633" alt="House Majority Leader Eric Cantor speaks at Northwestern University's Kellogg School of Management in Evanston, Illinois, October 28, 2011. REUTERS/John Gress (UNITED STATES - Tags: POLITICS)" defang_width="" defang_height="" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;'Also, there's a spider in my office. Huge thing, this big. We can't go in there anymore.'&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Having decided to do nothing on immigration reform this year, House Republicans are now in the position of having to explain that position in a manner that might sound plausible to people. Or at least plausible to their base, which you have to admit is a much easier proposition—those people will buy anything.
&lt;p&gt;And so we get things like Majority Leader Eric Cantor explaining that the big problem is, um, Obamacare. &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/11/19/immigration-reform_n_4298109.html"&gt;Via HuffPo&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"The news of this week, unfortunately, has been many, many Americans very unhappy with the work product coming out of this town as far as health care is concerned," Cantor said. "I would posit to the gentleman that a bill like Obamacare or a bill like the Senate immigration bill produces the kinds of impact and effect that we're seeing this week and last week and the prior. We don't want to commit that same mistake."&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Wait, did we say Obamacare? We meant because Obama, period. He's outta control, we tells ya:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Republicans are skeptical of Obama's commitment to enforcing immigration law and protecting the border -- despite record deportation numbers and high border patrol spending -- and argue they can't be sure he'd actually follow the law.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Rep. Tom Cole may be on to something with his theory that immigration reform can't happen primarily because his caucus is made up of incompetent bumblefucks:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;[Cole] said it was unrealistic to expect the House to be able to tackle what he called the "divisive and difficult issue" of immigration when it can barely handle the most basic task of keeping the government's lights on.
&lt;p&gt;"We're not sure we can chew gum, let alone walk and chew gum, so let’s just chew gum for a while," Cole said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Ooh, that's a good one. I'm gonna go with that one. I would also accept "frothing Republican base would not put up with doing humane things on behalf of any immigrants, ever"; see the collective oeuvre of Rep. Steve King for that one.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://campaigns.dailykos.com/p/dia/action3/common/public/?action_KEY=515"&gt;Sign our petition urging your House member to sign a "discharge petition" to bring comprehensive immigration reform to a floor vote.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=63vbkh-0Tqw:u8v8s9EltoI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/63vbkh-0Tqw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Hunter)</author>
<category>Congress</category>
<category>Conservatives</category>
<category>Immigration Reform</category>
<category>Republicans</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256781</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 19:25:46 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256781/-Republicans-struggle-to-explain-why-they-haven-t-acted-on-immigration-reform</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>CBS poll: Good news for Mitt Romney, bad news for Ted Cruz</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/mW9UaBnI94A/-CBS-poll-Good-news-for-Mitt-Romney-bad-news-for-Ted-Cruz</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58399/large/tedcruzmittromney_reuters.jpg?1384965536" alt="Side-by-side of Sen. Ted Cruz (R-TX) and fmr. Gov. Mitt Romney (R-MA)" width="550" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
First, &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-250_162-57613067/poll-obamacare-support-obama-approval-sink-to-new-lows/"&gt;the good news for Mitt Romney&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;President Obama's job approval rating has plunged to the lowest of his presidency, according to a new CBS News poll released Wednesday, and Americans' approval of the Affordable Care Act has dropped it's lowest since CBS News started polling on the law.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Ouch—but not exactly surprising, given that even President Obama admits that the Obamacare rollout hasn't gone smoothly. I'm sure he'd love for those numbers to be higher, but the reality is that until things are turned around, these sorts of approval numbers aren't going to look good—nor should they. That's why the most important thing the administration can do is to make the policy work.
&lt;p&gt;And that brings me to the second key finding in the poll, which has some bad news for Ted Cruz:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Just seven percent of Americans think the Affordable Care Act is working well and should be kept in place as it is. Far more, 48 percent, think there are some good things in the law, but changes are needed to make it work better, and another 43 percent think the law needs to be repealed entirely.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
So even though Obamacare now is pretty much at its lowest point ever, a clear majority opposes the Ted Cruz position, which is repealing it altogether. Moreover, support for repeal isn't exactly skyrocketing, despite all the problems of the past six weeks: that 43 percent figure is just 4 points higher than the 39 percent who supported repeal &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-505267_162-57595225/"&gt;in CBS's July survey&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;It's tempting to look at that 7 percent number as a very bad sign, but even the president doesn't take the position that the law is working perfectly and doesn't need changes. Like most Americans, Obama and the Democratic Party want Obamacare to work. On the other hand, Cruz—and pretty much the entire GOP—want it to fail. For them, it's repeal or bust. Changes to make it work better are off the table. If things get worse between now and November 2014, that position might work out for them, but if the program continues to improve, so will attitudes towards it, and Republicans will find themselves even more out of step with the public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=mW9UaBnI94A:C2_ILD6gUBU:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/mW9UaBnI94A" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>2014</category>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Poll</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257030</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 16:41:27 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257030/-CBS-poll-Good-news-for-Mitt-Romney-bad-news-for-Ted-Cruz</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Here's another idea, Reince</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/nvyYSrRJtIU/-Here-s-another-idea-Reince</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/3246/large/RTR2NTLD.jpg?1344611981" alt="Reince Priebus, chairman of the Republican National Committee, speaks during the 2011 Republican Leadership Conference in New Orleans, Louisiana June 18, 2011. REUTERS/Lee Celano " defang_width="" defang_height="" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
A &lt;a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/ballot-box/senate-races/190867-priebus-to-invite-vulnerable-dems-to-rnc-to-make-case-for"&gt;generous offer&lt;/a&gt; from RNC chairman Reince Priebus:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“We are going to invite them and give them an opportunity to come to the RNC and set up the press conference and tell the media and all the people in their district why it is that they believe ObamaCare is great for this country and great for their constituents,” Priebus said on Fox News’ “On the Record” Tuesday night.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Though something tells me that Democrats will be content to make the case for Obamacare on their own terms, however. On the other hand, Reince might want to put a little bit of time into thinking about how to help Senate Minority Leader Mitch McConnell make the case against Obamacare, because as Salon's Brian Beutler &lt;a href="http://www.salon.com/2013/11/19/the_rights_in_a_box_heres_how_gop_loses_obamacare_fight/"&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;As minority leader, and an in-cycle candidate with a primary challenger, he has to be leading the vanguard of Affordable Care Act opposition. But as a Kentucky senator, and a candidate with a general election opponent, he will soon be running on a platform of taking insurance away from tens, if not hundreds, of thousands of his own constituents.
&lt;p&gt;Kentucky’s exchange — Kynect — is the gold standard for state-based exchanges, and has been since day 1. It has perhaps the highest functioning Obamacare marketplace, relative to uninsured population, of any state in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
As Beutler notes, before Obamacare, 17 percent of adults in Kentucky did not have insurance. By the time McConnell's reelection rolls around (assuming he wins his primary), that number will be in single digits, and it will be because of Obamacare. And when that happens, Mitch is going to have a lot of explaining to do, because the core of his campaign will be a promise to return the uninsured rate back to double digits.
&lt;p&gt;Reince Priebus should start plotting strategy now. His good buddy is going to need it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=nvyYSrRJtIU:_XUuC2ClH-U:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/nvyYSrRJtIU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256819</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 16:10:12 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256819/-Here-s-another-idea-Reince</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cocaine congressman voted to force drug testing for food stamps</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/K_H60voFTCs/-Cocaine-congressman-voted-to-force-drug-testing-for-food-stamps</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58395/large/Trey_Radel_2.jpg?1384960787" alt="Rep. Trey Radel (R-FL) holds a chart about government spending while meeting with constituents." width="550" height="339" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Republican Rep. Trey Radel should be very, very glad he was busted and, having plead guilty, convicted for cocaine possession in Washington, DC, and not his home state of Florida. Because he was only charged with misdemeanor possession, he got just a &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2013/11/20/trey-radel-cocaine-sting-congress/3649619/"&gt;year of probation&lt;/a&gt;. In Florida, he could have faced substantially greater charges and punishment. But Radel's bust raises a question beyond sentencing issues.
&lt;p&gt;Drug-testing requirements for food stamps, unemployment insurance, or welfare are one of the big Republican pushes of the last few years. And at the state level, where many of those bills have come up, Democrats have responded by offering &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2012/01/30/1059941/-Democratic-legislators-keep-giving-Republicans-wedgies-over-drug-testing"&gt;amendments requiring legislators to be tested&lt;/a&gt; themselves. Considering the Radel example, it seems like it might be time for Democrats in the United States House to take up a similar push themselves: Radel &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/11/19/trey-radel-drug-testing_n_4305348.html"&gt;voted to force people to take drug tests to get food stamps&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The House over the summer approved an amendment by Rep. Richard Hudson (R-N.C.) that would let states drug test people on food stamps. The amendment passed by voice vote, meaning members' individual yeas and nays were not recorded. Radel later voted in favor of a broader food stamps bill that included Hudson's measure.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Radel has &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RepTreyRadel/posts/540739472682305"&gt;apologized for his cocaine bust&lt;/a&gt;, issuing a statement that "I struggle with the disease of alcoholism, and this led to an extremely irresponsible choice" and promising to "do whatever is necessary to overcome it, hopefully setting an example for others struggling with this disease." No word on whether he regrets having voted to deny nutrition assistance to people with similar struggles, or believes that members of Congress should be drug tested to get their paychecks.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=K_H60voFTCs:XFFWBUZviWE:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/K_H60voFTCs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Food Stamps</category>
<category>Trey Radel</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1257010</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 15:30:19 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1257010/-Cocaine-congressman-voted-to-force-drug-testing-for-food-stamps</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Healthcare dot gov fixing</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/2NsKtba4mI4/-Healthcare-dot-gov-fixing</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58243/lightbox/1044.png?1384880897"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58243/large/1044.png?1384880897" alt="" width="550" height="397" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;click to enlarge&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=2NsKtba4mI4:GD4vvZ_mqiA:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/2NsKtba4mI4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Matt Bors)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Cartoons</category>
<category>Comics</category>
<category>Healthcare.gov</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256741</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 14:50:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256741/-Healthcare-dot-gov-fixing</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Creigh Deeds stabbing and son's death highlight mental health care gaps</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/7u8sAWFrTv0/-Creigh-Deeds-stabbing-and-son-s-death-highlight-mental-health-care-gaps</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58222/large/RTXQ2KZ.jpg?1384874581" alt="Virginia gubernatorial candidate Creigh Deeds speaks at a rally at Old Dominion University in Norfolk, Virginia, October 27, 2009. &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;REUTERS/Jim Young &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;(UNITED STATES POLITICS) - RTXQ2KZ" width="550" height="376" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Virginia state Sen. Creigh Deeds&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Virginia state Sen. Creigh Deeds, the 2009 Democratic nominee for governor, was upgraded from critical to fair condition Tuesday after being stabbed in the face and chest by his son Austin (called Gus), who then fatally shot himself. Now the case is refocusing attention on Virginia's inadequate mental health system: Gus Deeds &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/local/crime/virginia-state-senator-injured-in-home-another-person-found-dead-inside/2013/11/19/3e419ac4-512c-11e3-9fe0-fd2ca728e67c_story.html"&gt;underwent psychiatric evaluation&lt;/a&gt; Monday and would have been admitted to the hospital overnight, but no beds were available:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;On Monday, a magistrate issued an emergency custody order for Austin Deeds, who was also known as Gus, after he had been evaluated by officials at the Rockbridge County Community Services Board, said Mary Ann Bergeron, the executive director of the Virginia Association of Community Services Boards. The boards oversee the local provision of mental-health services across Virginia. [...]
&lt;p&gt;Rockbridge officials had called hospitals in the area looking for a spot but were unable to find one, Bergeron said. “I can tell you right now, it was multiple hospitals that they called,” she said. “That is a very rural area. The hospitals are few and far between.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Temporary detention orders require an available bed, and a 2012 investigation found that in one 90-day period, beds could not be found for 72 people who otherwise were in serious enough condition to be held involuntarily. After the Virginia Tech massacre, the state invested in mental health, but six years later, the mental health system is still, or again, obviously inadequate. Likely this case will once again prompt expressions of concern over the issue in the legislature, but as we've seen so many times, it's less likely to produce the kind of real investment that leads to lasting change.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="update"&gt;&lt;a name="20131120084219" href="/story/2013/11/20/1256994/-Creigh-Deeds-stabbing-and-son-s-death-highlight-mental-health-care-gaps#20131120084219"&gt;&lt;b&gt; 8:42 AM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.nbc12.com/story/24022007/sen-creigh-deeds-condition-upgraded-to-good?utm_content=buffer5d200&amp;amp;utm_source=buffer&amp;amp;utm_medium=facebook&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Buffer"&gt;Some good news:&lt;/a&gt; Deeds has now been upgraded from fair to good condition by the University of Virginia Medical Center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=7u8sAWFrTv0:ky03CL_nhPU:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/7u8sAWFrTv0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Creigh Deeds</category>
<category>Mental Health</category>
<category>Virginia</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256994</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 14:25:18 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256994/-Creigh-Deeds-stabbing-and-son-s-death-highlight-mental-health-care-gaps</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Daily Kos Elections Morning Digest: Texas and California are swapping citizens in near-equal numbers</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/gneqAuYiqr0/-Daily-Kos-Elections-Morning-Digest-Texas-and-California-are-swapping-citizens-in-near-equal-numbers</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;a href="http://campaigns.dailykos.com/signup_page/electionsdigest"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images1.dailykos.com/i/user/73/Elections-MorningDigest.jpg" alt="Daily Kos Elections Morning Digest banner" height="100" width="550" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Want the scoop on hot races around the country? Get the digest emailed to you each weekday morning. &lt;a href="http://campaigns.dailykos.com/signup_page/electionsdigest"&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Leading Off&lt;/b&gt;:
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#1" id="1" name="1"&gt;•&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Demographics&lt;/b&gt;: The Census Bureau released a slew of data on state-to-state migration on Monday showing that Americans have become significantly &lt;a href="http://www.census.gov/newsroom/releases/archives/mobility_of_the_population/cb13-192.html"&gt;less mobile&lt;/a&gt; than they used to be, with just 11.7 percent moving in the last year, near historic lows. That's interesting in itself, but if you're wondering where people are going, a new &lt;a href="http://vizynary.com/2013/11/18/restless-america-state-to-state-migration-in-2012/"&gt;data visualization&lt;/a&gt; from analyst Chris Walker really makes the numbers pop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of a boring bar chart, Walker offers a dazzling pinwheel of webs between states. Walker's version is interactive, and you should click through to play with it, but here's a still to give you a taste:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images1.dailykos.com/i/user/96305/Migration.jpg" alt="Graph of migration data" height="520" width="550" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
If you want to drill down to a particular state, you can mouse over each state and see individual links to other states. For instance, contra conservatives claims, not everyone in California is moving to Texas. In fact, nearly as many Texans are moving to California as Californians are moving to Texas, and nearly as many Californians are moving to &lt;i&gt;Washington&lt;/i&gt; as they are to Texas.
&lt;p&gt;Atlantic Cities also has some more stationary images, like the one above, as well as &lt;a href="http://www.theatlanticcities.com/jobs-and-economy/2013/11/fascinating-look-migration-patterns-among-american-states/7630/"&gt;a brief interview&lt;/a&gt; with Walker. (David Jarman)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=gneqAuYiqr0:g_f2jHqgdeE:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/gneqAuYiqr0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Nir)</author>
<category>Aimee Belgard</category>
<category>Alan Nunnelee</category>
<category>Alex Sink</category>
<category>AZ-02</category>
<category>Bill Nelson</category>
<category>Brad Johnson</category>
<category>Champ Edmunds</category>
<category>Charlie Crist</category>
<category>Chris McDaniel</category>
<category>CO-Gov</category>
<category>Corey Stapleton</category>
<category>Creigh Deeds</category>
<category>David Jolly</category>
<category>Delbert Hosemann</category>
<category>Demographics</category>
<category>DKE Daily Digests</category>
<category>Elections</category>
<category>EMILY's List</category>
<category>FL-13</category>
<category>FL-19</category>
<category>FL-26</category>
<category>FL-Gov</category>
<category>GA-Sen</category>
<category>Greg Brophy</category>
<category>Gregg Harper</category>
<category>Jennifer Wexton</category>
<category>Jim Hood</category>
<category>Joe Martinez</category>
<category>John Amodeo</category>
<category>John Bohlinger</category>
<category>John Hickenlooper</category>
<category>John Lewis</category>
<category>John Walsh</category>
<category>Joseph Scarpa</category>
<category>Kathleen Peters</category>
<category>Ken Cuccinelli</category>
<category>KS-02</category>
<category>Laura Fjeld</category>
<category>Lucas Overby</category>
<category>Margie Wakefield</category>
<category>Mark Bircher</category>
<category>Matt Rosendale</category>
<category>MI-Sen</category>
<category>Michael Levinson</category>
<category>Migration</category>
<category>Mike Kopp</category>
<category>MS-Sen</category>
<category>MT-AL</category>
<category>MT-Sen</category>
<category>NC-06</category>
<category>NJ State Assembly</category>
<category>NJ-03</category>
<category>PA-08</category>
<category>Phil Gingrey</category>
<category>Polls</category>
<category>Public Policy Polling</category>
<category>Quinnipiac</category>
<category>Ron Barber</category>
<category>Ronnie Musgrove</category>
<category>Ryan Zinke</category>
<category>Scott Gessler</category>
<category>Shaughnessy Naughton</category>
<category>Sheila Olem</category>
<category>St. Pete Polls</category>
<category>Stacey Pickering</category>
<category>Steve Daines</category>
<category>Steven Palazzo</category>
<category>Tate Reeves</category>
<category>Terri Lynn Land</category>
<category>Terry McAuliffe</category>
<category>Thad Cochran</category>
<category>Tim Eustace</category>
<category>Tom Tancredo</category>
<category>Travis Childers</category>
<category>Trey Radel</category>
<category>VA State Senate</category>
<category>VA-Gov</category>
<category>VA-Sen</category>
<category>Vincent Mazzeo</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256883</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 13:00:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256883/-Daily-Kos-Elections-Morning-Digest-Texas-and-California-are-swapping-citizens-in-near-equal-numbers</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Daily Kos Radio is LIVE at 9am ET!</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/N_DBuqJWVsA/-Daily-Kos-Radio-is-LIVE-at-9am-ET</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/blog/dailykosradio"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/4434/large/398x296_FacebookInStream.jpg?1346121562" alt="Daily Kos Radio logo" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Kos Radio's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show podcasts are now available through iTunes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we're now being broadcast live on We Act Radio, Washington, DC's WPWC 1480 AM! So if you're in the area, tune in on your actual radio. And if not, you can always find their live stream at &lt;a href="http://www.weactradio.com/"&gt;WeActRadio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joan McCarter&lt;/strong&gt; is slated to join us for her regular Wednesday appearance. Good timing, too, since the filibuster showdown is about ready to hit fever pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, here's an &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mmusson/status/403007618677215233"&gt;endorsement&lt;/a&gt; for the show:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mmusson/status/403007618677215233"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/132372448/303198053_412e97cde9_s_normal.jpg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;@KagroX Since your master course on filibuster reform, I can barely watch any discussion about it on other news programs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mmusson"&gt;@mmusson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Wouldn't you like us to ruin your television news consumption for you, too?
&lt;p&gt;Hey, that's "disruption!" Someone call a venture capitalist!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're LIVE at 9:00 a.m. ET with &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt;, thanks to NetrootsRadio.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen LIVE here:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Daily Kos Radio Player&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-l"&gt;&lt;object classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" width="180" height="120" bgcolor="#FFFFFF"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/ffmp3-config.swf" /&gt;
&lt;param name="flashvars" value="url=http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls;;&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;codec=mp3&amp;amp;volume=20&amp;amp;buffering=5&amp;amp;skin=http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/skins/mcclean/ffmp3-mcclean.xml&amp;amp;title=NetrootsRadio&amp;amp;welcome=We%20are NetrootsRadio" /&gt;
&lt;param name="wmode" value="window" /&gt;
&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;
&lt;param name="scale" value="noscale" /&gt;
&lt;embed src="http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/ffmp3-config.swf" flashvars="url=http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls;;&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;codec=mp3&amp;amp;volume=20&amp;amp;buffering=5&amp;amp;skin=http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/skins/mcclean/ffmp3-mcclean.xml&amp;amp;title=NetrootsRadio&amp;amp;welcome=We%20are NetrootsRadio" width="180" scale="noscale" height="120" wmode="window" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls"&gt;Click this Link&lt;/a&gt; to Listen on your iTunes, Winamp or Windows Media Player
&lt;p&gt;Can't see the live stream and/or podcast players in these posts? Do you use NoScript or something similar to control Javascript? Want to? Remember to enable Libsyn and Shoutcastplayer, and you'll see our players every morning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or if you prefer, why not &lt;a href="http://landing.stitcher.com/?vurl=dailykos"&gt;download the Stitcher app&lt;/a&gt; on your favorite mobile device, and search for the Netroots Radio live stream? And hey, when you do, be sure to sign up with the promo code DAILYKOS, and earn Daily Kos Radio $1 in the Stitcher affiliate program!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do remember to "favorite" us while you're at Stitcher. We're bouncing up and down in the rankings these days, and the more of you who help us, the more listeners out there who'll find us on the Stitcher network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miss our last show? You can catch it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2558402/height/302/width/540/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="302" width="540" scrolling="no" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Need more info on how to listen? Find it below the fold.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=N_DBuqJWVsA:O9aNf179p30:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/N_DBuqJWVsA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Waldman)</author>
<category>Daily Kos Radio</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256927</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 13:30:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256927/-Daily-Kos-Radio-is-LIVE-at-9am-ET</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cheers and Jeers: Wednesday</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/FGykGIirlDE/-Cheers-and-Jeers-Wednesday</link>
<description>&lt;div id="uimg_center"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images2.dailykos.com/i/user/8411/CheersAndJeers.jpg" alt="C&amp;amp;J Banner" height="100" width="550" title="C&amp;amp;J Banner" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the GREAT STATE OF MAINE…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;BillyFact: Illinois Gay Marriage Edition&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History will be made today in the Land of Lincoln when Illinois Governor Pat Quinn &lt;a href="http://www.suntimes.com/opinions/23774887-474/gay-marriage-bill-signing-a-victory-for-equality-defeat-for-intolerance.html" target="_blank"&gt;signs into law a bill allowing same-sex couples to get married&lt;/a&gt;. To help separate fact from fiction, here's a helpful guide you can slice off of your monitor with a penknife and keep handy in your wallet for present and future reference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;b&gt;Claim:&lt;/b&gt; Before the ink is dry, waves of locusts will swarm the entire state and make life a living hell.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BillyFact Rates This Claim:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;u&gt;False&lt;/u&gt;. Locusts always wait until &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; the ink is dry. Then you're screwed.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Claim:&lt;/b&gt; Gay couples can't get married immediately after the law is signed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BillyFact Rates This Claim:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;u&gt;True&lt;/u&gt;. The law actually takes effect next June for a very good reason: Because.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58296/small/marriage.jpg?1384890514" alt="Illinois Unites for Marriage logo after Illinois victory" width="200" height="200" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;True!!!&lt;br /&gt;
-&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Claim:&lt;/b&gt; There's no way to prevent the sky from falling when the law takes effect.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BillyFact Rates This Claim:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;u&gt;False&lt;/u&gt;. An elaborate system of hydraulics (with backups) will keep this from happening, and each unit is controlled separately to prevent systemic failure. Some sections of the sky may sag during scheduled maintenance, but this is temporary and such work will only be done at night.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Claim:&lt;/b&gt; The National Organization for Marriage (NOM) is fully prepared to flood the state with millions of dollars to get the law repealed and restore heterosexual values to Illinois.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BillyFact Rates This Claim:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;u&gt;False&lt;/u&gt;. Their latest tax returns show that &lt;a href="http://joemygod.blogspot.com/2013/11/nom-posts-2012-990-27m-in-red.html" target="_blank"&gt;NOM is nearly 3 million dollars in the red&lt;/a&gt;. They can't even bring heterosexual values to a cup of coffee anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Claim:&lt;/b&gt; It's okay to laugh at the incompetence and disarray at NOM.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BillyFact Rates This Claim:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;u&gt;True&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Claim:&lt;/b&gt; Gay marriage means kissing, and kissing increases the risk of cooties.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BillyFact Rates This Claim:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;u&gt;True&lt;/u&gt;. But cooties vaccinations are now covered under the Affordable Care Act. Details at healthcare.gov/cooties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Claim:&lt;/b&gt; Catholic Bishop Thomas Paprocki is going to spend today &lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/lgbt/2013/11/15/2947921/illinois-bishop-offer-exorcism-marriage-equality/" target="_blank"&gt;conducting an exorcism&lt;/a&gt; that will cleanse the state of "evil" homosexual demons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BillyFact Rates This Claim:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;u&gt;False&lt;/u&gt;. Catholic Bishop Thomas Paprocki is going to spend today being a whiny 12th-century asshole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
We hope this helps clear up some of the confusion. Congratulations, Illinois. Welcome to the future.
&lt;p&gt;Cheers and Jeers starts below the fold... [Swoosh!!] RIGHTNOW! [Gong!!]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=FGykGIirlDE:jJFtTngdm4o:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/FGykGIirlDE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Bill in Portland Maine)</author>
<category>Cheers and Jeers</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256727</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 13:17:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256727/-Cheers-and-Jeers-Wednesday</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Abbreviated Pundit Round-up: The nuclear option; media revisits Obamacare narrative</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/e1TIK1nLJoo/-Abbreviated-Pundit-Round-up-The-nuclear-option-media-revisits-Obamacare-narrative</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/post-partisan/wp/2013/11/19/the-white-house-is-wrong-lots-of-people-dont-understand-obamacare/?hpid=z3"&gt;Stephen Stromberg&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Obama bears a lot of blame for the confusion on the recent cancellations. He set expectations when he promised that Americans could keep their health-care plans. His promise didn’t bear out, which looks like incompetence, dishonesty or both. High complexity was also the byproduct of Democrats’ choice to keep most of the existing system intact and build around it.
&lt;p&gt;But health-care reform was always going to be complicated — and easy for uncomplicated ideologues to denounce. Republican demagoguery — from the days of “death panels” to the current frenzy over cancellation letters — has done much more to confound public understanding of the Affordable Care Act, not to mention the law’s implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year, voters should judge the law based on how many more people ultimately get affordable health-care coverage, and at what cost to taxpayers. Right now, many appear to be judging the law based on misunderstandings and warped representations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Forbidden words for most pundits: maybe we should wait and see on Obamacare before rushing to judgment.
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SCOTUSblog/status/403124652996038656"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/378800000053782108/5f7ca6d4c00caa90f2072249447a11aa_normal.png" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;#scotus should announce it will hear the religion challenge to the ACA contraception mandate next Tues afternoon: &lt;a href="http://t.co/WQuVkEMtgR"&gt;http://t.co/...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/SCOTUSblog"&gt;@SCOTUSblog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/plum-line/wp/2013/11/19/harry-reid-is-set-to-go-nuclear/"&gt;Greg Sargent&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;Senator Harry Reid appears set to go nuclear — before Thanksgiving.
&lt;p&gt;With Senate Republicans blocking a third Obama nomination to the powerful D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals, a senior Senate Democratic leadership aide tells me Reid is now all but certain to move to change the Senate rules by simple majority — doing away with the filibuster on executive and judicial nominations, with the exception of the Supreme Court – as early as this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a presser today, Reid told reporters he was taking another look at rules reform, but didn’t give a timeline. The senior leadership aide goes further, saying it’s hard to envision circumstances under which Reid doesn’t act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
More politics and policy below the fold.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=e1TIK1nLJoo:02nC34GjWVI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/e1TIK1nLJoo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Greg Dworkin)</author>
<category>Abbreviated Pundit Round-up</category>
<category>APR</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256888</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 12:30:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/20/1256888/-Abbreviated-Pundit-Round-up-The-nuclear-option-media-revisits-Obamacare-narrative</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Open thread for night owls: Another reason to hate commuting</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/rGqEMj_GJOs/-Open-thread-for-night-owls-Another-reason-to-hate-commuting</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/7382/large/Snowy-Blue-Owl.jpg?1349052001" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Long commutes may make you &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/monkey-cage/wp/2013/11/19/long-commutes-are-making-americans-more-politically-apathetic/?Post+generic=%3Ftid%3Dsm_twitter_washingtonpost"&gt;less politically active&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;That is an implication of &lt;a href="http://apr.sagepub.com/content/early/2013/08/22/1532673X13498265.full.pdf+html"&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; by political scientists &lt;a href="http://www.polisci.uconn.edu/people/faculty/faculty.php?name=newman"&gt;Benjamin Newman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/joshuamjohnsonstonybrook/"&gt;Joshua Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.mendeley.com/profiles/patrick-lown/"&gt;Patrick Lown.&lt;/a&gt; (Another link to the piece is &lt;a href="http://www.polisci.uconn.edu/people/faculty/doc/Newman%20et%20al%20_TheDailyGrind.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.) They show that Americans who report longer commutes say they are less involved in politics.&amp;nbsp; Participation in politics is 12 points lower for people with a 60-minute commute relative to people who work from home and have no commute.&amp;nbsp; Why does this effect emerge?&amp;nbsp; Newman and colleagues suggest it is because commuting saps people’s underlying interest in politics. [...]
&lt;p&gt;[I]f it were just a question of time, then we might expect people who work long hours to be less involved in politics too. &amp;nbsp;But that isn’t true: people who report working more hours are no more or less likely to participate in politics. Instead, the authors argue that commuting depletes our psychological resources in unique ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Great, I can see it now. The new Republican plan for electoral success: kill all transportation projects, trapping Americans in soul-crushing commutes that drain their will to live or vote.
&lt;p&gt;Well, that's not really different from the old plan. Also, it comes with talk radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2009/11/19/806080/-Any-Afghan-Surge-a-Snare-and-a-Delusion"&gt;Blast from the Past&lt;/a&gt;. At Daily Kos on this date in &lt;b&gt;2009&lt;/b&gt;—&lt;i&gt;Any Afghan 'Surge' a Snare and a Delusion&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width="96%" align="center" style="background-color:rgb(249,246,234);border_collapse: collapse; border: 1px dashed black;" defang_cellpadding="5%"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Given the record of Goldman Sachs (as detailed in McClatchy's five-part series), AIG,Halliburton and other supposedly upright U.S. corporations, it's a tad arrogant to complain about the corruption of other countries. Endemic or not, the wink-wink, nod-nod deals of much of the Third World amount to peanuts when compared with the rip-offs visited on taxpayers, investors and consumers here at home. So, while the U.S. ranks 19th on the Transparency Index's corruption scale, and Afghanistan ranks 179th, one step off the bottom, there's a little more to the picture than can be addressed by such metrics.
&lt;p&gt;Be that as it may, corruption is viewed as one of the key obstacles in dealing with the resurgent Taliban in Afghanistan. That corruption, as the "leaked cables" sent to the White House by U.S. Ambassador to Kabul Karl Eikenberry pointed out, may make the sending of more troops foolish if President Karzai, newly sworn in after a tainted election, cannot be made to root it out. As Tom Engelhardt explains, however, rooting it out is like asking Karzai either to commit suicide or "drink the sea."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BillinPortland/status/402917067218628608"&gt;Tweet of the Day&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BillinPortland/status/402917067218628608"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/895386526/091209_067_normal.jpg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Breaking: George W. Bush now says he understands why Turkey got upset when he pardoned the country every November for eight straight years.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/BillinPortland"&gt;@BillinPortland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2558402/height/200/width/250/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen="" height="200" scrolling="no" width="250"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
On &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256788/-Daily-Kos-Radio-s-KITM-podcast-ACA-roundup-pension-pirates-want-Soc-Sec-cuts-WalMart-double-dip"&gt;today's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show&lt;/a&gt;, new polling fans Obamacare flames, and Gettysburg outrage is manufactured. &lt;strong&gt;Greg Dworkin&lt;/strong&gt; rounds up headlines, the surge in ACA enrollment, hyperbolic declarations of the end of Dem presidencies, and Jonathan Cohn's "Six Things the Media Doesn't Understand About Obamacare." Surprise! The Institute for Policy Studies says the people pushing to cut your Social Security are super rich and don't need Social Security. One of those people: the CEO of WalMart, where workers are now holding food drives for their fellow low-paid workers! Speaking of WalMart: GunFAIL! And Norway joins the parade of allies discovering NSA prying.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;hr width="75%" color="#000099" size="2" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256672/-High-Impact-Posts-November-18-2013"&gt;High Impact Posts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256767/-Top-Comments-Gettysburg-Address-Edition"&gt;Top Comments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=rGqEMj_GJOs:xV_XHN_7Z5s:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/rGqEMj_GJOs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Hunter)</author>
<category>Open Thread for Night Owls</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256840</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 04:30:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256840/-Open-thread-for-night-owls-Another-reason-to-hate-commuting</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Economics Daily Digest: Cheers for enforcing labor laws</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/37i7j_8YtnQ/-Economics-Daily-Digest-Cheers-for-enforcing-labor-laws</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/12380/large/EconomicsDailyDigest_(1).jpg?1355365637" alt="Economics Daily Digest by the Roosevelt Institute banner" width="550" height="100" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By Rachel Goldfarb, originally published on &lt;a href="http://www.nextnewdeal.net/daily-digest-november-19-cheers-enforcing-labor-laws"&gt;Next New Deal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://rooseveltinstitute.us1.list-manage2.com/subscribe?u=5044841afea7ba83dc11db61f&amp;amp;id=e4428ba350"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to receive the Daily Digest via email.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wal-Mart Faces Warehouse Horror Allegations and Federal Labor Board Complaint&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href="http://www.salon.com/2013/11/18/breaking_wal_mart_faces_warehouse_horror_allegations_and_federal_labor_board_complaint/"&gt;Salon&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh Eidelson reports on Wal-Mart's no-good, very bad day in labor news. Between allegations of worker safety concerns in California and a National Labor Relations Board complaint about strike retaliation, Wal-Mart started the week with a bang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reality Check: Obamacare is Not to Blame for Wal-Mart's Sluggish Sales&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/nov/18/walmart-blame-obamacare-sluggish-growth"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heidi Moore thinks it's ridiculous when big retailers try to use the Affordable Care Act as a scapegoat for their disappointing financial performance. Even if every person who enrolled in the ACA stopped shopping at Wal-Mart, it wouldn't cause this drop in sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Elizabeth Warren to Congress: Grandma "Will Be Left to Starve" If We Cut Social Security&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href="http://www.motherjones.com/mojo/2013/11/elizabeth-warren-social-security-retirement"&gt;MoJo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erica Eichelberger discusses Senator Warren's speech on the Senate floor yesterday, in which she decried the very idea of cutting Social Security benefits. The Senator insisted that balancing the budget couldn't come at the expense of seniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;American Inequality in Six Charts&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/johncassidy/2013/11/inequality-and-growth-what-do-we-know.html"&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Cassidy looks at charts shared by presenters at the launch of the Washington Center for Equitable Growth last week. He's particularly interested in the questions these charts raise about the relationship between inequality and growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;There is Not Enough Affordable Rental Housing&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href="http://blog.metrotrends.org/2013/11/affordable-rental-housing/"&gt;MetroTrends Blog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erika Poethig explains how programs for affordable housing haven't kept up with the expanding need. She suggests that policy changes like raising the minimum wage will help, but more proactive policy will make a much bigger difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Democrats Push For Extending A Lifeline For The Long-Term Unemployed&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/economy/2013/11/18/2957171/democrats-unemployment/"&gt;ThinkProgress&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bryce Covert reports on the push for extended unemployment benefits. The federal program, which helps support people who have been out of work for more than six months, will otherwise disappear at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;New on Next New Deal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nextnewdeal.net/courageous-boeing-workers-say-no-corporate-extortion"&gt;Courageous Boeing Workers Say No to Corporate Extortion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roosevelt Institute Senior Fellow Richard Kirsch applauds the Machinists Local 751, which voted down a contract despite the risk of lost work. The union saw this contract as an offense to past workers - and a destruction of middle class opportunity for future workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=37i7j_8YtnQ:HpRBlzKfRLY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/37i7j_8YtnQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Roosevelt Institute)</author>
<category>Economic Inequality</category>
<category>Economy</category>
<category>Jobs</category>
<category>Social Safety Net</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256728</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 16:19:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256728/-Economics-Daily-Digest-Cheers-for-enforcing-labor-laws</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>GOP commits double fraud with Obamacare navigator smear campaign</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/mm1iQ5iokvU/-GOP-commits-double-fraud-with-Obamacare-navigator-smear-campaign</link>
<description>&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;img border="0" src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58163/large/scott_real_health_fraud.png?1384809724" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week's target in the never-ending Republican crusade to sabotage the Affordable Care Act is the &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/dc/obamacare-navigators-gop-smear-campaign"&gt;Obamacare navigators&lt;/a&gt;, the dozens of community groups, hospitals and other non-profit organizations who have received federal grants to help Americans enroll in new health insurance plans. After launching a &lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/newsdesk/2013/11/obstructing-obamacares-navigators.html"&gt;House probe&lt;/a&gt; of the groups and enacting &lt;a href="http://www.nationaljournal.com/health-care/the-fight-of-obamacare-s-navigators-against-republican-hurdles-20131030"&gt;draconian state restrictions&lt;/a&gt; on their activities, Republicans are warning that the navigators, like &lt;a href="http://dailycaller.com/2013/11/13/to-speak-to-a-nigerian-prince-about-your-healthcare-press-1-now/"&gt;Nigerian email scammers&lt;/a&gt;, could be criminals intent on stealing Americans' identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, this GOP's cynical attempt to prevent Americans from obtaining health insurance is a double fraud. After all, President Bush's unfunded $400 billion &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/12/1255114/-O-Keefe-and-GOP-allies-forget-Bush-s-Medicare-Navigators-like-ACORN"&gt;Medicare prescription drug program used navigators&lt;/a&gt;, too. Many of the same groups are Obamacare navigators now. (Some of the Bush navigators, like ACORN and the arch-conservative 60 Plus Association, are not.) &amp;nbsp;And as it turns out, the real threat to bilk billions of dollars from the American people isn't a bunch of non-profit social workers with foreign sounding names, but comes from national hospital chains and device manufacturers with very American names like Florida Governor Rick Scott.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/dc/obamacare-navigators-gop-smear-campaign"&gt;TPM's Dylan Scott&lt;/a&gt; reported Monday, Senate Minority Leader Mitch McConnell is leading the GOP effort to slander the navigators. The last thing Americans seeking health coverage need, McConnell warned, "is to worry about some felon stealing their identity." Last week, conservative talking point bulimic &lt;a href="http://dailycaller.com/2013/11/13/to-speak-to-a-nigerian-prince-about-your-healthcare-press-1-now/"&gt;Ann Coulter&lt;/a&gt; went a step further, selectively using the record of Medicare fraud to argue that "the country is now chock-full of people who come from cultures where criminality and government corruption is a way of life":&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Do you notice anything that stands out about the list of convicts? Would any of their names have sounded strange to Ben Franklin? Of 22 people convicted of defrauding American taxpayers by fraudulently billing Medicare or Medicaid, at least 17 have almost comically foreign names.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
One name that wouldn't have sounded strange to the likes of Ben Franklin is &lt;a href="http://miamiherald.typepad.com/nakedpolitics/2010/06/rick-scotts-role-in-columbiahca-scandal.html"&gt;Rick Scott&lt;/a&gt;. And as you'll recall, before he became Republican Governor of Florida, the man with the all-American sounding name presided over the company that committed perhaps the largest Medicare fraud in history. As the Miami Herald recounted in June 2010:&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=mm1iQ5iokvU:wXtRpdmMzv4:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/mm1iQ5iokvU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jon Perr)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Ann Coulter</category>
<category>Columbia HCA</category>
<category>George W. Bush</category>
<category>Health Care</category>
<category>HHS</category>
<category>Insurance</category>
<category>John Cornyn</category>
<category>Medicare</category>
<category>Medicare Part D</category>
<category>Mike Leavitt</category>
<category>Mitch McConnell</category>
<category>Navigators</category>
<category>Prescription Drug Plan</category>
<category>Rick Scott</category>
<category>Tommy Thompson</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256540</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 21:21:50 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/18/1256540/-GOP-commits-double-fraud-with-Obamacare-navigator-smear-campaign</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Here's why a record number of women in the workforce is no cause for celebration</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/d807dgT2Dyc/-Here-s-why-a-record-number-of-women-in-the-workforce-is-no-cause-for-celebration</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58109/large/dreamstime_s_21524378.jpg?1384801837" alt="Donut shop cashier takes customer order." width="550" height="366" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Too many jobs like this.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
In a piece of news where the one-sentence version sounds better than the in-depth version, &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702303755504579203833804047994"&gt;more women are now employed&lt;/a&gt; than were at the beginning of the recession:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A record 67.5 million women are working today, up from the prior peak of 67.4 million in early 2008, according to the Labor Department's latest tally of payrolls that captured the full rebound for the first time. By comparison, 69 million men currently have jobs, below their high of 70.9 million in June 2007.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Why doesn't the in-depth version sound as good? For one thing, since the population is growing, there should have been job growth in the past five years:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;If the share [of Americans who are working] had remained constant since the economy tipped into recession in December 2007, women would hold an additional 3.8 million jobs today, according to an estimate by the Institute for Women's Policy Research. Men would have 5.5 million more jobs.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
For another thing, employment is recovering more quickly for women than for men because women are &lt;a href="http://www.epi.org/blog/jobs-gap-bigger-men-industries-men-gaining/"&gt;more likely to be employed in the industries&lt;/a&gt; that have had more job growth. But those include lower-paying industries like hospitality and retail, and:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;Within industries&lt;/i&gt; however, the story is different: look at the percentage point difference in employment growth between women and men in manufacturing, for example, and you’ll see that female employment has dropped 18.2% since 2007 while male employment has fallen by much less—10.8%. Conversely, in health care and social assistance both men and women saw gains in employment since 2007, but growth in male employment surpassed growth in female employment by 5 percentage points. In 9 of the 16 major industries (and 5 of the 7 largest industries), men have either regained a larger share of their 2007 employment in than women have, or have lost less since the Great Recession began.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
So as good as "women have recovered all the jobs lost in the recession" sounds, it's not good news for equality or jobs.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=d807dgT2Dyc:V943_pVntDQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/d807dgT2Dyc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Jobs</category>
<category>Recession</category>
<category>Women</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256478</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 19:13:02 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/18/1256478/-Here-s-why-a-record-number-of-women-in-the-workforce-is-no-cause-for-celebration</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>NSA says it's overwhelmed by records requests they refuse anyway</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/SnmngbI95BI/-NSA-says-it-s-overwhelmed-by-records-requests-they-ignore-nbsp-anyway</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58168/large/dreamstime_s_16611668.jpg?1384814110" alt="Face in profile in dark looking at a Facebook page." width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='293' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/559.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Security Agency has a problem with the American public. Well, not just one problem, considering the PR disaster for them the Snowden leaks have created. But one they're grappling with now: how to keep up with &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2013/11/17/nsa-grapples-with-988-increase-in-open-records-requests/3519889/"&gt;turning down&lt;/a&gt; the thousands and thousands of requests from citizens to discover if they've been spied on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Americans are inundating the NSA with open-records requests, leading to an 888% increase in such inquiries in the past fiscal year. Anyone asking is getting a standard pre-written letter saying the NSA can neither confirm nor deny that any information has been gathered.
&lt;p&gt;"This was the largest spike we've ever had," said Pamela Phillips, the chief of the NSA Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act Office, which handles all records requests to the agency. "We've had requests from individuals who want any records we have on their phone calls, their phone numbers, their e-mail addresses, their IP addresses, anything like that." [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her 19-person staff is grappling to deal with the boom in requests, she said. More than 900 are still pending, although the NSA tries to get back to people in the 20 days required by law, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it can take months, even years, to get a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Why it's so difficult and takes so long to send a form letter saying, in effect, go pound sand isn't at all clear. But maybe they should just make it easy on themselves. They've got everyone's email addresses and phone numbers. They could just pop and email or text message to deliver the bad news. Or maybe they could save some time by &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; collecting the data from absolutely everyone and just focus on the bad guys. That should free up some staff.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=SnmngbI95BI:hQ6v-NkngkQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/SnmngbI95BI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>National Security Agency</category>
<category>Surveillance</category>
<category>Wiretapping</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256564</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 22:36:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/18/1256564/-NSA-says-it-s-overwhelmed-by-records-requests-they-ignore-nbsp-anyway</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Mixed reaction from states on administration's fix for cancelled health policies</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/e0VhJxZEcwE/-Mixed-reaction-from-states-on-administration-s-fix-for-cancelled-health-nbsp-policies</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/57780/large/dreamstime_s_11031881.jpg?1384550756" alt="Los Angeles-September 22: Demonstrators rally outside of headquarters of Anthem Blue Cross Insurance Company in support of health care reform. The Big Insurance: Sick of It Rally was sponsored by MoveOn.org and California Coalition of Health Care For Amer" width="550" height="366" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/14/1255572/-What-the-Obamacare-fix-does-and-how-it-could-be-nbsp-better"&gt;administrative fix&lt;/a&gt; to the problem of health insurance cancellations President Obama announced is going to be up to states to implement. So far, only a &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/11/states-divided-over-complying-with-obamacare-fix-99968.html"&gt;handful of states&lt;/a&gt; have decided whether or not they'll allow insurers to continue to sell substandard policies to current customers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The initial reaction to the White House “fix” didn’t run along the usual red state-blue state lines. Even a reliable White House ally like Massachusetts Gov. Deval Patrick couldn’t say whether his state would back the administration’s cancellation plan. [...]
&lt;p&gt;Those on board with the White House strategy early on range the political gamut, though. California Insurance Commissioner Dave Jones and Florida Insurance Commissioner Kevin McCarty, who’ve taken almost exactly opposite positions on Obamacare, said they support the White House on cancellations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kentucky, which is running its own exchange, and Ohio Lt. Gov. Mary Taylor, a fervent Obamacare critic, said they’ll work to help plans to renew if they choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, commissioners Mike Chaney of Mississippi and Ralph Hudgens of Georgia said Obama’s plan isn’t of much use use for their states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Washington state has decided not to allow it, as did Rhode Island, while Colorado's insurance commissioner had already—previous to the announcement—decided to allow some of these plans to be grandfathered. South Carolina announced Monday that &lt;a href="http://www.thestate.com/2013/11/15/3100087/about-face-could-impact-14-insurers.html"&gt;it will allow&lt;/a&gt; the policies to continue. Other states are still trying to decide.
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, health insurers are still grumbling about the impossibility of uncancelling cancelled policies. The only problem they have there is that whole &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/15/1255924/-300-000-Floridians-health-policy-cancellations-undone"&gt;Florida thing&lt;/a&gt;, where Florida Blue reversed itself for about 300,000 customers. One suspects that the real problem for insurers is that if they decide not to continue these policies, it won't be Obama's fault anymore, but their own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=e0VhJxZEcwE:ld__c2TlyAs:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/e0VhJxZEcwE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Health Insurance</category>
<category>Health Insurance Reform</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256550</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 21:48:22 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/18/1256550/-Mixed-reaction-from-states-on-administration-s-fix-for-cancelled-health-nbsp-policies</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Marco Rubio's shiny new Obamacare lie</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/uXYHxL6EKJ8/-Marco-Rubio-s-shiny-new-Obamacare-lie</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/44482/large/RTX10MPF.jpg?1376413368" alt="Senator Marco Rubio (R-FL) drinks water before giving his speech at the Faith &amp;amp; Freedom Coalition Road to Majority Conference Kickoff Luncheon in Washington June 13, 2013. &amp;amp;nbsp; REUTERS/Gary Cameron" width="550" height="453" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Rubio wants the GOP to swallow yet another false claim about Obamacare&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Republican Sen. Marco Rubio of Florida &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702303985504579205743008770218"&gt;invents a new reason&lt;/a&gt; to oppose Obamacare, claiming that the legislation secretly created a taxpayer-subsidized slush fund giving the Obama administration the authority to bail out political allies in the health insurance industry. In Rubio's words:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;When ObamaCare was debated and passed in 2009 and 2010, none of its proponents, including the president, told the American people that the law granted the federal government the authority to bail out insurance companies at the expense of taxpayers. But now their dirty little secret is out, and it should be wiped out from the law.
&lt;p&gt;Americans are sick and tired of Washington politicians picking winners and losers—and nowhere is this practice more grotesquely evident than taxpayer-funded bailouts, which assault the economic values of our free enterprise system in favor of those who are politically connected and whose lobbyists know the right people to call and levers to pull. ObamaCare is a living monument to this culture, and no one loses more than the average American.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
If this were true, it would be cause for alarm, but aside from the ludicrous claim about secrecy—the legislation has been publicly available from the start—he's badly distorting the the reality of what the legislation does in order to make his deceptive bailout claim.
&lt;p&gt;As Michael Hiltzik of the &lt;em&gt;L.A. Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/business/hiltzik/la-fi-mh-cynical-20131119,0,3568906.story#axzz2l7LZr1sS"&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt;, Rubio is talking about &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/business/hiltzik/la-fi-mh-meltdown-20131023,0,7172280.story#axzz2l6NbabkP"&gt;a provision&lt;/a&gt; of the health care law that creates "risk corridors" to protect insurance companies from the possibility of getting a more sick customers than expected by covering some (but not all) of their expenses above their "target cost." These "risk corridors" don't just protect insurers, however: They also protect consumers by requiring insurers whose actual costs are below their target cost to refund a portion of the money to the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no guarantee the two line items will balance out, but the risk corridor provision does not create a secret discretionary bailout fund as Rubio claims. Instead, it creates a temporary mechanism that will last just three years to help mitigate risk as insurers determine appropriate prices. Without it, insurers would raise prices, effectively dealing a double whammy to consumers since insurance companies would be allowed to pocket the additional profits, even as consumers are mandated to buy their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Rubio surely must understand, risk corridors are an essential part of Obamacare. It's one thing for him to propose repealing Obamacare in its entirety, but for him to propose removing a provision like this without offering an alternative mechanism for stabilizing prices is nothing but demagoguery. If you're going to call yourself a transplant surgeon, removing the patient's heart isn't enough—you need a replacement. Fortunately for Rubio, that's something that the Republican presidential primary voters he's trying to woo don't understand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=uXYHxL6EKJ8:s08rKxotAAs:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/uXYHxL6EKJ8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Marco Rubio</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256777</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:15:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256777/-Marco-Rubio-s-shiny-new-Obamacare-lie</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cory Booker becomes the 48th senator to publicly support Gillibrand military sexual assault bill</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/T5Mu_UjVmsc/-Cory-Booker-becomes-the-48th-senator-to-publicly-support-Gillibrand-military-sexual-assault-bill</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58219/large/Booker_Reid.jpg?1384874211" alt="Sen. Cory Booker (D-NJ) stands with his mother Carolyn and Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid (D-NV)." width="550" height="366" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Sen. Cory Booker (D-NJ) stands with his mother Carolyn and Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid (D-NV) on the day of his swearing-in.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Sunday, Sen. Kirsten Gillibrand committed to &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/11/kirsten-gillibrand-military-sexual-assault-measure-99956.html"&gt;stay with her original military sexual assault bill&lt;/a&gt;, which gives prosecutors, not commanders, control over prosecution decisions about all major crimes committed by members of the military; last week, she had &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/14/1255589/-Gillibrand-considers-narrowing-military-sexual-assault-bill-to-gain-votes"&gt;floated the idea&lt;/a&gt; of narrowing the bill to only apply to sexual assault. That change was suggested in hopes of picking up the votes of undecided senators, but Gillibrand continued to express confidence that her fight to get 60 votes for the Military Justice Improvement Act would be successful. Monday, the plan picked up the support of the newest senator, raising the number of public supporters to 48:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CoryBooker/status/402599677738381312"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/378800000054714489/1b613bbcf0fb56cca9be197254fe5efb_normal.png" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I’m joining as cosponsor of @SenGillibrand amendment because I believe it offers best protection for survivors of assault&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/CoryBooker"&gt;@CoryBooker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
One of the key questions on the bill's future is whether Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid will decide to support it. Reid has said he will meet with both representatives from the Pentagon and victims before making a final decision; he's also facing tricky &lt;a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/ballot-box/190666-dems-dispute-over-sexual-assault-hems-in-sen-reid"&gt;internal politics&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Nearly three-quarters of Senate Democrats support Gillibrand’s measure, including every female Democratic senator except McCaskill.
&lt;p&gt;But Senate Armed Services Committee Chairman Carl Levin (D-Mich.) and senior members of the committee disagree with her proposed overhaul of the military’s judicial system. Pentagon leaders are also staunchly opposed to the measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Committee leadership usually gets a lot of deference on one side, but then you have clearly a majority of your caucus in opposition to those folks on the other side, so it creates a tough dynamic for him,” a Senate aide working on the issue said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
While the pressures from the Pentagon and from some senior Democrats may push Reid to preserve the status quo, hopefully not only the counter-pressures from the majority of his caucus but the fact that the status quo is an ongoing, damaging failure will persuade him to support real efforts to curb military sexual assault.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=T5Mu_UjVmsc:E5ql_5W5jwA:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/T5Mu_UjVmsc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Cory Booker</category>
<category>Harry Reid</category>
<category>Kirsten Gillibrand</category>
<category>Military</category>
<category>Military Justice Improvement Act</category>
<category>Military Sexual Assault</category>
<category>Sexual Assault</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256698</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 15:20:11 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256698/-Cory-Booker-becomes-the-48th-senator-to-publicly-support-Gillibrand-military-sexual-assault-bill</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Jay-Z/Barney's</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/VrKhr3wQsVo/-Jay-Z-Barney-s</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58204/lightbox/jayzbarneys.png?1384855822"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58204/large/jayzbarneys.png?1384855822" alt="" width="550" height="616" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support indie cartooning! &amp;nbsp;Join &lt;a href="http://www.kchronicles.com/subscribe.html"&gt;the Round Table&lt;/a&gt; and get yer Keef on!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=VrKhr3wQsVo:yiEUQL_1KaI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/VrKhr3wQsVo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (keefknight)</author>
<category>Cartoons</category>
<category>Comics</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256665</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 22:50:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256665/-Jay-Z-Barney-s</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Elizabeth Warren joins expand Social Security team</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/y_cLbfvA7ds/-Elizabeth-Warren-joins-expand-Social-Security-nbsp-team</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/57665/large/RTX15DNH.jpg?1384468303" alt="Senator Elizabeth Warren (D-MA) questions U.S. Federal Reserve Vice Chair Janet Yellen (not pictured) during a Senate Banking Committee confirmation hearing on Yellen's nomination to be the next chairman of the Federal Reserve, on Capitol Hill in Washingt" width="550" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='412' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/427.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If Elizabeth Warren is the new embodiment of the soul of the Democratic Party, as she is increasingly perceived to be following Noam Schreiber's &lt;a href="http://www.newrepublic.com/article/115509/elizabeth-warren-hillary-clintons-nightmare"&gt;lengthy profile&lt;/a&gt; and 2016 speculation, then the fight for strengthening Social Security might have reached a turning point to become, again, a key issue for Democrats.
&lt;p&gt;Warren added her voice, full-throated, to the call for expanding Social Security in a floor speech Monday. In it, she slammed the &lt;i&gt;Washington Post&lt;/i&gt; for an &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/social-security-proposals-are-wrongheaded/2013/11/17/38ebb486-4bde-11e3-ac54-aa84301ced81_story.html"&gt;editorial&lt;/a&gt; published Monday that suggested the upcoming retirement crisis isn't real and that making sure seniors had secure retirements would take food away from children. Warren brought it:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;No retirement crisis? Tell that to the millions of Americans who are facing retirement without a pension. Tell that to the millions of Americans who have nothing to fall back on except Social Security. There is a $6.6 trillion gap between what Americans under 65 are currently saving and what they will need to maintain their current standard of living when they hit retirement. $6.6 trillion—and that assumes Social Security benefits aren’t cut. Make no mistake: This is a crisis.
&lt;p&gt;The call to cut Social Security has an uglier side to it, too. The Washington Post framed the choice as more children in poverty versus more seniors in poverty. The suggestion that we have become a country where those living in poverty fight each other for a handful of crumbs tossed off the tables of the very wealthy is fundamentally wrong. This is about our values, and our values tell us that we don’t build a future by first deciding who among our most vulnerable will be left to starve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
She minced no words for the idea that cutting Social Security is necessary to get a budget deal.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The most recent discussion about cutting benefits has focused on something called the Chained-CPI. Supporters of the chained CPI say that it’s a more accurate way of measuring cost of living increases for seniors. That statement is simply not true. Chained CPI falls short of the actual increases in costs that seniors face, pure and simple. &amp;nbsp;Chained CPI? &amp;nbsp;It’s just a fancy way of saying cut benefits.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
And she rejected it:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The absolute last thing we should do in 2013 – at the very moment that Social Security has become the principal lifeline for millions of our seniors — is allow the program to begin to be dismantled inch by inch. [...] [W]e should be talking about expanding Social Security benefits—not cutting them.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Watch the whole thing here:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;iframe width="550" height="309" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/O99siSbqTX8" frameborder="0" defang_allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Expanding Social Security isn't just a fetish of the far left and our hero, Elizabeth Warren. Sen. Mark Begich (D-AK), a freshman facing re-election in 2014, is a lead sponsor of the Harkin/Begich bill to make Social Security stronger. That's a good indication that this is where Democrats should be on the issue, where they've always been: behind protecting Social Security. It's the mainstream of public opinion, and should be the mainstream opinion of elected Democrats. Maybe Warren jumping enthusiastically on that bandwagon will put it back there.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=y_cLbfvA7ds:1VjD12PXw4Y:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/y_cLbfvA7ds" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Chained CPI</category>
<category>Elizabeth Warren</category>
<category>Retirement</category>
<category>Social Security</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256815</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 21:02:30 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256815/-Elizabeth-Warren-joins-expand-Social-Security-nbsp-team</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>2016 watch: Scott Walker flirts with himself, Rand Paul gets explicit</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/umkwEw49FZQ/-2016-watch-Scott-Walker-flirts-with-himself-Rand-Paul-gets-explicit</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://img.youtube.com/vi/qzaX_d7G59Q/0.jpg' style='display:none;' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='dkimg-c'&gt;&lt;iframe width='550' height='309' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/qzaX_d7G59Q?rel=0&amp;amp;start=840&amp;amp;end=890' frameborder='0' defang_allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker &lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/politics/2013/11/scott-walker-congress-members-need-not-apply-for-2016-presidential-bid/"&gt;describes&lt;/a&gt; his ideal Republican presidential nominee for 2016:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I think it’s got to be an outsider. I think both the presidential and the vice presidential nominee should either be a former or current governor, people who have done successful things in their states, who have taken on big reforms, who are ready to move America forward.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Okay, so Walker didn't literally come right out and say "Me! Me! Me!" but he did come pretty dang close by saying both GOP nominees had to be governors. The obvious responses to that would be "Mitt Romney" and "Sarah Palin," but Sen. Rand Paul of Kentucky didn't go there.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/11/rand-paul-kentucky-2016-presidential-elections-republicans-100025.html"&gt;Instead:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Sen. Rand Paul (R-Ky.) thinks Americans are holding out for a D.C. outsider in 2016; perhaps “someone like myself,” he said Monday.
&lt;p&gt;“I think they want someone outside of, you know, what’s been going on. For example, someone like myself who has been promoting term limits,” he said on Fox News Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And I think I’m, enough, new here to still be perceived as an outsider, should that be the choice at sometime in 2016,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
So Rand's pitch is basically that he's for term limits and that he hasn't had any real impact on what's been going on in D.C., which is kind of lame, but you have to give him points for eschewing Walker's "aw, shucks, me?" routine and coming right out and pointing to himself as the kind of guy he thinks Republican primary voters will want to nominate. And who knows? Maybe we'll get lucky and he'll turn out to be right.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=umkwEw49FZQ:WMD4CS4pydY:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/umkwEw49FZQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>2016</category>
<category>Rand Paul</category>
<category>Scott Walker</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256801</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 22:00:18 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256801/-2016-watch-Scott-Walker-flirts-with-himself-Rand-Paul-gets-explicit</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Politico: Florida Republican Rep. Trey Radel was arrested last month for cocaine possession</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/qqpLWGaehpE/-Politico-Florida-Republican-Rep-Trey-Radel-was-arrested-last-month-for-cocaine-possession</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58309/small/Trey_Radel_113th_Congress.jpg?1384896717" alt="Rep.Trey Radel (FL-R)" width="250" height="306" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Rep. Trey Radel (R-FL)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Well, the headline &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/11/trey-radel-cocaine-possession-100075.html"&gt;pretty much covers it&lt;/a&gt;: Politico reports that freshman GOP Rep. Trey Radel, who represents Florida's 19th Congressional District, was arrested late last month in Washington, D.C. for possession of cocaine. He's due in court tomorrow, but so far, there are no further details about how Radel was nabbed or how much of the white stuff he had on him, though he's apparently been charged with a misdemeanor.
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Radel's seat is solidly Republican—it went for Mitt Romney &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2012/11/19/1163009/-Daily-Kos-Elections-presidential-results-by-congressional-district-for-the-2012-2008-elections?detail=hide"&gt;by a 61-39 margin&lt;/a&gt; last year. But Radel only won his primary with a slim &lt;a href="http://www.ourcampaigns.com/RaceDetail.html?RaceID=736120"&gt;30 percent plurality&lt;/a&gt;, so one of his old opponents or some other ambitious Republican could very well decide to parlay this bit of news into an intra-party challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we can all enjoy watching another hypocritical "family values" conservative stumble over his own nose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=qqpLWGaehpE:Dy8yxw_9XNk:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/qqpLWGaehpE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Nir)</author>
<category>FL-19</category>
<category>Trey Radel</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256825</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 21:38:59 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256825/-Politico-Florida-Republican-Rep-Trey-Radel-was-arrested-last-month-for-cocaine-possession</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Senate Republicans' latest filibuster last straw for Dianne Feinstein</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/4hjFpu9MiZ4/-Senate-Republicans-latest-filibuster-last-straw-for-Dianne-Feinstein</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/28570/large/RTR3AHSZ.jpg?1366301637" alt="U.S. Senate Intelligence Committee chairman Senator Dianne Feinstein (D-CA) REUTERS/Yuri Gripas" width="550" height="371" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;A convert.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
At least some Senate Democrats have had enough after Monday afternoon, when &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/18/1256572/-Filibustered-again"&gt;Republicans filibustered the third&lt;/a&gt; of President Obama's three nominees for the D.C. Circuit court. One Democrat who was previously opposed to rules reform on judicial nominees has &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/feinstein-comes-out-for-filibuster-reform-via-nuclear-option"&gt;changed her mind&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Sen. Dianne Feinstein (D-CA) said Tuesday she supports a rules change for nominees via the nuclear option after "unconscionable" GOP filibusters of three consecutive individuals to D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals.
&lt;p&gt;"I do now," she told TPM in the Capitol. "It is unconscionable for a president not to be able to have his cabinet team, his sub-cabinet team, and not be able to appoint judges."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I've been very shocked by the way very qualified nominees, particularly for the D.C. Circuit, have been filibustered," Feinstein said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Feinstein's California colleague Barbara Boxer &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/07/1253907/-Reid-sets-up-next-move-in-filibuster-fight"&gt;said a few weeks ago&lt;/a&gt; that she was finally open to the idea of reform. That's not as equivocal as Feinstein, but critical movement. It's not just these two: Huffington Post's Jennifer Bendery &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jbendery/status/402861248829984769"&gt;talked to 10 Democratic senators&lt;/a&gt; and among those 10, just one opposes rules reform. Some of those she talked to were previously opposed. Even for slow-to-react senators, they've seen with their own eyes just how bad it's become. Here's the evidence:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58293/large/BZHrDPnCIAA53B-.png?1384889640" alt="Chart showing drastic increase in filibusters of federal judges." width="470" height="330" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
A key to Reid amassing the 51 votes he needs for rules reform on judicial nomination is the Judiciary Committee chair Patrick Leahy, who previously has been cool to the idea. Monday's vote was the end of it for him. It was his &lt;a href="http://takingnote.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/11/19/what-is-harry-reid-waiting-for/"&gt;"tipping point."&lt;/a&gt; Let's hope he and Reid can make it the tipping point for enough of the others.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://campaigns.dailykos.com/p/dia/action3/common/public/?action_KEY=630"&gt;Email your Democratic senator(s). Tell them Republican obstruction of judicial nominees must stop—even if it stopping it requires going nuclear.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="update"&gt;&lt;a name="20131119133640" href="/story/2013/11/19/1256783/-Senate-Republicans-latest-filibuster-last-straw-for-Dianne-Feinstein#20131119133640"&gt;&lt;b&gt;1:36 PM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; It looks like Reid might think he has the votes, now. A senior Democratic Senate aide &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/plum-line/wp/2013/11/19/harry-reid-is-set-to-go-nuclear/"&gt;tells Greg Sargent&lt;/a&gt; he's ready to go on the nuclear option for judicial nominees (excepting Supreme Court nominees), possibly as soon as this week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Reid has become personally invested in the idea that Dems have no choice other than to change the rules if the Senate is going to remain a viable and functioning institution,” the aide says. That’s a long journey from where Reid was only 10 months ago, when he agreed to a toothless filibuster reform deal out of a real reluctance to change the rules by simple majority. Asked to explain the evolution, the aide said: “It’s been a long process. But this is the only thing we can do to keep the Senate performing its basic duties.”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked if Reid would drop the threat to go nuclear if Republicans green-lighted one or two of Obama’s judicial nominations, the aide said: “I don’t think that’s going to fly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Reid thinks Republicans have boxed themselves in to the point where they can't back down at all, and that going nuclear is the only option for Democrats, and that "Reid believes he now has 51 Dem Senators behind a rules change, if it comes down to it."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=4hjFpu9MiZ4:mjydirZCxFQ:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/4hjFpu9MiZ4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>CA-Sen</category>
<category>Dianne Feinstein</category>
<category>Filibuster</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>Robert Wilkins</category>
<category>Senate</category>
<category>U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256783</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 19:37:34 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256783/-Senate-Republicans-latest-filibuster-last-straw-for-Dianne-Feinstein</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>PPP's new Montana poll offers tough news for Democrats trying to hold Senate seat</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/n-Vxo0V9bMM/-PPP-s-new-Montana-poll-offers-tough-news-for-Democrats-trying-to-hold-Senate-seat</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58298/large/Daines.jpg?1384891354" alt="Photo of Steve Daines in front of hay bales in a stable" width="550" height="248" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;GOP Rep. Steve Daines&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
PPP's &lt;a href="http://www.publicpolicypolling.com/main/2013/11/montana-republicans-well-positioned-for-2014.html"&gt;new Montana numbers&lt;/a&gt; contain little but bad news for Democrats. In the state's open Senate race, GOP Rep. Steve Daines, who recently announced his candidacy, leads Lt. Gov. John Walsh 52-35 and former Lt. Gov. John Bohlinger 51-36. And that's despite his newly negative 37-42 job approval rating (he was at 41-33 in June). Barack Obama's approvals, meanwhile, are a brutal 34-63; by contrast, they stood at 44-53 &lt;a href="http://www.publicpolicypolling.com/pdf/2011/PPP_Release_AZMT_1104.pdf#page=11"&gt;a year ago&lt;/a&gt;, just ahead of Democratic Sen. Jon Tester's narrow re-election victory. If that doesn't change, it'll be very hard to stop Daines, given that he's already over 50.
&lt;p&gt;And while conservatives have grumbled over Daines' vote to end the government shutdown in October, he blows away state Rep. Champ Edmunds 66-7 in a hypothetical primary. Democrats, meanwhile, have a much closer race, as Walsh has a 39-31 lead over Bohlinger. Interestingly, Walsh does better with more liberal voters, even though Bohlinger is running a classic "outsider" campaign; however, Bohlinger used to be a Republican, so that might explain the gap (and in any event, the sub-group samples are very small).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the picture for Daines' now-open House seat isn't much better. Democrats have been hyping former congressional aide John Lewis, but he trails every Republican PPP tested. Former state Sen. Corey Stapleton leads 44-31; former Secretary of State Brad Johnson is up 43-32; and state Sen. Matt Rosendale and former state Sen. Ryan Zinke are both ahead 37-32. All of these candidates are unknown, so Lewis' deficit can't be ascribed merely to lack of name recognition. For what it's worth, though, Stapleton has an early lead in the GOP primary, taking 32 percent to Johnson's 20, with Zinke and Rosendale at 9 apiece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the usual caveats of "just one poll" and "it's still early" apply, as ever. But if Republicans finally end their lengthy streak of losing in Montana, will anyone really be surprised? It's &lt;i&gt;Montana&lt;/i&gt;, after all, a state Mitt Romney carried by over 13 points. Democrats should consider themselves very fortunate to have done this well in a state this red for this long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=n-Vxo0V9bMM:lcBSB826MKo:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/n-Vxo0V9bMM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Nir)</author>
<category>Brad Johnson</category>
<category>Champ Edmunds</category>
<category>Corey Stapleton</category>
<category>John Bohlinger</category>
<category>John Lewis</category>
<category>John Walsh</category>
<category>Matt Rosendale</category>
<category>MT-AL</category>
<category>MT-Sen</category>
<category>Ryan Zinke</category>
<category>Steve Daines</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256791</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 20:05:58 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256791/-PPP-s-new-Montana-poll-offers-tough-news-for-Democrats-trying-to-hold-Senate-seat</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Military Justice Improvement Act gains momentum in the Senate as poll shows public support</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/gHJWSyDZF7Q/-Military-Justice-Improvement-Act-gains-momentum-in-the-Senate-as-poll-shows-public-support</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/51238/large/Sailors_wear_the_Navy_working_uniform_(NWU)_at_Naval_Air_Station_Oceana.jpg?1380647060" alt="Group of Navy people." width="550" height="366" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;They all deserve protection.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Sen. Kirsten Gillibrand's Military Justice Improvement Act continued picking up momentum Tuesday morning; after Democratic Sen. Cory Booker &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256698/-Cory-Booker-becomes-the-48th-senator-to-publicly-support-Gillibrand-military-sexual-assault-bill"&gt;said Monday night&lt;/a&gt; he was co-sponsoring the plan, Republican Sen. Dean Heller &lt;a href="http://feministing.com/2013/11/19/breaking-cory-booker-dean-heller-join-the-fight-against-sexual-assault-in-the-military/"&gt;said Tuesday morning&lt;/a&gt; that he would support the amendment. What's more, a new poll finds &lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/politics/2013/11/most-favor-independent-prosecutors-in-military-sexual-assault-cases/"&gt;solid public support&lt;/a&gt; for putting prosecutors in charge of prosecution decisions when it comes to major crimes like sexual assault:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;With a vote on the issue pending in the Senate, 59 percent in a new ABC News/Washington Post poll favor the proposed change. Thirty-six percent instead prefer to keep authority over sexual assault cases within the usual channels.
&lt;p&gt;Support for the change includes equal numbers of women and men, albeit more married women than single women, 65 vs. 53 percent. It’s backed across the political spectrum, but by more Democrats and independents (about six in 10 in both cases), than Republicans (53 percent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
At a press conference Tuesday morning, a group of senators released a letter of support from 26 retired generals, admirals, commanders, colonels, captains and senior enlisted personnel, and:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“As a former commander, endorsing a change that removes certain authority from military commanders has been a tough decision,” said Major General (Ret.) Martha Rainville. “It was driven by my conviction that our men and women in uniform deserve to know, without doubt, that they are valued and will be treated fairly with all due process should they report an offense and seek help, or face being accused of an offense. When allegations of serious criminal misconduct have been made, the decision whether to prosecute should be made by a trained legal professional. Fairness and justice require sound judgment based on evidence and facts, independent of pre-existing command relationships.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.endsexualassault.com/?code=dailykos"&gt;Tell Congress to protect victims of military sexual assault by supporting the Military Justice Improvement Act.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="update"&gt;&lt;a name="20131119115404" href="/story/2013/11/19/1256762/-Military-Justice-Improvement-Act-gains-momentum-in-the-Senate-as-poll-shows-public-support#20131119115404"&gt;&lt;b&gt;11:54 AM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Definitely momentum—the plan picks up another, rather important, Senate supporter:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SenatorReid/status/402885932279296001"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/81906216/reid_square_normal.jpg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I'm going to support @SenGillibrand's important amendment to combat the problem of sexual assault in the military.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/SenatorReid"&gt;@SenatorReid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Reid makes the 50th public supporter.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=gHJWSyDZF7Q:2lfLzZTZnN4:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/gHJWSyDZF7Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Cory Booker</category>
<category>Dean Heller</category>
<category>Kirsten Gillibrand</category>
<category>Military</category>
<category>Military Justice Improvement Act</category>
<category>Military Sexual Assault</category>
<category>Sexual Assault</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256762</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 18:36:44 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256762/-Military-Justice-Improvement-Act-gains-momentum-in-the-Senate-as-poll-shows-public-support</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Midday open thread: Gettysburg, boxers, Jesus and gay 'cures'</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/hqlxnyc-qmg/-Midday-open-thread-Gettysburg-boxers-Jesus-and-gay-cures</link>
<description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today's &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/blog/comics"&gt;comic&lt;/a&gt; by Jen Sorensen is &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256487/-Hell-bent-for-healthcare?detail=hide"&gt;Hell bent for healthcare&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256487/-Hell-bent-for-healthcare?detail=hide"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58207/large/hygieiaPANEL.png?1384863849" alt="Cartoon by Jen Sorensen - Hellbent for healthcare" width="314" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On this day in 1863, 150 years ago today, President Abraham Lincoln delivered The Gettysburg Address:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Four score and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.
&lt;p&gt;Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation, or any nation so conceived and dedicated, can long endure. We are met on a great battle-field of that war. We have come to dedicate a portion of that field, as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live. It is altogether fitting and proper that we should do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, in a larger sense, we can not dedicate -- we can not consecrate -- we can not hallow -- this ground. The brave men, living and dead, who struggled here, have consecrated it, far above our poor power to add or detract. The world will little note, nor long remember what we say here, but it can never forget what they did here. It is for us the living, rather, to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they who fought here have thus far so nobly advanced. It is rather for us to be here dedicated to the great task remaining before us -- that from these honored dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of devotion -- that we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain -- that this nation, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom -- and that government of the people, by the people, for the people, shall not perish from the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And in related news, in case you missed it, a local newspaper has &lt;a href="http://www.pennlive.com/opinion/index.ssf/2013/11/a_patriot-news_editorial_retraction_the_gettysburg_address.html"&gt;retracted&lt;/a&gt; an editorial from 1863 that panned the Gettysburg Address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the Department of &lt;a href="http://americablog.com/2013/11/air-force-academy-ex-gay-cure-advocate-overseeing-cadet-counseling.html"&gt;WTF&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The US Air Force Academy hired a man to run their counseling program for young cadets who, for the past two decades, has devoted his entire professional career to the cause of “curing homosexuality,” and who claims that he himself has been “cured” of the “addiction.”
&lt;p&gt;The news of “ex-gay” activist Dr. Mike Rosebush running the academy’s counseling program comes on the heels of growing concerns as to whether the academy is serious about becoming a welcoming place for gay cadets in the post-”Don’t Ask, Don’t Tell” era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you didn't know it, Jesus was a &lt;a href="http://wonkette.com/534572/absolutely-super-straight-wingnut-jesus-wasnt-no-girly-man-jesus-had-a-ripped-buff-bod"&gt;macho, macho man&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Jerry Boykin is on a mission to rescue Jesus from those faggy Eye-Talian artists that painted him as some kind of wimpy homo ladyboy. The retired lieutenant-general, now executive VP of the Family Research Council, told a Men’s Prayer Breakfast at William Jessup University that we’ve got to stop thinking of Jesus as a skinny little guy with long pretty hair and start getting it right. Remember, the man was a carpenter:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Do you think he looked like the effeminate picture that we always see of him?” Boykin asked. “He didn’t look like that. He had big ole calluses over his hands, right? I imagine he probably lost a nail or two, he probably hit it with a hammer or something.”
&lt;p&gt;“You think his biceps weren’t big bulging biceps, big ole veins popping out of his arms, thin waist, strong shoulders from lifting?” he continued. “He smelled bad! Why? Because he sweated, he worked. You think I’m sacrilegious because I said Jesus smelled bad? No, he was a man! He was a man’s man.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He was a tough guy, and that’s the Jesus I want to be like,” he insisted. “But we feminize Jesus in the church and men can’t identify with him anymore, not the kind of men I want to hang out with. They can’t identify with this effeminate Jesus that we’ve tried to portray.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disgusting or funny? You &lt;a href="http://www.theblaze.com/stories/2013/11/19/brash-ugly-and-disgustingly-uncaring-kmarts-joe-boxer-christmas-ad-ignites-controversy/"&gt;make the call&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone needs to gag &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/politics/rob-ford-toronto-lucky-terrorists-binges-article-1.1521609#ixzz2l68kg0wy"&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Toronto Mayor Rob Ford admits it's only a matter of good luck that terrorists haven't targeted the town when he was off on a binge-filled bender.
&lt;p&gt;Ford said the 2.7 million people of Toronto are "very fortunate" that he hasn't been severely intoxicated at important times for the town but insisted that his drunken binges don't occur every weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-r"&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2558402/height/200/width/250/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="200" width="250" scrolling="no" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
On &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256788/-Daily-Kos-Radio-s-KITM-podcast-ACA-roundup-pension-pirates-want-Soc-Sec-cuts-WalMart-double-dip"&gt;today's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show&lt;/a&gt;, new polling fans Obamacare flames, and Gettysburg outrage is manufactured. &lt;strong&gt;Greg Dworkin&lt;/strong&gt; rounds up headlines, the surge in ACA enrollment, hyperbolic declarations of the end of Dem presidencies, and Jonathan Cohn's "Six Things the Media Doesn't Understand About Obamacare." Surprise! The Institute for Policy Studies says the people pushing to cut your Social Security are super rich and don't need Social Security. One of those people: the CEO of WalMart, where workers are now holding food drives for their fellow low-paid workers! Speaking of WalMart: GunFAIL! And Norway joins the parade of allies discovering NSA prying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=hqlxnyc-qmg:qwA3yxvC_ig:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/hqlxnyc-qmg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Barbara Morrill)</author>
<category>Open Thread</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256674</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 20:04:54 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256674/-Midday-open-thread-Gettysburg-boxers-Jesus-and-gay-cures</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Gettysburg Address 'outrage' provides handy checklist of stupidest people in America</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/cndWWR-75KA/-Gettysburg-Address-outrage-provides-handy-checklist-of-stupidest-people-in-America</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58283/large/FoxGettysburg.jpg?1384887362" alt="Fox News video, caption: 'Gettysburg Snub: President Obama to skip 150th Anniversary'" width="550" height="302" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;You're kidding, right?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The anniversary of the Gettysburg Address does not seem at first glance to be a subject steeped in controversy, but that is because you are not a dull-minded hack whose quest for new controversies must never fall below the speed of 50 miles per hour, &lt;a href="http://www.nationaljournal.com/white-house/obama-snubs-150th-anniversary-of-gettysburg-address-20131119"&gt;lest the whole movement die&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obama Snubs 150th Anniversary of Gettysburg Address&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I'm going to spare you the actual article under that headline. I first saw the premise being propped up yesterday as a prospective "scandal" when it slithered past in a Twitter stream via the apparently-still-around Breitbart conspiracy site. I did not think much of it, because I am not a shit-for-brains, but apparently I misunderestimated just how obsessively Actual Conservative Pundits troll the conspiracy sites for fodder. &lt;em&gt;Fox &amp;amp; Friends&lt;/em&gt; took it up this morning, and if that isn't ironclad proof that the story passes nicely under the you-must-be-this-stupid-to-enter bar than &lt;a href="http://mediamatters.org/blog/2013/11/19/foxs-obama-derangement-syndrome-gettysburg-edit/196967"&gt;nothing is&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Fox News's Brian Kilmeade discussed with Wall Street Journal columnist Daniel Henninger whether it is "inappropriate for our president to bypass" the commemoration ceremony of the 150th anniversary of the Gettysburg Address during the November 19 edition of Fox &amp;amp; Friends. At one point Kilmeade asked whether Henninger thought Obama was refusing to attend because "after that address and after the Civil War we still weren't a perfect union? We still had to wait for the Civil Rights Act and so many -- the integration of schools, Brown vs. the Board of Education?" Henninger replied, "I think probably that President Obama does think the unfinished business remains unfinished in bringing the country and its races together."&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Christ, people. Just ... Christ.
&lt;p&gt;More on the "outrage" below the fold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=cndWWR-75KA:UQ8evIBXwNI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/cndWWR-75KA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Hunter)</author>
<category>Barack Obama</category>
<category>Conservative Conspiracy Theories</category>
<category>Conservatives</category>
<category>Fox and Friends</category>
<category>Fox News</category>
<category>Gettysburg Address</category>
<category>Meida</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<category>White House</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256769</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 19:00:44 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256769/-Gettysburg-Address-outrage-provides-handy-checklist-of-stupidest-people-in-America</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Obamacare enrollments surging, HealthCare.gov working better</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/3ZnedV_2HNA/-Obamacare-enrollments-surging-HealthCare-gov-working-better</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/51323/large/obaMAcare.jpg?1380677375" alt="Banner from HealthCare.gov exchange portal." width="550" height="297" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
This should be the day's leading Obamacare news: enrollements across the country are surging, &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/nation/la-na-obamacare-increase-20131119,0,6486939.story#axzz2l5OXuHTS"&gt;coming in ahead of projections&lt;/a&gt; in states across the country.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"What we are seeing is incredible momentum," said Peter Lee, director of Covered California, the nation's largest state insurance marketplace, which accounted for a third of all enrollments nationally in October. California—which enrolled about 31,000 people in health plans last month—nearly doubled that in the first two weeks of this month.
&lt;p&gt;Several other states, including Connecticut and Kentucky, are outpacing their enrollment estimates, even as states that depend on the federal website lag far behind. In Minnesota, enrollment in the second half of October ran at triple the rate of the first half, officials said. Washington state is also on track to easily exceed its October enrollment figure, officials said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Enrollments are moving at a faster clip than during October in these, despite the fact that some people are confused by the problems the federal site has had, not sure if the sites in their own states are working. Covered California's director said that the state has had to change its marketing to remind people that the state site wasn't the same as the federal site, and was working just fine.
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, so far enrollments on the federal site are still lagging. For example, just &amp;nbsp;2,991 people in Texas were able to complete enrollment in October, fewer than Kentucky, which has a sixth of Texas' population. But there's better news on the federal site front today, as well. HealthCare.gov is now &lt;a href="http://www.11alive.com/news/article/313439/40/HealthCaregov-now-working-for-90-percent-of-users"&gt;working for 90 percent of users&lt;/a&gt; who have tried again to sign up. The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services updated reporters Monday with the news that the site was functioning better, and that it had sent out 275,000 emails to people who had started to create accounts, but couldn't get through the process. CMS says that 90 percent of those people who tried again got all the way through the process. So far in November, &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/19/us/politics/administration-open-to-direct-insurance-company-signups.html?hp&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;"&gt;50,000 people have selected a plan&lt;/a&gt; in the federal site, up from 27,000 for the entire month of October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people are likely still in window-shopping mode, and enrollments should pick up even more—both on the state sites and the federal site—in the last week or two before the December 15 deadline for insurance to be in place on January 1, and then again in February and March before the final deadline. The &lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/health/2013/11/12/2923931/obamacare-enrollment-going-better-think/"&gt;Massachusetts experience&lt;/a&gt; provides the best model for enrollment patterns, and in the first four months of enrollment just about one-fifth of the uninsured population enrolled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people will come. They're not freaked out over what most people perceive as inevitable: a problematic new government program. They're not &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256712/-Reuters-Ipsos-poll-No-big-drop-in-Obamacare-nbsp-support"&gt;abandoning support&lt;/a&gt; for the program in droves. They're not calling for an end to the program. They're patient enough to give it time to work, even if Republicans and the traditional media are not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=3ZnedV_2HNA:J2ipRVMwtCE:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/3ZnedV_2HNA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Health Insurance</category>
<category>Health Insurance Reform</category>
<category>Healthcare.gov</category>
<category>Recommended</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256749</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 17:32:56 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256749/-Obamacare-enrollments-surging-HealthCare-gov-working-better</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Republicans love Batkid, but they don't want him to have health care coverage</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/NTQdH1ikL_4/-Republicans-love-Batkid-but-want-to-let-insurers-refuse-to-provide-him-health-coverage</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58257/large/RTX15FD0.jpg?1384883111" alt="Five-year-old leukemia survivor Miles dressed as " defang_and="" defang_man="" defang_dressed="" defang_batman="" defang_are="" defang_escorted="" defang_police="" defang_officers="" defang_back="" defang_their="" defang_batmobile="" defang_after="" defang_they="" defang_apprehended="" defang_as="" defang_part="" defang_of="" defang_day="" defang_arranged="" defang_by="" defang_make-a-wish="" defang_foundation="" defang_in="" defang_california="" defang_november="" defang_the="" defang_young="" defang_cancer="" defang_survivor="" defang_will="" defang_be="" defang_treated="" defang_to="" defang_various="" defang_super="" defang_hero="" defang_scenarios="" defang_including="" defang_receiving="" defang_a="" defang_commendation="" defang_at="" defang_san="" defang_francisco="" defang_city="" defang_hall.="" defang_lam="" defang_states="" defang_tags:="" width="550" height="370" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Last week, much of America fell in love with Batkid, otherwise known as five-year-old leukemia survivor Miles Scott. Congressional Republicans were among those joining in the giant collective "awwww," yet, as &lt;i&gt;Rolling Stone&lt;/i&gt;'s Tim Dickinson &lt;a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/news/10-republicans-who-cheered-on-batkid-want-to-revoke-his-obamacare-20131116"&gt;points out&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Ironically, these same elected officials—in particular Senator Ted Cruz and House Majority Leader Eric Cantor—have been crusading for Obamacare's repeal, which would again make it legal for insurers to deny coverage to children like Batkid with preexisting conditions.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Before insurers were prohibited from denying coverage to kids with pre-existing conditions, it was common for them to &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2010/09/23/904515/-Republicans-want-to-take-away-your-health-care"&gt;do just that&lt;/a&gt;. Not only that, treatment for a disease like leukemia could have taken a child to a lifetime insurance cap—caps that have now been lifted by Obamacare. Those facts are a particularly poignant and outrageous contrast with the support Republicans expressed for Batkid.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SenTedCruz/statuses/401440363128172544"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/3396959978/e4a57f152c58effe0df43affb2e27ab8_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A heartwarming story of a community coming together to help make a 5-year-old’s superhero dreams come true &lt;a href="http://t.co/9KiHecCACj"&gt;http://t.co/...&lt;/a&gt; #SFBatKid&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/SenTedCruz"&gt;@SenTedCruz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Cruz, of course, SHUT DOWN THE GOVERNMENT to repeal Obamacare.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style="margin:18px auto; width:470px; font-size:12px;background-color: #eeeeee; border: 1px solid #999999;padding:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/repjustinamash/statuses/401437573173620736"&gt;&lt;img src="http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/378800000007276497/914fe6aab7e927ed37e55ad95760b38a_normal.jpeg" style="float:left;padding:0px;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; width:48px; height:48px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Thank you, #SFBatKid, for saving Gotham! You're the hero Gotham needs right now. @SFWish&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#555555;font-style:italic;"&gt;— &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/repjustinamash"&gt;@repjustinamash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Amash has &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/08/19/1232304/-Rep-Justin-Amash-That-pre-existing-condition-ban-wasn-t-so-bad"&gt;specifically said&lt;/a&gt; it doesn't matter so much if insurance companies can reject people for pre-existing conditions, because some insurance plans won't do that.
&lt;p&gt;Eric Cantor, Darrell Issa ... there's a substantial list of those cheering Batkid despite their long records of trying to repeal the bill that protects health coverage for kids like him. So disgusting, and so typical of their party.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=NTQdH1ikL_4:N-XZOeFC5ig:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/NTQdH1ikL_4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Batkid</category>
<category>Darrell Issa</category>
<category>Eric Cantor</category>
<category>Justin Amash</category>
<category>Ted Cruz</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256738</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 17:47:15 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256738/-Republicans-love-Batkid-but-want-to-let-insurers-refuse-to-provide-him-health-coverage</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Food stamps cuts hit food banks hard just in time for Thanksgiving</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/UIjA2xb48Zo/-Food-stamps-cuts-hit-food-banks-hard-just-in-time-for-Thanksgiving</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58084/large/food_bank_2.jpg?1384793602" alt="A box of food for a Family size of 4, given out through the Food Pantry at the Community Center of St Bernard." width="550" height="365" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe width='275' height='353' src='https://www.dailykos.com/campaigns/544.embed' style='box-shadow: 0px 3px 10px 6px #EBEBEB;margin: 0px 15px 10px 15px;float:right;' defang_overflow="false" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thanksgiving is coming up just as the effects of a recent food stamp reduction hit struggling families hard. Benefits were cut on November 1, which means people are running out of food even earlier in the month than they did previously. And that means they're turning to food pantries, which are doing everything they can to help but won't be able to make up the difference. In &lt;a href="http://chronicle.augusta.com/news/metro/2013-11-16/food-pantries-see-increase-requests-after-cuts-supplemental-nutrition?v=1384653101"&gt;Augusta, Georgia,&lt;/a&gt; for instance:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“We are beginning to hear from our pantries that they are beginning to see an increase in the number of families and individuals they are seeing each week and month,” said Travis McNeal, the executive director of Golden Harvest Food Bank.
&lt;p&gt;Golden Harvest serves more than 300 food pantries, churches and social service agencies in 30 counties in Georgia and South Carolina. In the 19 Georgia counties it serves, the food stamps cuts amount to $15.9 million, McNeal said. Richmond County food stamp recipients lost $6.8 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Downtown Cooperative Church Ministries, a mission of several local churches, will try to apply for more grant money to make up for the extra food supplies needed, said director Christy Cunningham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
In &lt;a href="http://www.abqjournal.com/302819/news/food-stamp-cuts-mean-more-in-need-at-pantries.html"&gt;Santa Fe, New Mexico,&lt;/a&gt; where one food pantry has already served 11.5 percent more households than at this time last year:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Even as greater demand is anticipated, Santa Fe’s biggest food pantry, Food for Santa Fe, has had to reduce the bags of groceries it distributes at 1222 Siler Road from 900 to 600 per week, according to Susan Odiseos, board president. That cutback occurred in mid-September to keep the program from operating in the red—a situation that develops partly due to the fact that the bulk of monetary donations come in November and December, she noted.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
In &lt;a href="http://www.dnainfo.com/new-york/20131118/east-harlem/rush-on-food-pantries-as-food-stamp-benefits-are-cut/page/2#image"&gt;New York City&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"There's a whole lot of struggling going on," said Mary, who waited in line for her turn at the food pantry housed in the Beulah Church of the Nazarene. Mary receives food stamps, which have been cut recently. "They cut my food stamps. How do they expect us to make it when we don't get food stamps?"&lt;/blockquote&gt;
According to Bradley Backus, the food pantry's director, "The cut in SNAP benefits has had a tremendous impact." Meanwhile, the House and Senate are &lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-18/food-stamp-costs-swelled-by-states-spending-1-for-heat.html"&gt;trying to agree&lt;/a&gt; on how much to cut from the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program, with proposals on the table that could kick &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/09/17/1239453/-CBO-3-8-million-would-lose-food-stamps-in-2014-under-House-cuts"&gt;millions of people&lt;/a&gt; out of the program altogether. Happy Thanksgiving!&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=UIjA2xb48Zo:nMLNxDdJirI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/UIjA2xb48Zo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Food banks</category>
<category>food pantries</category>
<category>Food Stamps</category>
<category>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256446</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 16:54:47 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/18/1256446/-Food-stamps-cuts-hit-food-banks-hard-just-in-time-for-Thanksgiving</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Cheney is right on marriage equality</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/HtdYw9JQoWE/-Cheney-is-right-on-marriage-equality</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/40687/large/RTRL2NM.jpg?1374072182" alt="U.S. Vice president Dick Cheney (L) takes the oath for his second term in office from House Speaker Dennis Hastert (R) at inaugural ceremonies in Washington D.C. on January 20, 2005. Cheney&amp;amp;#x27;s daughters Mary (2nd L) and Liz (2nd R) watched. REUTERS/Jason R" width="550" height="382" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Dick, Mary, and Liz in 2005.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
No, not that Cheney. (Points to Liz, on the right.)
&lt;p&gt;Nor that one. (Points to Dick, on the left.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That one. (Points to Mary, on the middle.) &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/19/us/politics/in-cheneys-gay-marriage-feud-parents-defend-liz.html?partner=rss&amp;amp;emc=rss&amp;amp;smid=tw-nytimes&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;She's right:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Mary Cheney has kept up her advocacy on her Facebook page, responding sharply to one commenter on the page who urged her to be “lovingly tolerant” of her sister’s position on same-sex marriage.
&lt;p&gt;“This isn’t like a disagreement over grazing fees or what to do about Iran,” Mary Cheney wrote. “There isn’t a lot of gray here. Either you think all families should be treated equally or you don’t. Liz’s position is to treat my family as second class citizens. That’s not a position I can be ’lovingly tolerant’ towards.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I'll admit that when I saw this "spat" &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/18/1256424/-The-2014-House-Republican-agenda-revealed-A-blank-piece-of-paper"&gt;take center stage&lt;/a&gt;, my first reaction was that Liz, Mary, and their families were engaged in an epic act of trolling on the issue in order to shore up Liz's support among social conservatives, because of things &lt;a href="http://www.denverpost.com/politics/ci_24553004/theres-more-than-gossip-behind-cheney-familys-clash"&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;In Wyoming, a conservative super PAC called American Principles Fund ran a television ad for three weeks this fall noting that Cheney is opposed to a federal constitutional amendment banning gay marriage.
&lt;p&gt;“This is a huge issue for Republican primary voters and it will carry over to the general election,” said the group's executive director, Sarah Huckabee Sanders, who is the daughter of former Arkansas Governor Mike Huckabee. “Jobs and economy and spending are still the most important, but a candidate's position on social issues such a life and marriage sends an extremely strong message about their values. That's why taking the wrong side could be fatal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Obviously, it would take a breathtaking act of cynicism to fake this fight just to highlight Liz's archaic point of view, but if there's any family capable of such cynicism, clearly it would be the Cheneys. But at this point, it seems like any benefit Liz might get from having her her anti-equality stance amplified is being outweighed by the nastiness of the intrafamily feud, which makes me lean back to the simpler explanation: That this is a genuine disagreement, and that Liz Cheney sincerely believes her sister should not be treated equally under the law.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=HtdYw9JQoWE:9mmZmXc2gWo:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/HtdYw9JQoWE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jed Lewison)</author>
<category>Equality</category>
<category>Liz Cheney</category>
<category>Mary Cheney</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256711</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 16:40:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256711/-Cheney-is-right-on-marriage-equality</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Sorry, Republicans: No big drop in Obamacare support</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/76jMUAKyzD0/-Reuters-Ipsos-poll-No-big-drop-in-Obamacare-nbsp-support</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/54501/large/RTR3FHI4.jpg?1382628213" alt="U.S. President Barack Obama delivers remarks alongside Human Services Secretary Kathleen Sebelius (R) and other Americans the White House says will benefit from the opening of health insurance marketplaces under the Affordable Care Act, in the Rose Garden" width="550" height="367" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Despite the bad website roll-out, despite the controversy over the small percentage of the population getting a huge proportion of media attention for losing their current policies, despite the hyperactive media equating all this to Katrina, the American people &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/11/18/us-usa-healthcare-poll-idUSBRE9AH18U20131118"&gt;are not abandoning support for Obamacare in any significant numbers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Forty-one percent of Americans expressed support for the 2010 law popularly known as Obamacare in a survey conducted from Thursday to Monday. That was down 3 percentage points from a Reuters/Ipsos poll taken from September 27 to October 1.
&lt;p&gt;Opposition to the healthcare law stood at 59 percent in the latest poll, versus 56 percent in the earlier survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been some shift ... but the shift has been small," said Ipsos pollster Chris Jackson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
That's pretty much where numbers have been for years. People have made up their minds about the law and are sticking with their opinions. Reuters/Ipsos didn't directly ask about repeal, but 65 percent of respondents said they'd support some changes to the law. They also found that some "elements of the law, such as requiring insurance companies to cover people with pre-existing conditions, remain popular," making repeal—still—politically problematic for Republicans.
&lt;p&gt;Another poll released today, from &amp;nbsp;United Technologies/National Journal Congressional Connection Poll, finds that &lt;a href="http://www.nationaljournal.com/congressional-connection/coverage/poll-most-americans-oppose-obamacare-repeal-despite-rollout-troubles-20131118"&gt;most Americans do oppose repeal&lt;/a&gt;, essentially the same numbers as they polled during the summer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Thirty-eight percent of those polled said Congress should "repeal the law so it is not implemented at all," while 35 percent said lawmakers should "wait and see how things go before making any changes." Another 23 percent said Congress should "provide more money to ensure it is implemented effectively" (the remaining 5 percent had no opinion).&lt;/blockquote&gt;
That's 58 percent of the public wanting Obamacare to have a chance to work. Back in July, the same poll found that 36 percent supported repeal, 30 percent wanted to give it time, and 27 percent said it should have more funding for implementation. That's where the public is, no matter how much the Republicans and the traditional media want to make them panic.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=76jMUAKyzD0:xRmJ3wJgqzw:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/76jMUAKyzD0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Joan McCarter)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Health Insurance</category>
<category>Health Insurance Reform</category>
<category>Polling</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256712</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 15:34:50 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256712/-Reuters-Ipsos-poll-No-big-drop-in-Obamacare-nbsp-support</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Virginia state Sen. Creigh Deeds in critical condition after stabbing</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/z3Al_RpeUIg/-Virginia-state-Sen-Creigh-Deeds-in-critical-condition-after-stabbing</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58222/large/RTXQ2KZ.jpg?1384874581" alt="Virginia gubernatorial candidate Creigh Deeds speaks at a rally at Old Dominion University in Norfolk, Virginia, October 27, 2009. &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;REUTERS/Jim Young &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;(UNITED STATES POLITICS) - RTXQ2KZ" width="550" height="376" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Creigh Deeds&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Little information is available, but Virginia state senator and former Democratic gubernatorial nominee &lt;a href="http://www.timesdispatch.com/news/state-regional/government-politics/deeds-critically-wounded-son-dead-from-gunshot/article_431e61ca-5128-11e3-944a-001a4bcf6878.html"&gt;Creigh Deeds is hospitalized&lt;/a&gt; after a stabbing at his home:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Sen. Creigh Deeds, D-Bath, is in critical condition after being stabbed in his home and his son Gus is dead from a gunshot wound, law enforcement sources told the Richmond Times-Dispatch this morning.
&lt;p&gt;Deeds is being treated at the University of Virginia Medical Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authorities said they are trying to determine the sequence of events at the Deeds home in Bath County early today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Condolences to his family and best wishes for his recovery.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="update"&gt;&lt;a name="20131119080052" href="/story/2013/11/19/1256706/-Virginia-state-Sen-Creigh-Deeds-in-critical-condition-after-stabbing#20131119080052"&gt;&lt;b&gt; 8:00 AM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Take it with the usual grain of salt applied to early reports on terrible events, &lt;a href="http://www.nbcwashington.com/news/local/Senator-Creigh-Deeds-Assaulted-in-Bath-County-Home--232498761.html"&gt;but&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Virginia State Senator Creigh Deeds was stabbed by his son, Austin "Gus" Deeds before the son fatally shot himself, Democratic sources tell News4.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=z3Al_RpeUIg:MuhP-n1Ey0k:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/z3Al_RpeUIg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Laura Clawson)</author>
<category>Creigh Deeds</category>
<category>Virginia</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256706</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 15:26:45 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256706/-Virginia-state-Sen-Creigh-Deeds-in-critical-condition-after-stabbing</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Hell bent for healthcare</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/4fl4fkQTHJI/-Hell-bent-for-healthcare</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="lightbox" href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58107/lightbox/hygieia720.png?1384801696"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/58107/large/hygieia720.png?1384801696" alt="" width="550" height="558" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Click to enlarge)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize I'm mixing cosmologies here, and that it should really read "Hades bent for healthcare," but that didn't quite have the same ring. Seriously, though, I can't understand the logic of scrapping an entire program that will probably save countless lives just because the rollout was bad. Am I upset about the website not working? Yes. But mainly because it is a tremendous political blunder that reinforces opponents' "train wreck" narrative, which was going to happen whether the website worked or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get a &lt;a href="http://jensorensen.com/store/" target="_blank"&gt;signed print&lt;/a&gt; of this cartoon from the artist. Follow Jen on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jensorensen" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=4fl4fkQTHJI:r-MY-6kwEq4:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/4fl4fkQTHJI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (Jen Sorensen)</author>
<category>Affordable Care Act</category>
<category>Cartoons</category>
<category>Comics</category>
<category>Health Care</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256487</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 14:50:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256487/-Hell-bent-for-healthcare</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Daily Kos Elections Morning Digest: Attacked from right and left, Fletcher may miss San Diego runoff</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/UWxJ_9HyJVs/-Daily-Kos-Elections-Morning-Digest-Attacked-from-right-and-left-Fletcher-may-miss-San-Diego-runoff</link>
<description>&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;a href="http://campaigns.dailykos.com/signup_page/electionsdigest"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images1.dailykos.com/i/user/73/Elections-MorningDigest.jpg" alt="Daily Kos Elections Morning Digest banner" height="100" width="550" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-cap"&gt;Want the scoop on hot races around the country? Get the digest emailed to you each weekday morning. &lt;a href="http://campaigns.dailykos.com/signup_page/electionsdigest"&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Leading Off&lt;/b&gt;:
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#1" id="1" name="1"&gt;•&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;SD Mayor&lt;/b&gt;: I was initially very skeptical of SurveyUSA's last poll of the San Diego special election for mayor that's taking place on Tuesday. The numbers showed a hard-to-believe surge for Republican Kevin Faulconer and a comparable decline for Democratic frontrunner Nathan Fletcher, but now SUSA's &lt;a href="http://www.surveyusa.com/client/PollReport.aspx?g=1e1beef1-79eb-4613-bd3b-c3ae28a45f09"&gt;newest poll&lt;/a&gt; keeps heading even further in that direction. Faulconer now takes 40 percent, with Fletcher at 24—just a step ahead of fellow Democrat David Alvarez, who's at 22. Two weeks ago, Faulconer was at 41, but Fletcher at least had a 28-17 edge on Alvarez. (Assuming Faulconer can't crack 50 percent, the top two vote-getters will advance to a runoff, likely in February.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if these polls are accurate, what's going on here? Faulconer, preferring to face Alvarez in the second round, &lt;a href="http://www.utsandiego.com/news/2013/nov/17/tp-poll-faulconer-leads-tight-race-for-second/all/?print"&gt;has gone negative&lt;/a&gt; on Fletcher, attacking him over his attendance record in the Assembly, where he used to serve. The labor unions backing Alvarez, meanwhile, &lt;a href="http://www.utsandiego.com/news/2013/nov/16/following-the-money-trail/all/?print"&gt;have hammered Fletcher&lt;/a&gt;—who in the last two years went from Republican to independent to Democrat—as an "opportunist." Both sides &lt;a href="http://www.utsandiego.com/news/2013/nov/16/following-the-money-trail/all/?print"&gt;have spent heavily&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The middle, it turns out, is not a comfortable place to be, so despite coming into the race with strong name recognition thanks to his third-place finish in the mayoral primary last year, Fletcher is getting squeezed from the left and right. And it may wind up allowing Alvarez to serve as the Democratic standard-bearer in the runoff. We'll find out tonight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=UWxJ_9HyJVs:4j9z8iNtdDI:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/UWxJ_9HyJVs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Nir)</author>
<category>Alan Webber</category>
<category>Andrew Cuomo</category>
<category>Anthony Brown</category>
<category>Ben Cardin</category>
<category>Ben Cayetano</category>
<category>Bill Brady</category>
<category>Bill Owens</category>
<category>Bruce Rauner</category>
<category>CA-24</category>
<category>Carl Paladino</category>
<category>Charles Djou</category>
<category>Dale Francisco</category>
<category>Dan Rutherford</category>
<category>David Alvarez</category>
<category>David Ige</category>
<category>David Larsen</category>
<category>DKE Daily Digests</category>
<category>Doug Gansler</category>
<category>Ed Cox</category>
<category>Elections</category>
<category>FL-13</category>
<category>Gary King</category>
<category>George Ariyoshi</category>
<category>HI-Gov</category>
<category>HI-Sen</category>
<category>Howie Morales</category>
<category>ID-02</category>
<category>Ideology</category>
<category>IL-Gov</category>
<category>John Lehman</category>
<category>John Walsh</category>
<category>Kevin Faulconer</category>
<category>Kirk Dillard</category>
<category>kshama sawant</category>
<category>Lawrence Rael</category>
<category>Linda Lopez</category>
<category>Lynwood Lewis</category>
<category>Maps</category>
<category>MD-Gov</category>
<category>Mike Simpson</category>
<category>Mitt Romney</category>
<category>MT-Sen</category>
<category>Nathan Fletcher</category>
<category>NC-06</category>
<category>NJ-07</category>
<category>NM-Gov</category>
<category>NY-21</category>
<category>NY-Gov</category>
<category>Onzlee Ware</category>
<category>Peter Schorsch</category>
<category>Phil Berger Jr.</category>
<category>Polls</category>
<category>Richard Conlin</category>
<category>Rob Astorino</category>
<category>SD Mayor</category>
<category>SeaTac</category>
<category>Siena</category>
<category>Special Elections</category>
<category>Steve Bullock</category>
<category>SurveyUSA</category>
<category>VA State House</category>
<category>VA State Senate</category>
<category>VA-AG</category>
<category>Washington</category>
<category>We Ask America</category>
<category>Wi State Senate</category>
<category>WI-LG</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256591</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 13:00:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256591/-Daily-Kos-Elections-Morning-Digest-Attacked-from-right-and-left-Fletcher-may-miss-San-Diego-runoff</feedburner:origLink></item>
<item>
<title>Daily Kos Radio is LIVE at 9am ET!</title>
<link>http://feeds.dailykos.com/~r/dailykos/index/~3/dOInjSJpoLc/-Daily-Kos-Radio-is-LIVE-at-9am-ET</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/blog/dailykosradio"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;span class="image_container"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/dk-production/images/4434/large/398x296_FacebookInStream.jpg?1346121562" alt="Daily Kos Radio logo" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Kos Radio's &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt; show podcasts are now available through iTunes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we're now being broadcast live on We Act Radio, Washington, DC's WPWC 1480 AM! So if you're in the area, tune in on your actual radio. And if not, you can always find their live stream at &lt;a href="http://www.weactradio.com/"&gt;WeActRadio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, I can't wait to find out what this show is going to be about! The answer is likely somewhere in my Pocket list, or about to be. When it comes to producing news to talk about, the world has never failed me yet. And if it does, we can always talk about who's stealing your money, or monitoring your phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're LIVE at 9:00 a.m. ET with &lt;em&gt;Kagro in the Morning&lt;/em&gt;, thanks to NetrootsRadio.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen LIVE here:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Daily Kos Radio Player&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-l"&gt;&lt;object classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" width="180" height="120" bgcolor="#FFFFFF"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/ffmp3-config.swf" /&gt;
&lt;param name="flashvars" value="url=http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls;;&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;codec=mp3&amp;amp;volume=20&amp;amp;buffering=5&amp;amp;skin=http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/skins/mcclean/ffmp3-mcclean.xml&amp;amp;title=NetrootsRadio&amp;amp;welcome=We%20are NetrootsRadio" /&gt;
&lt;param name="wmode" value="window" /&gt;
&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;
&lt;param name="scale" value="noscale" /&gt;
&lt;embed src="http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/ffmp3-config.swf" flashvars="url=http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls;;&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;codec=mp3&amp;amp;volume=20&amp;amp;buffering=5&amp;amp;skin=http://shoutcastflashplayer.com/skins/mcclean/ffmp3-mcclean.xml&amp;amp;title=NetrootsRadio&amp;amp;welcome=We%20are NetrootsRadio" width="180" scale="noscale" height="120" wmode="window" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://198.245.62.81:8018/listen.pls"&gt;Click this Link&lt;/a&gt; to Listen on your iTunes, Winamp or Windows Media Player
&lt;p&gt;Can't see the live stream and/or podcast players in these posts? Do you use NoScript or something similar to control Javascript? Want to? Remember to enable Libsyn and Shoutcastplayer, and you'll see our players every morning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or if you prefer, why not &lt;a href="http://landing.stitcher.com/?vurl=dailykos"&gt;download the Stitcher app&lt;/a&gt; on your favorite mobile device, and search for the Netroots Radio live stream? And hey, when you do, be sure to sign up with the promo code DAILYKOS, and earn Daily Kos Radio $1 in the Stitcher affiliate program!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do remember to "favorite" us while you're at Stitcher. We're bouncing up and down in the rankings these days, and the more of you who help us, the more listeners out there who'll find us on the Stitcher network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miss our last show? You can catch it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="dkimg-c"&gt;&lt;iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2556312/height/302/width/540/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="302" width="540" scrolling="no" defang_webkitallowfullscreen="" defang_mozallowfullscreen="" defang_oallowfullscreen="" defang_msallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Need more info on how to listen? Find it below the fold.&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://feeds.dailykos.com/~ff/dailykos/index?a=dOInjSJpoLc:J5Y0EyO9S7w:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/dailykos/index?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/dailykos/index/~4/dOInjSJpoLc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<author>rss@dailykos.com (David Waldman)</author>
<category>Daily Kos Radio</category>
<guid isPermaLink="false">_1256638</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 13:30:13 UTC</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/11/19/1256638/-Daily-Kos-Radio-is-LIVE-at-9am-ET</feedburner:origLink></item>
</channel>
</rss>
