<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	
	<link>http://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>TechCrunch is a group-edited blog that profiles the companies, products and events defining and transforming the new web.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 01:15:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain="techcrunch.com" port="80" path="/?rsscloud=notify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
<image><link>http://www.techcrunch.com</link><url>http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunchmu/images/techcrunch_logo.png</url><title>TechCrunch</title></image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://techcrunch.com/osd.xml" title="TechCrunch" />
	
	<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" /><feedburner:info uri="techcrunch" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://techcrunch.com/?pushpress=hub" /><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://add.my.yahoo.com/rss?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/us.yimg.com/i/us/my/addtomyyahoo4.gif">Subscribe with My Yahoo!</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.newsgator.com/ngs/subscriber/subext.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.newsgator.com/images/ngsub1.gif">Subscribe with NewsGator</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://feeds.my.aol.com/add.jsp?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://o.aolcdn.com/favorites.my.aol.com/webmaster/ffclient/webroot/locale/en-US/images/myAOLButtonSmall.gif">Subscribe with My AOL</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.bloglines.com/sub/http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" src="http://www.bloglines.com/images/sub_modern11.gif">Subscribe with Bloglines</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.netvibes.com/subscribe.php?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.netvibes.com/img/add2netvibes.gif">Subscribe with Netvibes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://fusion.google.com/add?feedurl=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://buttons.googlesyndication.com/fusion/add.gif">Subscribe with Google</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.pageflakes.com/subscribe.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.pageflakes.com/ImageFile.ashx?instanceId=Static_4&amp;fileName=ATP_blu_91x17.gif">Subscribe with Pageflakes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
		<title>Android App Marketplace 91 Wireless CEO Joe Wu Speaks For First Time about $1.9 Billion Acquisition By Baidu</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/9qDSsYRLJyc/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/android-app-marketplace-91-wireless-ceo-joe-wu-speaks-for-first-time-about-1-9-billion-acquisition-by-baidu/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 01:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[91Wireless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baidu]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=918060</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/image.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="image" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Now that his company, Android app marketplace 91 Wireless, has been acquired by search giant Baidu for $1.9 billion in the Chinese Internet industry's largest deal ever, CEO Joe Wu said he plans to become an angel investor and mentor to other entrepreneurs. During Wu's fireside chat at the Technode/TechCrunch event in Shanghai yesterday, his first in public since the deal was announced in July, he also talked about life at one of China's largest Internet companies after heading a startup.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=918060&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/image.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="image" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Now that his company, Android app marketplace 91 Wireless, has been acquired by search giant Baidu for $1.9 billion in the Chinese Internet industry's largest deal ever, CEO Joe Wu said he plans to become an angel investor and mentor to other entrepreneurs. During Wu's fireside chat at the Technode/TechCrunch event in Shanghai yesterday, his first in public since <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/07/15/baidu-agrees-to-buy-chinese-android-app-distributor-91-wireless-for-1-9b/">the deal was announced in July</a>, he also talked about life at one of China's largest Internet companies after heading a startup.</p>
<p>Before its acquisition, 91 Wireless was already one of the top players in China's lucrative but highly segmented Android app industry. But Wu says he knew that competition would only become more heated thanks to the country's rapidly growing smartphone penetration rates.</p>
<p>&#8220;I struggled with the idea of selling for a long time. When I talked with other companies they were shocked that I was consideirng the idea,&#8221; Wu said. &#8220;But I could only see the mobile Internet industry becoming even more competitive. 91 Wireless was a NetDragon subsidiary and we were doing well, but I thought we could collaborate Baidu because of the synergy between us. $1.9 billion is not the end of our story. I hope we'll get bigger and bigger.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wu says he also liked Baidu's culture, which he says emphasizes &#8220;simplicity and reliability&#8221; in their products.</p>
<p>When asked about the record-breaking $1.9 billion deal, which critics considered an extravagant valuation, Wu responded &#8220;we can't say if the price was too high or too low. We just needed someone who could see how 91 Wireless is changing the Internet in China. I thought that maybe we could collaborate with Baidu or Alibaba since the giant companies control the strategic landscape.&#8221;</p>
<p>In 2008, when Wu joined 91 Wireless, there were only 10 people in the NetDragon subsidiary. He took over as CEO the next year. Though 91 Wireless grew rapidly, it also had its share of growing pains. At one point, a third of its employees were poached by large tech companies. Wu said that he once became so agitated while thinking about money owed to 91 Wireless's creditors that he nearly crashed his car.</p>
<p>&#8220;It made me think that if I had been killed, then those people wouldn't have caused my death. It would have been my fault. I had to start thinking about how to get away from my depression,&#8221; says Wu. &#8220;That's the mindset. No matter what kind of business you startup, everyone is going to get grilled at some point and you have to figure out a solution. You can't be threatened or crushed by challenges. You need to see them as tests that will fully enhance your capabilities.&#8221;</p>
<p>Despite 91 Wireless's setbacks, Hu said the team had a very &#8220;easygoing&#8221; attitude. Now that he works for Baidu, Wu says he is busier than ever. &#8220;At 91 Wireless I was content as long as I saw growth every day. I wasn't obsessed with our market share. But at Baidu we're facing different kinds of competition from other big companies and Baidu has very high targets for its metrics and market share.&#8221;</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/918060/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9qDSsYRLJyc:Up8rYS8KWZ4:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9qDSsYRLJyc:Up8rYS8KWZ4:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9qDSsYRLJyc:Up8rYS8KWZ4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9qDSsYRLJyc:Up8rYS8KWZ4:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=9qDSsYRLJyc:Up8rYS8KWZ4:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9qDSsYRLJyc:Up8rYS8KWZ4:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=9qDSsYRLJyc:Up8rYS8KWZ4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9qDSsYRLJyc:Up8rYS8KWZ4:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/9qDSsYRLJyc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/android-app-marketplace-91-wireless-ceo-joe-wu-speaks-for-first-time-about-1-9-billion-acquisition-by-baidu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Android%20App%20Marketplace%2091%20Wireless%20CEO%20Joe%20Wu%20Speaks%20For%20First%20Time%20about%20%241.9%20Billion%20Acquisition%20By%26nbsp%3BBaidu</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/image.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/image.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f80a0e0a6502b4ec4f97f5b3bbd6ac25?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">catherineshu</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/android-app-marketplace-91-wireless-ceo-joe-wu-speaks-for-first-time-about-1-9-billion-acquisition-by-baidu/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>With $2.4M From Atlas, 500 Startups &amp; More, Colingo's Live Online School Aspires To Teach The World English</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/Nf4UoMQVZ00/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/with-2-4m-from-atlas-500-startups-more-colingos-live-online-school-aspires-to-teach-the-world-english/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rip Empson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[english language]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917912</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-11-56-40-am.png?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 11.56.40 AM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Like clockwork, today brings yet another entrant into the fast-growing and noisy language learning space. Just last night we told you about the expansion of Verbling, which is putting a live, interactive spin on language education. This morning, Colingo joined Verbling and others in this mission &#8212; to take on tired incumbents like Rosetta Stones and tackle the multi-billion dollar opportunity in the language learning market. Unlike many of its cohorts, yet similar to Verbling, Colingo is taking a web-first approach, using in-browser, Google Hangouts-based video chat to bring language learners together with native speakers (and teachers) and to help them learn through conversation and immersion. However, while some startups and services focus on breadth and offer support for multiple languages, Colingo is trying to stand out from the pack by focusing on English-language proficiency and learning. The startup wants to create a live, global and digital English school, starting with the launch of its teacher-led, group video chat classes, personalized skill training and private tutoring. To do so, Colingo founder Ben Lowenstein told us today that the company has raised $2.4 million in seed funding to help it ramp up hiring and meet the growing demand for quality English-language learning services in developing countries. Atlas Venture led the startup&#8217;s first investment, with contributions from 500 Startups, Morado Ventures, Crosslink Capital, Havoc Capital and Social Leverage, as well as handful of angel investors, including Khosla Partner Ben Ling, Dogster founder Ted Rheingold and Chegg founder Aayush Phumbhra. With Livemocha, Babbel, Voxy, MindSnacks, OpenEnglish and Duolingo all having raised multiple millions, Colingo becomes the latest indication that investor interest in language learning continues. Although it launches officially today, Colingo has been building the foundations of its English-language platform for over a year now and as of today, the startup counts 27 teachers, 70-plus curricular skills and over 150,000 students from 180 countries in its network. Given the early success OpenEnglish has had in Brazil, and the huge opportunity it sees going forward, it may not surprise you to learn that it has the largest share of Colingo&#8217;s customer base with over 30K students. Following Brazil are the U.S. and Mexico and Lowenstein that Eastern Europe and Latin America (at large) represent two potentially core areas for Colingo&#8217;s growth going forward. Beyond a growing Latin American user base &#8212; which is really just a micro-representation of the fast-growing demand for quality English-language learning programs across Latin America<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917912&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-11-56-40-am.png?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 11.56.40 AM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Like clockwork, today brings yet another entrant into the fast-growing and noisy language learning space. Just last night we told you <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/new-funding-in-tow-verbling-adds-live-study-groups-and-one-on-one-tutoring-as-its-spin-on-language-learning-begins-to-catch-on/">about the expansion of Verbling</a>, which is putting a live, interactive spin on language education.</p>
<p>This morning, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.colingo.com/">Colingo</a> joined Verbling and others in this mission - to take on tired incumbents like Rosetta Stones and tackle the multi-billion dollar opportunity in the language learning market. Unlike many of its cohorts, yet similar to Verbling, Colingo is taking a web-first approach, using in-browser, Google Hangouts-based video chat to bring language learners together with native speakers (and teachers) and to help them learn through conversation and immersion.</p>
<p>However, while some startups and services focus on breadth and offer support for multiple languages, Colingo is trying to stand out from the pack by focusing on English-language proficiency and learning. The startup wants to create a live, global and digital English school, starting with the launch of its teacher-led, group video chat classes, personalized skill training and private tutoring. </p>
<p>To do so, Colingo founder Ben Lowenstein told us today that the company has raised $2.4 million in seed funding to help it ramp up hiring and meet the growing demand for quality English-language learning services in developing countries. Atlas Venture led the startup's first investment, with contributions from 500 Startups, Morado Ventures, Crosslink Capital, Havoc Capital and Social Leverage, as well as handful of angel investors, including Khosla Partner Ben Ling, Dogster founder Ted Rheingold and Chegg founder Aayush Phumbhra.</p>
<p>With Livemocha, Babbel, Voxy, MindSnacks, OpenEnglish and Duolingo all having raised multiple millions, Colingo becomes the latest indication that investor interest in language learning continues. Although it launches officially today, Colingo has been building the foundations of its English-language platform for over a year now and as of today, the startup counts 27 teachers, 70-plus curricular skills and over 150,000 students from 180 countries in its network. </p>
<p>Given the early success OpenEnglish has had in Brazil, and the huge opportunity it sees going forward, it may not surprise you to learn that it has the largest share of Colingo's customer base with over 30K students. Following Brazil are the U.S. and Mexico and Lowenstein that Eastern Europe and Latin America (at large) represent two potentially core areas for Colingo's growth going forward. </p>
<p>Beyond a growing Latin American user base - which is really just a micro-representation of the fast-growing demand for quality English-language learning programs across Latin America - Colingo is trying to differentiate by not only focusing on English, but a particular segment of English learners. Colingo's core demographic, Lowenstein says, is those who have a basic understanding of English but lack the confidence or fluency to speak comfortably in conversational and professional settings. </p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-2-52-36-pm.png"></a></p>
<p>Offering live classes 24-hours-a-day, Colingo's classes aim to blend &#8220;authentic conversation about contemporary topics,&#8221; Lowenstein says, with a more structured curriculum of skill-training and assessment. So, while users have the freedom to join as many classes as they want and seek, private, one-on-one tutoring, at their own pace and speed, Colingo is trying to strike a balance on its approach to language education. </p>
<p>On the one hand, it's meant to be casual and conversational, so ESL students can learn English from a certified teacher (and native speaker) by discussing topics they actually care about, whether that's the latest news from the NFL, the day's political headlines or fresh celebrity gossip. </p>
<p>The idea, the founder says, is to remove formalized learning methods from language education, whether it be rote memorization or using boring examples and exercises (the book is on the table, under the table, next to the table, etc etc). But the goal of removing the formality from learning isn't to reduce Colingo's responsibility or to avoid having to offer credentials, it's to provide a more authentic and appealing learning experience, he says, balanced with the structure of training and assessment on over 70 core grammar and pronunciation skills.</p>
<p>In addition, like Harvard (and Verbling to a degree), Colingo is focused on becoming a Small Private Online Class (SPOC) platform, as opposed to the Massive Open Online Course (MOOC) model which has skyrocketed to popularity thanks to the likes of Coursera, Udacity and EdX, among others. The Colingo CEO believes that part of the reason MOOC platforms have traditionally suffered from such appalling dropout rates (near 90 percent in some cases) has to do with the lack of sustained interpersonal interaction. </p>
<p>While some MOOC platforms have been battling this, it's easy for students to fall through the cracks when their classmates are remote, remain relatively anonymous and number in the the thousands. Conversely, Colingo has made its live, online classes the centerpiece of its platform for this very reason - to encourage group interaction among students and teachers. The startup also intentionally keeps class sizes small, with the average size of classes on Colingo being three to five students, allowing students to build confidence without having to pronounce unfamiliar words in front of 50K people.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-2-53-32-pm.png"></a></p>
<p>Ultimately, one doesn't learn to drive a car by watching a YouTube video, the CEO explains, so the mission for Lowenstein and Colingo's teachers is to get their students to tap the brakes on studying and start testing themselves by speaking with others - as much as possible. But it's not just aimless immersion, again, the startup wants to focus these conversations on a succession of skills within a larger learning path. </p>
<p>It may sound obscure, but that's potentially where Colingo's real value could lie: In its ability to create a conversational and immersive learning experience that's both casual and structured. A little bit of formal education, a little rambling video chat about how terrible the Jacksonville Jaguars are. </p>
<p>After a 7-day free trial, Colingo offers a monthly subscription for $50/month, which offers students unlimited access to its platform, or those looking for more personalized, one-on-one instruction can opt into its &#8220;Personal Teacher&#8221; plan, which costs $150/month. </p>
<p>Colingo has an uphill battle in front of it just given how many language learning services, apps and platforms are out there. It will have to find a way to overcome an obstacle that has stalled many language startups: Maintaining both teacher and curricular quality at scale. It's not easy to do, but the startup is off to a good start.</p>
<p>Find <a target="_blank" href="http://www.colingo.com/">Colingo at home here</a>.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917912/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Nf4UoMQVZ00:3Vjz_kbXcyI:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Nf4UoMQVZ00:3Vjz_kbXcyI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Nf4UoMQVZ00:3Vjz_kbXcyI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Nf4UoMQVZ00:3Vjz_kbXcyI:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Nf4UoMQVZ00:3Vjz_kbXcyI:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Nf4UoMQVZ00:3Vjz_kbXcyI:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Nf4UoMQVZ00:3Vjz_kbXcyI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Nf4UoMQVZ00:3Vjz_kbXcyI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/Nf4UoMQVZ00" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/with-2-4m-from-atlas-500-startups-more-colingos-live-online-school-aspires-to-teach-the-world-english/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-11-56-40-am.png" type="image/png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">With%20%242.4M%20From%20Atlas%2C%20500%20Startups%20%26amp%3B%20More%2C%20Colingo%26%238217%3Bs%20Live%20Online%20School%20Aspires%20To%20Teach%20The%20World%26nbsp%3BEnglish</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-11-56-40-am.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-11-56-40-am.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 11.56.40 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a94f6b72a8ee7342e862c1c9d6c5b826?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rempson8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-2-52-36-pm.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 2.52.36 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-2-53-32-pm.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 2.53.32 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/with-2-4m-from-atlas-500-startups-more-colingos-live-online-school-aspires-to-teach-the-world-english/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>In Case You Thought BuzzFeed Needed More GIFs, The Site Launches A GIF Feed Sponsored By Google+</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/HZ9xkx5XreA/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/buzzfeed-gif-feed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buzzfeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIFs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=918043</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/buzzfeed-gif-feed.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="buzzfeed gif feed" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Do you sometimes read <a target="_blank" href="http://www.buzzfeed.com">BuzzFeed</a> and think, "This is great, but why is all this text getting in the way of the funny GIFs?" If so, there's a perfect new section for you, called <a target="_blank" href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/giffeed">the GIF Feed</a>.

It's actually not a standard editorial page but ratherof a promotional campaign sponsored by Google+ as a way to show off <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/08/20/google-expands-google-photos-app-to-all-chromebooks-no-longer-limited-to-just-the-pixel/">its Auto Awesome feature</a>, which creates GIFs. (This parenthetical remark was originally where I <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphics_Interchange_Format">explained what a GIF is</a>, but if you don't know, then this post probably isn't for you.) Most of the GIFs are shared by BuzzFeed, but there's also a sponsored unit in the upper right corner which points to more Google+-sponsored GIF collections.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=918043&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/buzzfeed-gif-feed.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="buzzfeed gif feed" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Do you sometimes read <a target="_blank" href="http://www.buzzfeed.com">BuzzFeed</a> and think, &#8220;This is great, but why is all this text getting in the way of the funny GIFs?&#8221; If so, there's a perfect new section for you, called <a target="_blank" href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/giffeed">the GIF Feed</a>.</p>
<p>It's actually not a standard editorial page but ratherof a promotional campaign sponsored by Google+ as a way to show off <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/08/20/google-expands-google-photos-app-to-all-chromebooks-no-longer-limited-to-just-the-pixel/">its Auto Awesome feature</a>, which creates GIFs. (This parenthetical remark was originally where I <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphics_Interchange_Format">explained what a GIF is</a>, but if you don't know, then this post probably isn't for you.) Most of the GIFs are shared by BuzzFeed, but there's also a sponsored unit in the upper right corner which points to more Google+-sponsored GIF collections. </p>
<p>A Google spokesperson sang the praises of GIFs via email and told me the company created the Auto Awesome feature because &#8220;we love them so much.&#8221;</p>
<p>The campaign seems worth pointing out for a couple of reasons. First of all: GIFs! Secondly, it's a good example of the kinds of <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/08/13/buzzfeed-pepsi-listiclock/">custom ad campaigns</a> that have apparently <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/04/buzzfeed-profitable/">brought the site to profitability</a>.</p>
<p>A BuzzFeed spokesperson said the campaign will run until the end of the year, and that it's the first such section that the company have created. When I admitted that I wasn't as totally addicted to the feed as they claimed to be (maybe it's because you have to click on images to see the full picture and the animation, maybe it's because my heart is made of stone), the spokesperson added:</p>
<blockquote><p>BuzzFeed users that love GIFs get to look at a comprehensive library of their favorite GIFs and share with their friends. Just like any other piece of social content on our site, this is another fun way for users to share their favorite moments via social sharing.</p></blockquote><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/918043/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HZ9xkx5XreA:83xaJMrRmrA:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HZ9xkx5XreA:83xaJMrRmrA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HZ9xkx5XreA:83xaJMrRmrA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HZ9xkx5XreA:83xaJMrRmrA:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=HZ9xkx5XreA:83xaJMrRmrA:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HZ9xkx5XreA:83xaJMrRmrA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=HZ9xkx5XreA:83xaJMrRmrA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HZ9xkx5XreA:83xaJMrRmrA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/HZ9xkx5XreA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/buzzfeed-gif-feed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/buzzfeed-gif-feed.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">In%20Case%20You%20Thought%20BuzzFeed%20Needed%20More%20GIFs%2C%20The%20Site%20Launches%20A%20GIF%20Feed%20Sponsored%20By%26nbsp%3BGoogle%2B</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/buzzfeed-gif-feed.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/buzzfeed-gif-feed.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">buzzfeed gif feed</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/72b358648f4587cc2a11895c32b8e979?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anthha</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/buzzfeed-gif-feed/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Dropbox-Rival Box Is Raising $100M In New Funding At A $2B Valuation</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/3PMgWxz0jzU/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/dropbox-rival-box-is-raising-100m-in-new-funding-at-a-2b-valuation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm,Leena Rao]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Box]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=918022</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="197" height="116" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/3484v3-max-250x250.png?w=197&amp;h=116&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="3484v3-max-250x250" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Enterprise cloud file storage firm Box is raising an additional $100 million in capital at a valuation of around $2 billion. A filing with the State of Delaware was first <a target="_blank" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/box-may-raise-100m-be-worth-2-billion-2013-11">noticed by VC Experts</a>. We've heard from sources that Box is indeed raising a new round, at a $2 billion-plus valuation. The company raised $125 million in June of 2012 at a valuation of roughly $1 billion.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=918022&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="197" height="116" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/3484v3-max-250x250.png?w=197&amp;h=116&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="3484v3-max-250x250" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Enterprise cloud file storage firm Box is raising an additional $100 million in capital at a valuation of around $2 billion. A filing with the State of Delaware was first <a target="_blank" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/box-may-raise-100m-be-worth-2-billion-2013-11">noticed by VC Experts</a>. We've heard from sources that Box is indeed raising a new round, at a $2 billion-plus valuation. The company raised $125 million in June of 2012 at a valuation of roughly $1 billion.</p>
<p>The new funds could be viewed as capital to help Box reach the public markets, provided that its revenue growth is on track. This will likely be the last round of funding for the company before it IPOs next year. </p>
<p>According to <a target="_blank" href="https://vcexperts.com/">VCExperts'</a> Justin Byers, on October 14, 2013, Box authorized a new series of preferred stock. To be exact, there were 5,556,000 shares of Series E-1 Preferred stock authorized at $18 per share, or a $100 million value, authorized for this new preferred stock. The prior round of preferred stock authorized by the company was a Series E Preferred on August 3, 2012, at a price of $13.0949 per share. VC Experts is calculating the valuation following this round at just shy of $2 billion.</p>
<p>According to the data VC Experts has collected, this price at $18 per share is still a far cry from where they recently priced their Class B Common Stock. VC Experts obtained a filing from May 17, 2013, that showed the company pricing their Class B Common stock at $4.63.</p>
<p>Box just raised <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/31/box-raises-125m/">$125 million</a> in new funding last year, and another $25 million <a target="_blank" href="http://allthingsd.com/20130129/dont-look-now-but-boxs-last-funding-round-just-got-bigger/">earlier this year.</a> A new round would put Box's funding at over $400 million total. Box famously turned down a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/13/box-the-path-from-arringtons-backyard-to-a-billion-dollar-business/">$600 million acquisition offer from Citrix in 2011</a>.</p>
<p>The company was said to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/boxnet-operates-at-15-million-loss-each-month-2011-11">generate $10 million</a> in the fourth quarter of 2011, with around $25 million in revenue for that full calendar year. Revenue for 2012 was tipped to be <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/13/box-the-path-from-arringtons-backyard-to-a-billion-dollar-business/">on track to reach $75 million</a>. It was later reported that Box instead was <a target="_blank" href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/victoriabarret/2012/07/31/boxs-big-125-million-round-signals-a-bigger-shift-in-software/">on track for $85 million</a> in revenue for that year.</p>
<p>It isn't clear what Box's current revenue rate is, though the company is presumably growing in keeping with its prior rates.</p>
<p>What's odd about the news is that Box is raising funds at a valuation of one fourth that of its rival, Dropbox, a company that has had a somewhat comparable revenue curve. According <a target="_blank" href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702303985504579206763922615986">to the Wall Street Journal</a>, Dropbox had 2011 revenue of $46 million, $116 million in 2012, and will produce something over $200 million this year.</p>
<p>So, Dropbox was around $21 million ahead of Box in 2011, around $31 million ahead of Box in 2012, and likely a similar chunk this year. So, Dropbox appears to be ahead. But the percentage different isn't anything close to a four times multiplier, making Box's paltry &#8211; in comparison &#8211; $2 billion valuation almost strange.</p>
<p>For example, Box had 2012 revenue of roughly 73% of Dropbox's top line. Which makes the delta between their valuation odd unless either Box has seen its growth decelerate, or Dropbox has found an updraft and is beating its internal metrics.</p>
<p>Assuming Box doubled its 2012 revenue in 2013 &#8211; essentially mirroring the doubling of its market capitalization &#8211; it will generate sales of $170 million in the year. At a $2 billion valuation, Box is valued at a mere 11.7 times trailing earnings. When Twitter went public, it was valued three to five times as richly, looking at its past revenue and market cap (using a diluted share count).</p>
<p>We contacted Box for comment and will update if we receive more information.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/918022/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3PMgWxz0jzU:fWi-1KQTlos:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3PMgWxz0jzU:fWi-1KQTlos:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3PMgWxz0jzU:fWi-1KQTlos:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3PMgWxz0jzU:fWi-1KQTlos:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=3PMgWxz0jzU:fWi-1KQTlos:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3PMgWxz0jzU:fWi-1KQTlos:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=3PMgWxz0jzU:fWi-1KQTlos:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3PMgWxz0jzU:fWi-1KQTlos:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/3PMgWxz0jzU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/dropbox-rival-box-is-raising-100m-in-new-funding-at-a-2b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/3484v3-max-250x250.png" type="image/png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Dropbox-Rival%20Box%20Is%20Raising%20%24100M%20In%20New%20Funding%20At%20A%20%242B%26nbsp%3BValuation</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/3484v3-max-250x250.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/3484v3-max-250x250.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3484v3-max-250x250</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a3a71bf0d3d22efa0db4b77936a066b8?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexjameswilhelm</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/dropbox-rival-box-is-raising-100m-in-new-funding-at-a-2b-valuation/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>TOMS Founder Blake Mycoskie On Turning The One-For-One Charity Model Into A Platform</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/TinoI0lujb8/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/toms-founder-blake-mycoskie-marketplace/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Colleen Taylor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=916593</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/blakemycoskie.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="blakemycoskie" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Given the near ubiquity of its simply designed shoes, it's almost hard to believe that <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toms_Shoes">TOMS</a>, the company that's known for donating one pair of shoes or eyewear to an impoverished child for every pair that it sells, was founded just seven years ago. But it turns out TOMS founder <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blake_Mycoskie">Blake Mycoskie</a> has only just gotten started on his mission -- and with the launch this month of a new e-commerce initiative called TOMS Marketplace, the one-for-one concept that's been popularized by TOMS is moving well beyond shoes and sunglasses. <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=916593&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/blakemycoskie.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="blakemycoskie" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><div class="video-container" id="a13bacf7da"><script type="text/javascript" src="http://pshared.5min.com/Scripts/PlayerSeed.js?sid=577&#038;width=640&#038;height=450&#038;colorPallet=%2300B100&#038;playerActions=8260&#038;hasCompanion=false&#038;playList=518011023&#038;autostart=false"></script></div><br />
Given the near ubiquity of its simply designed shoes, it's almost hard to believe that <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toms_Shoes">TOMS</a>, the company that's known for donating one pair of shoes or eyewear to an impoverished child for every pair that it sells, was founded just seven years ago. But it turns out TOMS founder <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blake_Mycoskie">Blake Mycoskie</a> has only just gotten started on his mission - and with the launch this month of a new e-commerce initiative called <a target="_blank" href="http://www.toms.com/marketplace">TOMS Marketplace</a>, the one-for-one concept that's been popularized by TOMS is moving well beyond shoes and sunglasses. </p>
<p>In a way, TOMS' latest web launch turns the company into a platform - a concept that should be quite familiar to anyone in the tech sector. The TOMS Marketplace <a target="_blank" href="http://www.toms.com/marketplace">website</a> is a one-stop-shop that brings together hundreds of &#8220;socially conscious products&#8221; from 30 different companies. The idea, Mycoskie said, is to encourage people to look at more purchasing decisions as opportunities to think about giving to those in need.  </p>
<p>Mycoskie was visiting the San Francisco Bay Area last week, so we asked him to swing by TechCrunch HQ to talk about his new foray in the e-commerce space. We also discussed how tech companies can start thinking in a more philanthropic way from the start, how giving back can be good for business, and more. You can check that all out in the video embedded above.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/916593/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TinoI0lujb8:VF8X5q_2sH4:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TinoI0lujb8:VF8X5q_2sH4:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TinoI0lujb8:VF8X5q_2sH4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TinoI0lujb8:VF8X5q_2sH4:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=TinoI0lujb8:VF8X5q_2sH4:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TinoI0lujb8:VF8X5q_2sH4:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=TinoI0lujb8:VF8X5q_2sH4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TinoI0lujb8:VF8X5q_2sH4:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/TinoI0lujb8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/toms-founder-blake-mycoskie-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://pthumbnails.5min.com/10360221/518011023_8_1279_727.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">TOMS%20Founder%20Blake%20Mycoskie%20On%20Turning%20The%20One-For-One%20Charity%20Model%20Into%20A%26nbsp%3BPlatform</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/blakemycoskie.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/blakemycoskie.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">blakemycoskie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4978d78871dc3ed1a4264d051e6c9193?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">colleentechcrunch</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/toms-founder-blake-mycoskie-marketplace/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>TaskRabbit Takes Its Errands Marketplace To London For Its First Move Outside The U.S.</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/_hw9do94gjY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/taskrabbit-takes-its-errands-marketplace-to-the-uk-for-its-first-move-outside-the-u-s/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TaskRabbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collaborative consumption]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=918008</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/christmas-help2x.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="christmas-help@2x taskrabbit" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.taskrabbit.com">TaskRabbit</a>, the U.S. startup that runs a marketplace for people who need help with short-term work and errands, is hopping over the pond for its first international city launch. On Thursday, it will open for business in London, starting with 50 Taskers ready to take on your every need in the areas of Christmas-related errands, cleaning and handyman-type work. Further UK cities will come in the months ahead, Stacy Brown-Philpot, TaskRabbit's COO, told me on Wednesday.
<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=918008&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/christmas-help2x.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="christmas-help@2x taskrabbit" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.taskrabbit.com">TaskRabbit</a>, the U.S. startup that runs a marketplace for people who need help with short-term work and errands, is hopping over the pond for its first international city launch. On Thursday, it will open for business in London, starting with 50 Taskers ready to take on your every need in the areas of Christmas-related errands, cleaning and handyman-type work. Further UK cities will come in the months ahead, Stacy Brown-Philpot, TaskRabbit's COO, told me on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Prices for the initial errands on offer while TaskRabbit is still in beta in the UK range from between £12 to £25 per hour ($19-$40).</p>
<p>TaskRabbit has seen some knocks in its home market - manifested in the form of <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/07/08/taskrabbit-confirms-layoffs-as-it-realigns-to-focus-on-mobile-and-enterprise/">layoffs</a> to refocus on what the company believes are opportunities in enterprise, mobile and geographic expansion. And <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/09/zaarly-shutters-its-reverse-craigslist-marketplace-goes-all-in-on-virtual-storefronts-as-co-founder-exits/">some of its would-be competitors like Zaarly</a> have also faced business challenges. In that sense, expanding internationally and the move to greener pastures could be a way for the company to spur growth. The London launch follows on the heels of a five-city expansion in the U.S. in <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/08/19/taskrabbit-launches-its-on-demand-errand-running-service-in-5-new-cities/">August</a>. London brings the total number of cities where TaskRabbit is active to 20.</p>
<p>But TaskRabbit is not entering a new market without its own hurdles. The UK, as <a target="_blank" href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2013/11/04/131104fa_fact_smith">Zadie Smith recently noted</a>, is not exactly known for its service culture around food delivery, partly because the people who bring the food are surly, and partly because customers find the whole exchange so awkward. Taking that another step further, and going on my own experience as a longtime London transplant, I'd venture to say that perhaps many UK consumers are not naturally inclined to call on strangers to do lots of other things for them at the spur of the moment. The pictures that TaskRabbit supplied to me, in their stilted staging, only emphasize that feeling to me even more.</p>
<p>There are other challenges in the UK, in the form of existing players in the delivery market. Among them, the UK has <a target="_blank" href="http://www.taskpandas.com/">TaskPandas</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://sortedlocal.com/">Sorted</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://sooqini.com/">Sooqini</a>, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/05/mila-a-local-mobile-marketplace-for-errands-raises-3m-to-bag-emerging-markets/">Mila</a>, along with at least one casualty, Milk.ly, which started as TaskRabbit clone but now has pivoted to e-commerce.</p>
<p>Interestingly, although there are a ton of offerings in the UK already, TaskRabbit says that London has been the most-requested city outside of the U.S. for the company. &#8220;Paris is a hot city that has the largest amount of demand after London,&#8221; Brown-Philpot says. &#8220;Toronto and Sydney after that.&#8221; (All those expansions would make a big dent in the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/taskrabbit">$37.7 million</a> the company has raised to date.) You could argue that the fact that these other startups are here working will make the market more receptive to TaskRabbit, too.</p>
<p>So what will set TaskRabbit apart from the rest? At its base, TaskRabbit is coming into the UK with the feeling that it is the market leader. Even if there are others, none have &#8220;our reputation,&#8221; she says, with 75% of its business coming from word-of-mouth. (And, from my own experience, using TaskRabbit in San Francisco, I have wished we had it here in London - although the service I have used it for, slightly odd purchasing and delivery requests, doesn't fall into the three categories TaskRabbit's launching with here in London.)</p>
<p>Brown-Philpot says that TaskRabbit has also done its homework, with a survey of some 2,000 consumers. The three areas where it is first concentrating (Christmas shopping/wrapping/preparing; cleaning; small repairwork) came directly from those results. The target audience, she says, are professional women who are married and have kids and just want more time in their lives.</p>
<p>On the supplier side, Brown-Philpot says that TaskRabbit had no problems getting people to sign up to become Taskers. She says that TaskRabbit found them through Facebook and Google advertising, and as part of getting onboarded they were vetted for fraud and other security-related areas, &#8220;and to make sure they had the skills they said they had.&#8221; There are more applications coming in, as there always have been in its home market, she says. Putting demand and cultural norms in the UK to one side, &#8220;We never have a problem with supply. There are always people looking for extra income.&#8221;</p>
<p></p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/918008/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_hw9do94gjY:jyBMDdztONM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_hw9do94gjY:jyBMDdztONM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_hw9do94gjY:jyBMDdztONM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_hw9do94gjY:jyBMDdztONM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=_hw9do94gjY:jyBMDdztONM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_hw9do94gjY:jyBMDdztONM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=_hw9do94gjY:jyBMDdztONM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_hw9do94gjY:jyBMDdztONM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/_hw9do94gjY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/taskrabbit-takes-its-errands-marketplace-to-the-uk-for-its-first-move-outside-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/christmas-help2x.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">TaskRabbit%20Takes%20Its%20Errands%20Marketplace%20To%20London%20For%20Its%20First%20Move%20Outside%20The%26nbsp%3BU.S.</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/christmas-help2x.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/christmas-help2x.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">christmas-help@2x taskrabbit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6648ec93043f0f368091adece63c6d52?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ingridlunden</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/house-cleaning2x.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">house-cleaning@2x</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-23-51-25.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 23.51.25</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/taskrabbit-takes-its-errands-marketplace-to-the-uk-for-its-first-move-outside-the-u-s/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week On The TechCrunch Droidcast: Moto G's Big Battery, Moto X Financing And Google Wallet Card</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/jxIU0r4ZcHg/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/this-week-on-the-techcrunch-droidcast-moto-gs-big-battery-moto-x-financing-and-google-wallet-card/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 23:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[droidcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=918016</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/droidcast15.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="droidcast15" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />This week, me and Chris Velazco talk about using the Moto G for a prolonged period, Motorola trying to attract more Moto X shoppers with no-money-down deals, and Google going after shopper activity with a physical card for its digital wallet. We have a grand old time, and for once a mid-market phone is the talk of the town, which is actually refreshing. Also Chris needed like fifteen takes just to get us started, because apparently he&#8217;s a completely ridiculous person. We invite you to enjoy weekly Android podcasts every Wednesday at 5:30 p.m. Eastern and 2:30 p.m. Pacific (generally speaking), in addition to our weekly Gadgets podcast at 3 p.m. Eastern and noon Pacific on Fridays. Subscribe to the TechCrunch Droidcast in iTunes, too, if that’s your fancy. Intro music by Kris Keyser. Direct download available here.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=918016&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/droidcast15.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="droidcast15" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>This week, me and Chris Velazco talk about using the Moto G for a prolonged period, Motorola trying to attract more Moto X shoppers with no-money-down deals, and Google going after shopper activity with a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/google-wallet-invades-your-physical-one-with-a-new-prepaid-debit-card/">physical card for its digital wallet</a>.</p>
<p>We have a grand old time, and for once a mid-market phone is the talk of the town, which is actually refreshing. Also Chris needed like fifteen takes just to get us started, because apparently he's a completely ridiculous person.</p>
<iframe style="border: none;" src="//html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2560042/height/360/width/640/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe>
<p>We invite you to enjoy <a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/android-podcast/">weekly Android podcasts</a> every Wednesday at 5:30 p.m. Eastern and 2:30 p.m. Pacific (generally speaking), in addition to our <a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/gadgets-podcast/">weekly Gadgets podcast</a> at 3 p.m. Eastern and noon Pacific on Fridays. Subscribe to the <a target="_blank" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/techcrunch-droidcast/id685717834?mt=2">TechCrunch Droidcast in iTunes, too, if that's your fancy</a>.</p>
<p>Intro music by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.kriskeyser.com/">Kris Keyser</a>.</p>
<p>Direct <a target="_blank" href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3">download available here</a>.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/918016/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jxIU0r4ZcHg:gKLZsoi48FI:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jxIU0r4ZcHg:gKLZsoi48FI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jxIU0r4ZcHg:gKLZsoi48FI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jxIU0r4ZcHg:gKLZsoi48FI:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=jxIU0r4ZcHg:gKLZsoi48FI:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jxIU0r4ZcHg:gKLZsoi48FI:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=jxIU0r4ZcHg:gKLZsoi48FI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jxIU0r4ZcHg:gKLZsoi48FI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/jxIU0r4ZcHg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/this-week-on-the-techcrunch-droidcast-moto-gs-big-battery-moto-x-financing-and-google-wallet-card/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/tcdroidcast/droidcast-ep-15.mp3" length="45206382" type="audio/mpeg" />
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/droidcast15.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">This%20Week%20On%20The%20TechCrunch%20Droidcast%3A%20Moto%20G%26%238217%3Bs%20Big%20Battery%2C%20Moto%20X%20Financing%20And%20Google%20Wallet%26nbsp%3BCard</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/droidcast15.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/droidcast15.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">droidcast15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/188039e12983eb749171a75cfd01378d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">etherin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/this-week-on-the-techcrunch-droidcast-moto-gs-big-battery-moto-x-financing-and-google-wallet-card/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Google's Cerf Says “Privacy May Be An Anomaly”. Historically, He's Right.</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/msvyqeHTTl4/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/googles-cerf-says-privacy-may-be-an-anomaly-historically-hes-right/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 22:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gregory Ferenstein]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Crunch-gov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917960</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/1818985346_1a4e83b3ce_b.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="1818985346_1a4e83b3ce_b" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />One of the original architects of the Internet wants to remind us that privacy is a relatively new concept. &#8220;Privacy is something which has emerged out of the urban boom coming from the industrial revolution,&#8221; said Google&#8217;s Chief Internet Evangelist and a lead engineer on the Army&#8217;s early 1970&#8242;s Internet prototype, ARPANET. As a result, &#8216;privacy may actually be an anomaly,&#8221; he told a gathering of the Federal Trade Commission. Looking back at history, Cerf is mostly right. Up until the 19th century, most houses had few or no internal walls. Bathing was a public act. For most of the post-Roman era, the very concept of &#8220;solitude&#8221; was limited to clergy, who dedicated their lives to private worship. &#8220;Intercourse, birth, death, just about every aspect of the life cycle plays out with some sort of audience,&#8221; architectural historian Bernard Herman explained to me. An expert in early American housing, Herman found that the average home was about 16&#215;10 ft with multiple families living under one roof. Indeed, the invention of the &#8220;Bed Chamber&#8221; really doesn&#8217;t become popular among the European wealthy  until around the 1600s. The few Medieval aristocrats who could afford a bed still used to sleep with house guests and servants on extra large mattresses. In Rome, bathrooms were public; evidence suggests people chatted while relieving themselves in open multi-toilet rooms. Indeed, in Rome, even for those who could afford to build houses with internal walls, still chose to put their private lives on display. Ostentatious displays of one&#8217;s wealth to the world with an open house was a status symbol. There may have been once exeption to this rule: excavations of ancient greek houses reveal architecture with partitioned rooms and windows that obscured views inside the home [PDF]. But, for the most part, privacy didn&#8217;t really exist in ancient cities. Perhaps the real concern is with information privacy? Well, that&#8217;s new too. The &#8220;right to privacy&#8221; was not coined until 1890, by future Chief Justice Louis Brandeis. The right to privacy would not be recognized by the Supreme Court until the landmark 1967 case, Katz v. The United States. In some ways, informational privacy isn&#8217;t a concern until the modern age, because few people had the technology or knowhow to write anything down. Still, privacy regulations did not catch up with literacy until the mid 19th Century. For instance, while there were scattered concerns with the very<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917960&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/1818985346_1a4e83b3ce_b.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="1818985346_1a4e83b3ce_b" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>One of the original architects of the Internet wants to remind us that privacy is a relatively new concept. &#8220;Privacy is something which has emerged out of the urban boom coming from the industrial revolution,&#8221; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/11/20/5125922/vint-cerf-google-internet-evangelist-says-privacy-may-be-anomaly">said</a> Google's Chief Internet Evangelist and a lead engineer on the Army's early 1970&#8242;s Internet prototype, ARPANET. As a result, &#8216;privacy may actually be an anomaly,&#8221; he told a gathering of the Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<p>Looking back at history, Cerf is mostly right.</p>
<p>Up until the 19th century, most houses had few or no internal walls. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-399017/The-steamy-truth-Roman-Bath.html">Bathing was a public act</a>. For most of the post-Roman era, the very concept of &#8220;solitude&#8221; <a target="_blank" href="http://books.google.com/books/about/Privacy_and_Solitude.html?id=MdF9QgAACAAJ">was limited to clergy</a>, who dedicated their lives to private worship. &#8220;Intercourse, birth, death, just about every aspect of the life cycle plays out with some sort of audience,&#8221; architectural historian Bernard Herman explained to me.</p>
<p>An expert in early American housing, Herman found that the average home was about 16&#215;10 ft with multiple families living under one roof. Indeed, the invention of the &#8220;Bed Chamber&#8221; really doesn't become <a target="_blank" href="http://books.google.com/books?id=Xn24enePQeoC&amp;q=bedchamber#v=snippet&amp;q=bedchamber&amp;f=false">popular</a> among the European wealthy  until around the 1600s. The few Medieval aristocrats who could afford a bed still used to sleep with house guests and servants on extra large mattresses.</p>
<p>In Rome, bathrooms were public; <a target="_blank" href="http://books.google.com/books?id=BAoUAQAAMAAJ&amp;focus=searchwithinvolume&amp;q=latrines">evidence suggests</a> people chatted while relieving themselves in open multi-toilet rooms. Indeed, in Rome, even for those who could afford to build houses with internal walls, still chose to put their private lives on display. Ostentatious displays of one's wealth to the world with an open house was a status symbol.</p>
<p>There may have been once exeption to this rule: excavations of ancient greek houses reveal architecture with partitioned rooms and windows that obscured views inside the home [<a target="_blank" href="https://lra.le.ac.uk/handle/2381/8947">PDF</a>]. But, for the most part, privacy didn't really exist in ancient cities.</p>
<p>Perhaps the real concern is with <em>information</em> privacy? Well, that's new too. The &#8220;right to privacy&#8221; was not coined until 1890, by future Chief Justice Louis Brandeis. The right to privacy would not be recognized by the Supreme Court until the landmark 1967 case, <em>Katz v. The United States</em>.</p>
<p>In some ways, informational privacy isn't a concern until the modern age, because few people had the technology or knowhow to write anything down. Still, privacy regulations did not catch up with literacy until the mid 19th Century. For instance, while there were scattered concerns with the very first census in 1790, the results were still posted publicly so that citizens could double-check their accuracy [<a target="_blank" href="http://www.census.gov/prod/2003pubs/conmono2.pdf">PDF</a>].</p>
<p>&#8220;So I'm not saying that we shouldn't be interested in privacy, but I am suggesting to you that it's an accident, in some respect, of the urban revolution,&#8221; concludes Cerf.</p>
<p>Now, our liberty-loving readers could argue that the invention of privacy is just a natural evolution of social advancement, like democracy or medicine. "Civilization is the progress toward a society of privacy," <a target="_blank" href="http://books.google.com/books?id=kW3b020OVZ8C&amp;pg=PA176&amp;dq=%22civilization+is+the+progress%22+privacy&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=xyKNUq-FLoSWiQKkioHwDA&amp;ved=0CDEQ6AEwAQ#v=onepage&amp;q=%22civilization%20is%20the%20progress%22%20privacy&amp;f=false">said</a> libertarian heroine, Ayn Rand.</p>
<p>Cerf's comments have gotten pickup due to <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/18/google-pays-17-million-settlement-over-no-harm-browser-privacy-violations/">increased scrutiny</a> of Google's ad targeting policies and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/06/05/google-glass-should-be-banned-for-privacy-reasons-say-one-in-five-uk-residents-per-new-survey/">Glass project</a>. Government's around the world want to rein Google's ambitious mission to organize the world's information.</p>
<p>Regardless of the law, Cerf's point was that transparency &#8220;is something we're gonna have to live through.&#8221; It's quite difficult to find technological solutions to privacy. Savvy data scientists are <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/18/we-must-choose-privacy-or-medical-breakthroughs/">getting increasingly clever at identifying individuals</a> from anonymous datasets. Even if an individual chooses to keep information private, its<a target="_blank" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/11/facebook-likes-personality-traits_n_2854403.html"> getting easier</a> to ID someone's tastes, gender, and sexual orientation from the public activity of their share-happy friends.</p>
<p>The more sustainable solution maybe to rekindle the social norms we had around tolerance. Like Cerf, I lived in a small town (in Brazil); knowing everything about everyone else isn't the end of the world. In some ways, it's beneficial. We often suffer alone unnecessarily.</p>
<p>Perhaps, there is something in our history that can help us adapt to a life that is, once again, radically transparent.</p>
<p>[<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/1818985346/sizes/l/in/photolist-3LJLYj-3Mc8Ji-3McavP-3MgrCw-3MQQed-3MTHVL-3T2eob-48viga-4frXiw-4p6Q7L-4p6QqC-57cyyQ-5uoev9-63PfgB-64eWai-64fK4P-64jZjS-64k3R5-65fsGL-65ftTw-6sM6sz-6sNCWP-6sNHQD-6sNMsH-6sSR3U-6sSVqQ-6t9c7F-6t9cA8-6t9hmV-6tdjPq-6tiMSy-6tsAMa-6tsAZD-6twJmQ-6twJEw-6uwmqZ-6uwn3p-6uwoLT-6uAzjQ-6wPoiF-6wTyAE-6QwDMG-6YXHw9-7ggPxv-7j4Eiv-7j8yrb-7kZ5jT-7nvkP2-7nYP42-e4yvdi-fti73F/"><em>Image Credit: Flickr Joi</em></a>]</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917960/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=msvyqeHTTl4:unnrbcHa-Ss:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=msvyqeHTTl4:unnrbcHa-Ss:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=msvyqeHTTl4:unnrbcHa-Ss:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=msvyqeHTTl4:unnrbcHa-Ss:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=msvyqeHTTl4:unnrbcHa-Ss:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=msvyqeHTTl4:unnrbcHa-Ss:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=msvyqeHTTl4:unnrbcHa-Ss:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=msvyqeHTTl4:unnrbcHa-Ss:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/msvyqeHTTl4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/googles-cerf-says-privacy-may-be-an-anomaly-historically-hes-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/1818985346_1a4e83b3ce_b.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Google%26%238217%3Bs%20Cerf%20Says%20%26%238220%3BPrivacy%20May%20Be%20An%20Anomaly%26%238221%3B.%20Historically%2C%20He%26%238217%3Bs%26nbsp%3BRight.</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/1818985346_1a4e83b3ce_b.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/1818985346_1a4e83b3ce_b.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1818985346_1a4e83b3ce_b</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36fb0b62cd32125bebf1806040529d3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ferenstein</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/googles-cerf-says-privacy-may-be-an-anomaly-historically-hes-right/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Ribbon Is Building A Peer-To-Peer Payments For Consumers, No App Or Account Required</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/uZNGYzSfbLs/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/ribbon-is-building-a-peer-to-peer-payments-for-consumers-no-app-or-account-required/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 21:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ribbon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payments]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917651</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ribbon-payments.png?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="ribbon-payments" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Payments startup <a target="_blank" href="https://ribbon.co/">Ribbon</a>, which launched last year with a focus on making it easier to accept payments online across websites, blogs and social media services like Facebook and Twitter, is expanding in a new direction. The company is now working to develop a person-to-person payments service that will allow users to send money to friends over the web.
<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917651&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ribbon-payments.png?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="ribbon-payments" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Payments startup <a target="_blank" href="https://ribbon.co/">Ribbon</a>, which launched last year with a focus on making it easier to accept payments online across websites, blogs and social media services like Facebook and Twitter, is expanding in a new direction. The company is now working to develop a person-to-person payments service that will allow users to send money to friends over the web.</p>
<p>Though the company's main website at <a target="_blank" href="https://ribbon.co/">Ribbon.co</a> was reflecting what appeared to be an entirely new service, we understand that Ribbon's earlier, merchant-facing product is not being shut down in favor of the peer-to-peer payments product. In fact, it's still live <a target="_blank" href="https://o.ribbon.co/">here</a>. Instead, the consumer-facing version of Ribbon will arrive early next year to complement merchant service, potentially furthering Ribbon's reach.</p>
<p>Today, the majority of Ribbon merchants use the service on their own website, where it's easy to add a line of code in order to have a fully functional checkout experience set up in a matter of minutes. As of last month, Ribbon had 10,000 merchants using the product, and saw 150,000 unique buyers who visited checkout pages. The company also recently scored Target as a customer, who used Ribbon as part of a Facebook campaign.</p>
<p>The consumer version of Ribbon, however, is not about buying and selling, but rather about moving money quickly between two people. It will include a responsive, web-based version of Ribbon which you can use without having to first establish an account &#8211; basically, it's a web-based Venmo, from what we're hearing. You'll be able to quickly type in a URL, and then dash off your payment and note to a recipient from a single webpage.</p>
<p>This new product would compete more broadly with things like PayPal, Google Wallet or Square Cash, for example, all of which have a consumer angle to their services intended for those who need to pay back friends or family. (PayPal also <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/26/paypal-acquires-payments-gateway-braintree-for-800m-in-cash/">acquired</a> Venmo maker Braintree this fall, for $800 million in cash). But unlike Square Wallet or Google Wallet's Gmail integration, the new Ribbon service for consumers is designed to work on the web or mobile web, not <em>within</em> email. Nor will it work over text.</p>
<p>An earlier version of the updated Ribbon <a target="_blank" href="https://ribbon.co/about">website</a> (now pulled) mentioned that the service would support Visa, MasterCard, Discover, and American Express, and noted that payments could be sent via the web or mobile. The site has changed again today, offering still few details on the product, but adding that the service won't hold your money for a week before you cash out, and won't freeze accounts without explanation &#8211; something PayPal <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/10/26/wepay-ice-paypal/">seems</a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/11/paypal-jay-lake-apology/">fond of</a>.</p>
<p>Interested users are also invited to sign up for invitation <a target="_blank" href="https://ribbon.co/">here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/ribbon-is-building-a-peer-to-peer-payments-for-consumers-no-app-or-account-required/ribbon-black/" rel="attachment wp-att-917964"></a></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.5;">When Ribbon first <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/20/ribbon-a-bit-ly-with-payments-brings-simplified-checkout-to-any-platform/">launched</a> one of its key features was its ability to offer a different kind of payment experience &#8211; one where payments could operate &#8220;in-stream&#8221; on social media sites like Facebook or Twitter. But as the company grew, it seemed that merchants were more often using Ribbon's embedding function on their own websites instead. </span></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.5;">This spring, Ribbon also ran into trouble when it </span><a>expanded</a><span style="line-height:1.5;"> its service to Twitter, allowing for in-stream payments on Twitter's site. But </span><a>Twitter shut Ribbon down</a><span style="line-height:1.5;"> </span><span style="line-height:1.5;">almost immediately after its public debut, forcing the company to go back to the drawing board and then </span><a>relaunch</a><span style="line-height:1.5;"> using Twitter's Product Cards. No longer was Ribbon able to execute on its vision of real &#8220;in-stream&#8221; payments on Twitter's platform &#8211; a factor that likely played into its decision to think about other areas in the payments space where it could have an impact.</span></p>
<p>We should hear more about the consumer service after the holidays. When reached for comment, Ribbon co-founder Hany Rashwan confirmed Ribbon's new direction, and provided the following statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;For the last few months, we've been working on a new version of Ribbon that takes the technology and ideas that we've already built, and uses them in a different way. We're not ready to fully announce the new Ribbon, but are excited for people to use a payment system built for +today's age and technology.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="line-height:1.5;">Ribbon is backed by $1.75 million in funding from AngelPad, Sierra Ventures, InterWest Partners, Draper Associates and others.  </span></p>
<p><em>Update: 150,000 buyers refers to unique visitors, not necessarily those performing transactions. The article has been changed to clarify this. </em></p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917651/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uZNGYzSfbLs:CAVDergoJ2Y:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uZNGYzSfbLs:CAVDergoJ2Y:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uZNGYzSfbLs:CAVDergoJ2Y:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uZNGYzSfbLs:CAVDergoJ2Y:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=uZNGYzSfbLs:CAVDergoJ2Y:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uZNGYzSfbLs:CAVDergoJ2Y:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=uZNGYzSfbLs:CAVDergoJ2Y:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uZNGYzSfbLs:CAVDergoJ2Y:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/uZNGYzSfbLs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/ribbon-is-building-a-peer-to-peer-payments-for-consumers-no-app-or-account-required/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ribbon-payments.png" type="image/png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Ribbon%20Is%20Building%20A%20Peer-To-Peer%20Payments%20For%20Consumers%2C%20No%20App%20Or%20Account%26nbsp%3BRequired</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ribbon-payments.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ribbon-payments.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ribbon-payments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5225bb627e112543aa03bf3b2958be3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarahintampa</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ribbon-black.png?w=628" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ribbon-black</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/ribbon-is-building-a-peer-to-peer-payments-for-consumers-no-app-or-account-required/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Now Sells T-Shirts That Claim Google's Chrome Steals Your Data</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/JNdyvUiCgVo/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/microsoft-now-sells-t-shirts-that-claim-googles-chrome-steals-your-data/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 21:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scroogled]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917928</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_12h53_28.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="2013-11-20_12h53_28" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Microsoft has started to sell t-shirts, hats, mugs, and sweatshirts that bear slogans from its Scroogled campaign that needles Google as bad on privacy. I confirmed with the company that the clothing line was released today. It&#8217;s more than cheeky. Here&#8217;s one of the offered shirts, bearing a statement that you can also get on a mug if you so desire: Yes, that&#8217;s the Chrome logo sitting on top of text that says that you should really kick back as your data is stolen. Oh my. Google is not going to be happy with this, I presume. Scroogled, as you certainly know, is a campaign by Microsoft to paint Google in a negative light when it comes to things like Gmail&#8217;s automatic scanning of incoming email to target advertisements. Google maintains that it doesn&#8217;t do so for sensitive categories such as bankruptcy. Microsoft also scans incoming email, but only to weed out malware and the like. This has always felt like a small distinction to me. A recent Google response to Microsoft&#8217;s claims went as follows: &#8220;Ad targeting in Gmail is fully automated, and no humans read your email or Google Account information in order to show you advertisements or related information. [...] We also don&#8217;t deliver ads based on sensitive information, such as race, religion, sexual orientation, health, or sensitive financial categories.&#8221; Still, Microsoft is pushing on with the campaign with apparent gusto. You don&#8217;t release a clothing line like this if you don&#8217;t want to make a little noise. The above shirt will knock you back $12, if you were curious. Google has had a few recent scraps with the law on the privacy front, including a recent $17 million fine that it paid over its changing Safari settings. The fine was token, given its size when compared to Google&#8217;s wealth as a company. Microsoft and Google have had a rough year, fighting over email, YouTube, and more. Given their huge competitive surface area &#8212; from selling music, to search, to mobile operating systems, and so forth &#8212; that&#8217;s not surprising. Still, Microsoft appears more willing to sling mud. Top Image Credit: Flickr<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917928&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_12h53_28.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="2013-11-20_12h53_28" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Microsoft has <a target="_blank" href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msusa/en_US/cat/Scroogled/categoryID.67575900">started to sell</a> t-shirts, hats, mugs, and sweatshirts that bear slogans from its Scroogled campaign that needles Google as bad on privacy. I confirmed with the company that the clothing line was released today.</p>
<p>It's more than cheeky. Here's one of the offered shirts, bearing a statement that you can also get on a mug if you so desire:</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_12h26_45.jpg"></a></p>
<p>Yes, that's the Chrome logo sitting on top of text that says that you should really kick back as your data is stolen. Oh my. Google is not going to be happy with this, I presume.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_13h16_19.jpg"></a></p>
<p>Scroogled, as you certainly know, is a campaign by Microsoft to paint Google in a negative light when it comes to things like Gmail's automatic scanning of incoming email to target advertisements. Google maintains that it doesn't do so for sensitive categories such as bankruptcy. Microsoft also scans incoming email, but only to weed out malware and the like. This has always felt like a small distinction to me.</p>
<p>A <a target="_blank" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-2487660/Google-snoops-email-uses-private-details-sell-adverts-Microsoft-claims.html#ixzz2jmuZIEo4">recent Google response</a> to Microsoft's claims went as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Ad targeting in Gmail is fully automated, and no humans read your email or Google Account information in order to show you advertisements or related information. [...] We also don't deliver ads based on sensitive information, such as race, religion, sexual orientation, health, or sensitive financial categories.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Still, Microsoft is pushing on with the campaign with apparent gusto. You don't release a clothing line like this if you don't want to make a little noise. The above shirt will <a target="_blank" href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msusa/en_US/pdp/Scroogled-Keep-Calm-T-shirt/productID.291425700">knock you back $12</a>, if you were curious.</p>
<p>Google has had a few recent scraps with the law on the privacy front, including a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/18/google-pays-17-million-settlement-over-no-harm-browser-privacy-violations/">recent $17 million fine</a> that it paid over its changing Safari settings. The fine was token, given its size when compared to Google's wealth as a company.</p>
<p>Microsoft and Google have <a target="_blank" href="http://thenextweb.com/insider/2013/05/17/rivals-a-short-history-of-google-and-microsoft-long-burning-turf-and-platform-war/">had a rough year</a>, fighting over email, YouTube, and more. Given their huge competitive surface area - from selling music, to search, to mobile operating systems, and so forth - that's not surprising. Still, Microsoft appears more willing to sling mud.</p>
<p><em>Top Image Credit: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/runneralan/">Flickr</a></em></p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917928/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JNdyvUiCgVo:rVrcQ7_ioGc:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JNdyvUiCgVo:rVrcQ7_ioGc:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JNdyvUiCgVo:rVrcQ7_ioGc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JNdyvUiCgVo:rVrcQ7_ioGc:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=JNdyvUiCgVo:rVrcQ7_ioGc:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JNdyvUiCgVo:rVrcQ7_ioGc:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=JNdyvUiCgVo:rVrcQ7_ioGc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JNdyvUiCgVo:rVrcQ7_ioGc:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/JNdyvUiCgVo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/microsoft-now-sells-t-shirts-that-claim-googles-chrome-steals-your-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_12h53_28.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Microsoft%20Now%20Sells%20T-Shirts%20That%20Claim%20Google%26%238217%3Bs%20Chrome%20Steals%20Your%26nbsp%3BData</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_12h53_28.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_12h53_28.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-11-20_12h53_28</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a3a71bf0d3d22efa0db4b77936a066b8?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexjameswilhelm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_12h26_45.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-11-20_12h26_45</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_13h16_19.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-11-20_13h16_19</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/microsoft-now-sells-t-shirts-that-claim-googles-chrome-steals-your-data/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Tumblr for iOS 7 Sharpens A Great Design Without Diluting It, And Brings Focus Onto Activity Stream</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/jKrWnzf16n8/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/tumblr-for-ios-7-sharpens-a-great-design-without-diluting-it-and-brings-focus-onto-activity-stream/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 20:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Panzarino]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tumblr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios 7]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917924</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-12-40-01-pm.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 12.40.01 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Today, Tumblr is releasing its redesigned client for iPhone and iPad, bringing along a completely refreshed look and feel for iOS 7. The redesign, unlike some others to come out of Apple&#8217;s big shakeup, manages to maintain the core of what makes Tumblr so attractive to its millions of users. The new Tumblr app will look fairly familiar to users, as the trademark blue remains, as does the post format that puts the focus on the content being shared, with a slim bar of interface hovering behind, helpful but not intrusive. What&#8217;s gained this time is a big focus on the Activity stream, which was previously buried underneath the account tab. Moving the Activity stream out to the tabs, says Tumblr&#8217;s Creative Director Peter Vidani, was a decision that was made simply because it was so popular. Users, especially heavy users, were checking it a lot to see the latest likes, replies, reblogs and follows incessantly. Moving that out to the tab bar is a statement about how important this stream is. It&#8217;s the feedback loop, the thing that keeps you coming back to the app obsessively, just to see if you&#8217;ve got some new interactions to check out. The same concept drives feeds in other apps like Twitter&#8217;s Connect tab. If you&#8217;re getting feedback, you&#8217;re going to keep producing content (or re-blogging it) to get more. Call it Pavlovian, but it makes a lot of sense. In addition to the Activity stream&#8217;s promotion, posting has also gotten a complete revamp. Tapping the new post icon gives you access to six large and easier to tap icons for all of the content types. Each of the composition screens has also gotten a revamp, but the photo sharing option is probably the most different. The photo capture screen is really cleverly done, and now dumps you onto a grid of images from your camera roll, rather than allowing you to choose immediately between the roll and the camera. This, Vidani says, was done after the data suggested that people dipped into their albums for images to post far more than they went to the camera. But the camera experience isn&#8217;t neglected — there&#8217;s a square near the bottom with a camera icon that displays a live view of your phone&#8217;s camera, inviting you to shoot an image if you choose. It&#8217;s neatly done. Nicely detailed touches are scattered throughout. There are<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917924&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-12-40-01-pm.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 12.40.01 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Today, Tumblr is releasing its redesigned client for iPhone and iPad, bringing along a completely refreshed look and feel for iOS 7. The redesign, unlike some others to come out of Apple's big shakeup, manages to maintain the core of what makes Tumblr so attractive to its millions of users.</p>
<p>The new Tumblr app will look fairly familiar to users, as the trademark blue remains, as does the post format that puts the focus on the content being shared, with a slim bar of interface hovering behind, helpful but not intrusive. What's gained this time is a big focus on the Activity stream, which was previously buried underneath the account tab.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/iphone5_activity-presskit.png"></a></p>
<p>Moving the Activity stream out to the tabs, says Tumblr's Creative Director Peter Vidani, was a decision that was made simply because it was so popular. Users, especially heavy users, were checking it a lot to see the latest likes, replies, reblogs and follows incessantly. Moving that out to the tab bar is a statement about how important this stream is. It's the feedback loop, the thing that keeps you coming back to the app obsessively, just to see if you've got some new interactions to check out. The same concept drives feeds in other apps like Twitter's Connect tab. If you're getting feedback, you're going to keep producing content (or re-blogging it) to get more. Call it Pavlovian, but it makes a lot of sense.</p>
<p>In addition to the Activity stream's promotion, posting has also gotten a complete revamp. Tapping the new post icon gives you access to six large and easier to tap icons for all of the content types. Each of the composition screens has also gotten a revamp, but the photo sharing option is probably the most different.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/iphone5_compose-presskit.png"></a></p>
<p>The photo capture screen is really cleverly done, and now dumps you onto a grid of images from your camera roll, rather than allowing you to choose immediately between the roll and the camera. This, Vidani says, was done after the data suggested that people dipped into their albums for images to post far more than they went to the camera. But the camera experience isn't neglected - there's a square near the bottom with a camera icon that displays a live view of your phone's camera, inviting you to shoot an image if you choose. It's neatly done.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20-12_34_11.gif"></a></p>
<p>Nicely detailed touches are scattered throughout. There are now &#8216;toast' notifications that pop up while you're using the app to tell you if you've gotten a reblog or like. This behavior was more difficult to implement on previous versions of iOS, Vidani says, because it was tough to get the metaphors to make sense. iOS 7 allows for much more freedom to &#8216;play with shapes', letting the tab bar expand outwards to display the notification naturally.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/iphone5_explore-presskit.png"></a></p>
<p>The Explore screen has also gotten a nice refresh, with a line of hashtag topics near the top that use iOS 7&#8242;s dynamics engine to stretch and scroll quirkily. They're also animated, displaying video or gif content to catch the eye.</p>
<p>Vidani says that Tumblr has been making an effort to make posting more of a &#8216;casual' function. This, he says, is in keeping with Tumblr's design directives to &#8216;keep it small'. Even the number of things that a user is being asked to assimilate on the screen at once is given careful consideration.</p>
<p>This fits in thematically with other interesting experiments in the online publishing world. Medium, for instance, leverages the lowered barriers that come from making the act of creating a post the same as publishing a post. It's a one-for-one equation. When you make a post in Tumblr, the post screen looks exactly like it will once you hit go. There's no &#8216;rendering' process here like there is with some platforms like WordPress. Yes, there are limitations to this approach, but it also keeps the threshold for self-publishing to the bare minimum.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/iphone5_dashboard-presskit.png"></a></p>
<p>Services like Tumblr (or Twitter, for that matter) have taught a generation of content creators that publishing things to the web can be something we do from anywhere, at any time, without a major production. This redesign keeps to that tenet well.</p>
<p>The overall feel of the Tumblr app for iOS 7 remains close to its previous editions at heart. Everything has been touched, massaged or redesigned, but it doesn't feel foreign. &#8220;We thought hard about how to apply the feel [of iOS 7] without compromising what we know to be Tumblr, what users know to be Tumblr,&#8221; says Vidani. From our brief time with the app, that appears to be true. It's a solid, clever and beautiful update that has found a home on iOS 7 without selling all of its belongings to buy it.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917924/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jKrWnzf16n8:f_Nga2xylFo:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jKrWnzf16n8:f_Nga2xylFo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jKrWnzf16n8:f_Nga2xylFo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jKrWnzf16n8:f_Nga2xylFo:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=jKrWnzf16n8:f_Nga2xylFo:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jKrWnzf16n8:f_Nga2xylFo:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=jKrWnzf16n8:f_Nga2xylFo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=jKrWnzf16n8:f_Nga2xylFo:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/jKrWnzf16n8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/tumblr-for-ios-7-sharpens-a-great-design-without-diluting-it-and-brings-focus-onto-activity-stream/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-12-40-01-pm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Tumblr%20for%20iOS%207%20Sharpens%20A%20Great%20Design%20Without%20Diluting%20It%2C%20And%20Brings%20Focus%20Onto%20Activity%26nbsp%3BStream</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-12-40-01-pm.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-12-40-01-pm.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 12.40.01 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b801d387d4af3749fed05f0f2e82690f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gre9del</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/iphone5_activity-presskit.png?w=360" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iphone5_activity-presskit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/iphone5_compose-presskit.png?w=360" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iphone5_compose-presskit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20-12_34_11.gif?w=360" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-11-20 12_34_11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/iphone5_explore-presskit.png?w=360" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iphone5_explore-presskit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/iphone5_dashboard-presskit.png?w=360" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iphone5_dashboard-presskit</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/tumblr-for-ios-7-sharpens-a-great-design-without-diluting-it-and-brings-focus-onto-activity-stream/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Coin, Kicking Credit Cards To The Curb, Answers A Few Questions</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/s_67n8TKKPU/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/coin-kicking-credit-cards-to-the-curb-answers-a-few-questions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 20:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917614</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/coin.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="coin" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />YC-backed Coin, the electronic credit card that stores multiple cards on one Bluetooth device, made a big splash last week <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/14/coin-the-electronic-credit-card-reaches-its-pre-order-goal-in-40-minutes/">blowing past its $50,000 pre-order in less than 40 minutes</a>. 

Turns out, people not only want to buy more Coins but they want to know more about Coin, too. That said, the company is responding to consumer feedback, announcing a number of features that will be available in the first release. <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917614&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/coin.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="coin" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>YC-backed Coin, the electronic credit card that stores multiple cards on one Bluetooth device, made a big splash last week <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/14/coin-the-electronic-credit-card-reaches-its-pre-order-goal-in-40-minutes/">blowing past its $50,000 pre-order in less than 40 minutes</a>.</p>
<p>Turns out, people not only want to buy more Coins but they want to know more about Coin, too. That said, the company is responding to consumer feedback, announcing a number of features that will be available in the first release.</p>
<p>Most importantly, Coin will be equipped with an alarm that learns how many times your Coin is being swiped and alerts you if it believes there is fraudulent activity going on.</p>
<p>For example, your card may be swiped once by a merchant or waiter to pay for the transaction, and again to steal the information on your card. Traditionally, your bank or credit card company wouldn't notify you of the fraudulent activity until a transaction was completed in another city or in an odd way using your information.</p>
<p>Coin actually notifies you the moment the information might be stolen, allowing you to make an inquiry about the activity.</p>
<p>You can also lock down one particular card so that friends, waiters, or strangers can't swap to a different card on their own. The team has also revealed that Coin can work without being tied to a phone.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we released Coin we wanted to have a succinct message,&#8221; said founder Kanishk Parashar. &#8220;We just wanted to let our users know that yes, we understand your feedback and we have been designing these features all along, and that they will be available in the first release.&#8221;</p>
<p>Beyond the new features, Coin has also updated its FAQ to answer the influx of questions its been receiving since launching the pre-order.</p>
<p>Here are a few helpful answers:</p>
<p><strong>Q. Can someone accidentally change which card is selected on my Coin?</strong><br />
<em>A. We've designed the button to toggle cards in a way that makes it difficult to trigger a &#8220;press&#8221; unintentionally. Dropping a Coin, holding a Coin, sitting on a Coin, or putting the Coin in a check presenter at a restaurant will not inadvertently toggle the card that is selected.</em></p>
<p><strong>Q. What if my phone runs out of power or is in airplane mode? Will my Coin be useable?</strong><br />
<em>A. Yes, but you may need to unlock it if the Coin becomes deactivated due to being out of contact with your phone for too long.</em></p>
<p><strong>Q. How secure is Coin?</strong><br />
<em>A. Maintaining the integrity of your Coin's data is critical to your peace of mind. That's why our servers, mobile apps and the Coin itself use 128-bit or 256-bit encryption for all storage and communication (http and bluetooth). Additionally Coin can alert you in the event that you leave it somewhere.</em></p>
<p>Parashar also assured us that the Coin will be available throughout the rest of the campaign, for the next 24 days, with no cap on the amount of pre-orders made.</p>
<p>&#8220;It actually helps when we have more orders,&#8221; said Parashar. &#8220;It means that larger manufacturers will be willing to prioritize us and work with us.&#8221;</p>
<p>Interestingly, this is Parashar's first time running a hardware business, previously founding a software payments company called SmartMarket. It asked for both merchants and consumers to change behavior entirely by using a mobile only payments product. This is what led to Coin.</p>
<p>After realizing that the app was getting plenty of downloads, but not very frequent use as a payment method, Parashar decided to build a payment solution for consumer side only.</p>
<p>When asked if Coin would eventually morph into his grander scheme for payments, all digital on consumer and merchant side, Parashar simply said that Coin is currently focused on delivering the first version to consumers.</p>
<p>If you want to get some more information on Coin, head over <a target="_blank" href="https://onlycoin.com/support/faq/">here</a>.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='360' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/w9Sx34swEG0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917614/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=s_67n8TKKPU:0e2dowWGnEk:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=s_67n8TKKPU:0e2dowWGnEk:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=s_67n8TKKPU:0e2dowWGnEk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=s_67n8TKKPU:0e2dowWGnEk:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=s_67n8TKKPU:0e2dowWGnEk:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=s_67n8TKKPU:0e2dowWGnEk:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=s_67n8TKKPU:0e2dowWGnEk:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=s_67n8TKKPU:0e2dowWGnEk:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/s_67n8TKKPU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/coin-kicking-credit-cards-to-the-curb-answers-a-few-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/coin.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Coin%2C%20Kicking%20Credit%20Cards%20To%20The%20Curb%2C%20Answers%20A%20Few%26nbsp%3BQuestions</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/coin.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/coin.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">coin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/123a4c264172746af556b0c74c72b308?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">biggsismyboss</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/coin-kicking-credit-cards-to-the-curb-answers-a-few-questions/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Windows Phone Now Sees 10M Transactions And 500 New Apps Daily, Has Served 3B Total Downloads</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/eLXzNougvlA/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/windows-phone-now-sees-10m-transactions-and-500-new-apps-daily-has-served-3b-total-downloads/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows phone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917839</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_10h49_25.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="2013-11-20_10h49_25" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Today Instagram and Waze came to the Windows Phone platform, bringing two applications to Microsoft&#8217;s smartphone venture that it has long lacked. Microsoft also released a set of numbers that outline the platform&#8217;s growth, and yet modest size. Windows Phone has seen 3 billion applications downloads, a fine number for the platform, but something that pales in comparison to iOS&#8217;s more than 60 billion aggregate downloads. The platform tallies 10 million app transactions each day, or 300 million per month. That&#8217;s up from 9 million per day in September, and 6.66 million per day in June. According to the company, 500 new Windows Phone applications are uploaded daily. The release of Windows Phone 8 remains the crux moment for the platform, with &#8220;monthly paid app revenue&#8221; up 181% since its launch. Also in roughly the past year, app downloads have increased 290%. Windows Phone is small, but growing at healthy rates. The above figures indicate that there is likely enough user activity for developers to warrant the platform enough attention to build for it. However, Windows Phone remains especially small in its home market, the United States, a key application revenue source for iOS and Android developers. Its lack of popularity in that country likely tempers developer enthusiasm. Sales numbers for Windows Phone handsets are growing, often at triple digit paces on a year-over-year basis, but the platform was small enough a year ago that those figures don&#8217;t indicate rampaging growth that could rival iOS or Android on a unit volume basis anytime soon. The company still has most of its work in front of it: Unit volume must rise in the United States, and other issues such as developer lassitude persist.  The above all sums to the simple fact that Microsoft, through expense and struggle, has managed to build a mobile platform that has achieved something close to exit velocity. It wasn&#8217;t long ago that that wasn&#8217;t true, and that Windows Phone was more the butt of jokes than something for developers to begin to get to know. The Windows Phone story remains mixed, but I think it&#8217;s trending positive.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917839&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_10h49_25.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="2013-11-20_10h49_25" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Today <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/instagram-windows-phone/">Instagram and Waze came to the Windows Phone platform</a>, bringing two applications to Microsoft's smartphone venture that it has long lacked.</p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.5;">Microsoft also released a set of numbers that outline the platform's growth, and yet modest size. Windows Phone has seen 3 billion applications downloads, a fine number for the platform, but something that pales in comparison to iOS's more than 60 billion aggregate downloads.</span></p>
<p>The platform tallies 10 million app transactions each day, or 300 million per month. That's up from 9 million per day in September, and 6.66 million per day in June. According to the company, 500 new Windows Phone applications are uploaded daily.</p>
<p>The release of Windows Phone 8 remains the crux moment for the platform, with &#8220;monthly paid app revenue&#8221; up 181% since its launch. Also in roughly the past year, app downloads have increased 290%. Windows Phone is small, but growing at healthy rates.</p>
<p>The above figures indicate that there is likely enough user activity for developers to warrant the platform enough attention to build for it. However, Windows Phone remains especially small in its home market, the United States, a key application revenue source for iOS and Android developers. Its lack of popularity in that country likely tempers developer enthusiasm.</p>
<p>Sales numbers for Windows Phone handsets are growing, often at triple digit paces on a year-over-year basis, but the platform was small enough a year ago that those figures don't indicate rampaging growth that could rival iOS or Android on a unit volume basis anytime soon.</p>
<p>The company still has most of its work in front of it: Unit volume must rise in the United States, and other issues such as developer lassitude persist. </p>
<p>The above all sums to the simple fact that Microsoft, through expense and struggle, has managed to build a mobile platform that has achieved something close to exit velocity. It wasn't long ago that that wasn't true, and that Windows Phone was more the butt of jokes than something for developers to begin to get to know.</p>
<p>The Windows Phone story remains mixed, but I think it's trending positive.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917839/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=eLXzNougvlA:7T7oR_PjLj8:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=eLXzNougvlA:7T7oR_PjLj8:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=eLXzNougvlA:7T7oR_PjLj8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=eLXzNougvlA:7T7oR_PjLj8:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=eLXzNougvlA:7T7oR_PjLj8:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=eLXzNougvlA:7T7oR_PjLj8:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=eLXzNougvlA:7T7oR_PjLj8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=eLXzNougvlA:7T7oR_PjLj8:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/eLXzNougvlA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/windows-phone-now-sees-10m-transactions-and-500-new-apps-daily-has-served-3b-total-downloads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_10h49_25.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Windows%20Phone%20Now%20Sees%2010M%20Transactions%20And%20500%20New%20Apps%20Daily%2C%20Has%20Served%203B%20Total%26nbsp%3BDownloads</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_10h49_25.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_10h49_25.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-11-20_10h49_25</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a3a71bf0d3d22efa0db4b77936a066b8?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexjameswilhelm</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/windows-phone-now-sees-10m-transactions-and-500-new-apps-daily-has-served-3b-total-downloads/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Instagram For Windows Phone Photo Taking Controversy Explained</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/lauQPILwvjM/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/the-great-instagram-for-windows-phone-photo-taking-controversy-explained/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[instagram]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917890</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_11h36_38.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="2013-11-20_11h36_38" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Instagram made it onto the Windows Phone platform today as a beta and immediately, everyone lost their mind. You see, the Instagram app for Windows Phone defaults to an in-app screen that shows you the photos you have already taken. You can click on a little button to take a photo, but you are then scooted out of the application to the default camera application where you shoot the picture. Then you are scooted back into Instagram. It&#8217;s about as smooth as sandpaper. The iOS experience, for contrast, let&#8217;s you quickly shoot a picture inside the application itself, something that is fast, and far more seamless. People have pointed out the discrepancy, stating variously that you can&#8217;t take photos inside of the Windows Phone Instagram application. This is technically true. Others, incensed by the assertion, claim that you can, you just have to exit the application to do so. That&#8217;s not quite the same thing. The shitbag of all of this is that Windows Phone users have waited years for the application to land on their platform in an official capacity. And when it finally did, it was not as good as what the photo sharing service offers to others. You get to wait, and then you get less. The official line about this is that many Instagram users use photos that they have already taken, and given that Windows Phone devices have other pretty darn good photo taking applications, defaulting in-app to your photo roll makes sense. Not really, as if I am Instagraming a photo I&#8217;m hardly fretting about its crispness given that I am about to Sepia its brains out, but even still, it would be nice to have the same flow that I have on other platforms. Don&#8217;t make the choice for me, essentially. Instagram on iOS has been one of the largest mobile application success stories, ever. It worked. The version that Windows Phone users received today &#8211; albeit in beta, somehow &#8211; is less good than what other platforms have. No matter how you slice it, late and less good isn&#8217;t so great. Top Image Credit: Flickr<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917890&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_11h36_38.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="2013-11-20_11h36_38" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Instagram made it onto the Windows Phone platform today as a beta and immediately, everyone lost their mind.</p>
<p>You see, the Instagram app for Windows Phone defaults to an in-app screen that shows you the photos you have already taken. You can click on a little button to take a photo, but you are then scooted out of the application to the default camera application where you shoot the picture. Then you are scooted back into Instagram.</p>
<p>It's about as smooth as sandpaper. The iOS experience, for contrast, let's you quickly shoot a picture inside the application itself, something that is fast, and far more seamless.</p>
<p>People have pointed out the discrepancy, stating variously that you can't take photos inside of the Windows Phone Instagram application. This is technically true. Others, incensed by the assertion, claim that you <em>can</em>, you just have to exit the application to do so. That's not quite the same thing.</p>
<p>The shitbag of all of this is that Windows Phone users have waited years for the application to land on their platform in an official capacity. And when it finally did, it was not as good as what the photo sharing service offers to others. You get to wait, and then you get less.</p>
<p>The official line about this is that many Instagram users use photos that they have already taken, and given that Windows Phone devices have other pretty darn good photo taking applications, defaulting in-app to your photo roll makes sense. Not really, as if I am Instagraming a photo I'm hardly fretting about its crispness given that I am about to Sepia its brains out, but even still, it would be nice to have the same flow that I have on other platforms. Don't make the choice for me, essentially.</p>
<p>Instagram on iOS has been one of the largest mobile application success stories, ever. It worked. The version that Windows Phone users received today &#8211; albeit in beta, somehow &#8211; is less good than what other platforms have. No matter how you slice it, late and less good isn't so great.</p>
<p><em>Top Image Credit: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/janitors/">Flickr</a></em></p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917890/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=lauQPILwvjM:VO5kd_zN5NU:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=lauQPILwvjM:VO5kd_zN5NU:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=lauQPILwvjM:VO5kd_zN5NU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=lauQPILwvjM:VO5kd_zN5NU:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=lauQPILwvjM:VO5kd_zN5NU:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=lauQPILwvjM:VO5kd_zN5NU:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=lauQPILwvjM:VO5kd_zN5NU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=lauQPILwvjM:VO5kd_zN5NU:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/lauQPILwvjM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/the-great-instagram-for-windows-phone-photo-taking-controversy-explained/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_11h36_38.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">The%20Great%20Instagram%20For%20Windows%20Phone%20Photo%20Taking%20Controversy%26nbsp%3BExplained</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_11h36_38.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_11h36_38.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-11-20_11h36_38</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a3a71bf0d3d22efa0db4b77936a066b8?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexjameswilhelm</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/the-great-instagram-for-windows-phone-photo-taking-controversy-explained/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>After 15 Years Of Whipping The Llama's Ass, Winamp Shuts Down</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/c7_zBHVwphg/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/after-15-years-of-whipping-the-llamas-ass-winamp-shuts-down/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Winamp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mp3]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917854</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_1135.png?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="2013-11-20_1135" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />If you had a PC and you listened to MP3s in the late 90s, chances are you managed your playlists with <a target="_blank" href="http://winamp.com">Winamp</a>. Since then, Nullsoft sold Winamp to AOL (the parent company of TechCrunch) <a target="_blank" href="http://news.cnet.com/2100-1023-226540.html">for $80 million</a> and online music has changed quite a bit, but there was always something reassuring about the fact that Winamp was still hanging in there. So much for that. Winamp is shutting down. The website and all of Winamp's <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.winamp.com/2009/04/06/set-up-your-karaoke-using-winamp-online-services-songbook-lyri/">web services</a> will shut down on December 20 and the desktop player will no longer be available for download.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917854&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_1135.png?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="2013-11-20_1135" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>If you had a PC and you listened to MP3s in the late 90s, chances are you managed your playlists with <a target="_blank" href="http://winamp.com">Winamp</a>. Since then, Nullsoft sold Winamp to AOL (the parent company of TechCrunch) <a target="_blank" href="http://news.cnet.com/2100-1023-226540.html">for $80 million</a> and online music has changed quite a bit, but there was always something reassuring about the fact that Winamp was still hanging in there. So much for that. Winamp is shutting down. The website and all of Winamp's <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.winamp.com/2009/04/06/set-up-your-karaoke-using-winamp-online-services-songbook-lyri/">web services</a> will shut down on December 20 and the desktop player will no longer be available for download.</p>
<p>Even if you don't remember Winamp, you may remember the demo MP3 that played when you installed the app: &#8220;Winamp, it really whips the llama's ass.&#8221;</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/cKqKrH0O9yg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/winamp.png"></a>In an <a target="_blank" href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2012/06/winamp-how-greatest-mp3-player-undid-itself/">interview with Ars Technica</a> last year, Rob Lord, the first hire at Nullsoft and the first general manager of Winamp said that he believed that &#8220;there's no reason that Winamp couldn't be in the position that iTunes is in today if not for a few layers of mismanagement by AOL that started immediately upon acquisition.&#8221;</p>
<p>While AOL kept Winamp going – it released an Android version in 2010 and Winamp Sync for Mac, including a full player, <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.winamp.com/2011/10/26/introducing-winamp-for-mac-sync-beta/">launched in 2011</a> – there was never a clear sense of what was going on with the product. The Winamp blog, however, hasn't been updated <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.winamp.com/">for the last year</a> and judging from Ars' portrait of the company's fortunes from 2012, it seems like AOL never quite knew what to do with it.</p>
<p>If you still want a copy of Winamp, now is the time to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.winamp.com/help/Version_History#Winamp_5.66">download it</a> and to import those MP3s you downloaded from Napster back in 1999 into it.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917854/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=c7_zBHVwphg:Xn2YXxIzr80:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=c7_zBHVwphg:Xn2YXxIzr80:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=c7_zBHVwphg:Xn2YXxIzr80:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=c7_zBHVwphg:Xn2YXxIzr80:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=c7_zBHVwphg:Xn2YXxIzr80:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=c7_zBHVwphg:Xn2YXxIzr80:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=c7_zBHVwphg:Xn2YXxIzr80:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=c7_zBHVwphg:Xn2YXxIzr80:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/c7_zBHVwphg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/after-15-years-of-whipping-the-llamas-ass-winamp-shuts-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_1135.png" type="image/png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">After%2015%20Years%20Of%20Whipping%20The%20Llama%26%238217%3Bs%20Ass%2C%20Winamp%20Shuts%26nbsp%3BDown</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_1135.png?w=148" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/2013-11-20_1135.png?w=148" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-11-20_1135</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/55542aa717199728948f628edc1170b1?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fredericlardinois</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/winamp.png?w=238" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">winamp</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/after-15-years-of-whipping-the-llamas-ass-winamp-shuts-down/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Wallet Invades Your Physical One With A New Prepaid Debit Card</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/xRIwc47GF5U/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/google-wallet-invades-your-physical-one-with-a-new-prepaid-debit-card/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris Velazco]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google wallet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/google-wallet-card.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="google-wallet-card" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />For a while there a physical Google Wallet card seemed like the stuff of rumors, and then it looked like another project lost to the ages when former Wallet chief Osama Bedier (who purportedly pushed the concept) officially resigned from his post earlier this year. Larry Page's disapproval of the card after a buggy pre-launch demo certainly didn't help the project's chances either.

But here we are, months later, and Google has gone ahead with the project anyway.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917888&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/google-wallet-card.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="google-wallet-card" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>For a while there a physical Google Wallet card seemed like the stuff of rumors, and then it looked like another project lost to the ages when former Wallet chief Osama Bedier (who purportedly pushed the concept) officially resigned from his post earlier this year. Larry Page's disapproval of the card after a buggy pre-launch demo certainly didn't help the project's chances either.</p>
<p>But here we are, months later, and Google has gone ahead with the project anyway. The folks at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.droid-life.com/2013/11/20/google-wallet-card-is-official-wallet-users-can-sign-up-now-for-physical-cards/">Droid-Life</a> spotted the updated <a target="_blank" href="https://support.google.com/wallet/answer/3529204?hl=en&amp;ref_topic=3209987">Google support entry </a>first, which allows Google Wallet users to order their own physical Wallet cards - that first batch is expected to hit doorsteps in under two weeks. </p>
<p>Don't expect Google to be getting into the lending and collections game (but hell, could you imagine?) - this card is a purely prepaid affair, affording its users access to the funds that are currently stored in their Google Wallets. At first glance it doesn't seem like a game-changer considering most of the particulars will be familiar to anyone who already owns a debit card, but there are some neat Googlean touches here. According to a <a target="_blank" href="http://googlecommerce.blogspot.com/2013/11/receive-money-with-google-wallet-spend.html">newly-posted article</a> on Google's Commerce blog, there's a distinct lack of service fees tied to using the card, and users will get instant notifications on their phones when they've made a purchase (just like Simple).</p>
<p>So sure, if you have a Google Wallet account and it's got a few dollars ferreted away in it, there's really no reason <em>not</em> to get one. While it may be a low-risk action for you though, the card provides plenty of value to the folks in Mountain View - an earlier report from <a target="_blank" href="http://allthingsd.com/20130510/googles-wallet-plans-for-io-cloud-expansion-on-but-longtime-physical-card-plan-scuttled/">AllThingsD</a> painted Google's push into a more physical payment scheme as a way to gather more consumer purchasing data to help power its gigantic online advertising business. </p>
<p><em>This is a developing story, please refresh for updates.</em></p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917888/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xRIwc47GF5U:rBu4HDtlvio:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xRIwc47GF5U:rBu4HDtlvio:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xRIwc47GF5U:rBu4HDtlvio:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xRIwc47GF5U:rBu4HDtlvio:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=xRIwc47GF5U:rBu4HDtlvio:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xRIwc47GF5U:rBu4HDtlvio:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=xRIwc47GF5U:rBu4HDtlvio:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xRIwc47GF5U:rBu4HDtlvio:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/xRIwc47GF5U" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/google-wallet-invades-your-physical-one-with-a-new-prepaid-debit-card/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/google-wallet-card.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Google%20Wallet%20Invades%20Your%20Physical%20One%20With%20A%20New%20Prepaid%20Debit%26nbsp%3BCard</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/google-wallet-card.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/google-wallet-card.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">google-wallet-card</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ec2ac47d9dad53c2ae4f7882ae9bf6b9?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ctvelazco</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/google-wallet-invades-your-physical-one-with-a-new-prepaid-debit-card/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Takes You Through Middle-Earth, Providing Both An Eagle- And A Hobbit's-Eye View</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/QFm2NpBeBuo/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/google-takes-you-through-middle-earth-providing-both-an-eagle-and-a-hobbits-eye-view/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hobbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917855</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-1-54-03-pm.png?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 1.54.03 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Google has launched an ambitious Chrome experiment today, in <a target="_blank" href="http://googleblog.blogspot.ca/2013/11/bringing-hobbits-dwarves-and-dragons-to.html">partnership with The Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug</a>. It's an interactive updated version of those great handdrawn maps Tolkien included in his print edition of the works upon which these movies are based, that provides a guided tour of Middle-earth and the people, elves, trolls, wizards and other beasts that populate it.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917855&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-1-54-03-pm.png?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 1.54.03 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='360' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/BVvMGD8LNL0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>Google has launched an ambitious Chrome experiment today, in <a target="_blank" href="http://googleblog.blogspot.ca/2013/11/bringing-hobbits-dwarves-and-dragons-to.html">partnership with The Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug</a>. It's an interactive updated version of those great hand-drawn maps Tolkien included in his print edition of the works upon which these movies are based, that provides a guided tour of Middle-earth and the people, elves, trolls, wizards and other beasts that populate it.</p>
<p>Accompanied by soothing, presumably Elvish music, the narrated feature allows you to zoom into a 3D map of Middle-earth from a prospective somewhere just above the cloud line, to a current total of three locations (with more promised to follow). Once zoomed in, you can learn more about the place, why it's important, and who lives there. There's also a 3D exploreable render of each location, which is all done in CSS3 and WebGL – and it's designed to work on Chrome on Android, too, thanks to those technologies. If you're interested in the nerdier side, there's <a target="_blank" href="http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/casestudies/hobbit/">full post on how it was built here</a>.</p>
<p>Admittedly this is tech demo, and a promotional piece of marketing for The Hobbit sequel that's coming out in December, but it's also a pretty cool use of modern web technologies and a proof of just how powerful the browser can be, especially on mobile. And really any excuse for additional Tolkien geekery has me on board.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917855/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QFm2NpBeBuo:Ig91gh-EFiA:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QFm2NpBeBuo:Ig91gh-EFiA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QFm2NpBeBuo:Ig91gh-EFiA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QFm2NpBeBuo:Ig91gh-EFiA:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=QFm2NpBeBuo:Ig91gh-EFiA:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QFm2NpBeBuo:Ig91gh-EFiA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=QFm2NpBeBuo:Ig91gh-EFiA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QFm2NpBeBuo:Ig91gh-EFiA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/QFm2NpBeBuo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/google-takes-you-through-middle-earth-providing-both-an-eagle-and-a-hobbits-eye-view/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-1-54-03-pm.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/screen-shot-2013-11-20-at-1-54-03-pm.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-11-20 at 1.54.03 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/188039e12983eb749171a75cfd01378d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">etherin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/google-takes-you-through-middle-earth-providing-both-an-eagle-and-a-hobbits-eye-view/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Tencent Was Already A Covert Investor In Snapchat's Last Round</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/12j_yTTKJSA/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/tencent-snapchat/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim-Mai Cutler]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snapchat]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917700</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/snapchat-still.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="snapchat-still" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />While there are unverified rumors that Chinese mega-giant Tencent is interested in joining a fresh, large round for Snapchat, mainland China&#8217;s biggest social networking platform actually already secretly invested in the ephemeral messaging app. Tencent was an undisclosed minority participant in the company&#8217;s last $60 million round led by Institutional Venture Partners, according to sources familiar with the deal in both China and the U.S. Such a relationship is a win-win for both parties. Snapchat gets an powerful strategic partner if it wants to expand into Asia &#8212; especially mainland China, where other Western consumer Internet and mobile companies have stumbled like Google or are blocked like Facebook. Snapchat also gets to learn from the most successful social networking platform in the world aside from Facebook. Tencent, which is valued at $99.3 billion on public markets, has 815.6 million monthly active users on its messaging platform. Its upstart messaging app, Weixin or WeChat, has racked up 272 million monthly active users in the last two years or so. Tencent also said it sees 400 million photos uploaded per day according to a presentation the company gave at MIT over the weekend, more than the 350 million per day Facebook sees, according to a whitepaper published in September. In turn, Tencent absolutely has ambitions of being a global company, not one that&#8217;s limited to mainland China. CEO Pony Ma said back in May that internationalizing China&#8217;s consumer Internet companies, in the same way that the country&#8217;s manufacturing industry serves a global market, would be a &#8220;revolution.&#8221; Right now, WeChat is the company&#8217;s most visible shot of building a truly global product. The messaging app &#8212; which, by the way, is a fantastic product that&#8217;s ubiquitously used throughout China&#8217;s coastal cities &#8212; is growing internationally with help from the Chinese diaspora. But, like other powerful Asian messaging apps, it will have trouble expanding in the super-competitive U.S. market. Having a U.S. subsidiary, joint venture or large-scale strategic investment might make a lot more sense. This is a route Tencent has taken in the neighboring South Korean market after it acquired a 13.84% percent stake in Kakao Talk, the maker of South Korea&#8217;s leading mobile messaging app. It also successfully pulled off a strategy like this when it acquired a majority stake in Los Angeles-based, League of Legends-maker Riot Games in 2011 for $400 million. Notably, that was another deal where Snapchat board<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917700&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/snapchat-still.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="snapchat-still" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>While there are unverified rumors that Chinese mega-giant Tencent is interested in joining a fresh, large round for Snapchat, mainland China's biggest social networking platform actually already secretly invested in the ephemeral messaging app.</p>
<p>Tencent was an undisclosed minority participant in the company's last $60 million round led by Institutional Venture Partners, according to sources familiar with the deal in both China and the U.S.</p>
<p>Such a relationship is a win-win for both parties. Snapchat gets an powerful strategic partner if it wants to expand into Asia - especially mainland China, where other Western consumer Internet and mobile companies have stumbled like Google or are blocked like Facebook. </p>
<p>Snapchat also gets to learn from the most successful social networking platform in the world aside from Facebook. Tencent, which is valued at $99.3 billion on public markets, has 815.6 million monthly active users on its messaging platform. Its upstart messaging app, Weixin or WeChat, has racked up <a target="_blank" href="http://www.tencent.com/en-us/content/ir/news/2013/attachments/20131113.pdf">272 million monthly active users</a> in the last two years or so. Tencent also said it sees 400 million photos uploaded per day according to a presentation the company gave at MIT over the weekend, more than the <a target="_blank" href="https://fbcdn-dragon-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/851590_229753833859617_1129962605_n.pdf">350 million per day Facebook sees, according to a whitepaper published in September</a>. </p>
<p>In turn, Tencent absolutely has ambitions of being a global company, not one that's limited to mainland China. CEO Pony Ma <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/05/22/made-for-the-world-built-and-designed-in-china/">said back in May</a> that internationalizing China's consumer Internet companies, in the same way that the country's manufacturing industry serves a global market, would be a &#8220;revolution.&#8221;</p>
<p>Right now, WeChat is the company's most visible shot of building a truly global product. The messaging app - which, by the way, is a fantastic product that's ubiquitously used throughout China's coastal cities - is <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/06/13/messaging-apps/">growing internationally with help from the Chinese diaspora</a>. But, like other powerful Asian messaging apps, it will have trouble expanding in the super-competitive U.S. market. </p>
<p>Having a U.S. subsidiary, joint venture or large-scale strategic investment might make a lot more sense. This is a route Tencent has taken in the neighboring South Korean market after it <a target="_blank" href="http://technode.com/2013/10/23/tencent-has-invested-2-bn-dollars-in-overseas-markets-here-is-the-list/">acquired a 13.84% percent stake</a> in Kakao Talk, the maker of South Korea's leading mobile messaging app. It also successfully pulled off a strategy like this when it acquired a majority stake in Los Angeles-based, League of Legends-maker Riot Games in 2011 for $400 million. Notably, that was another deal where Snapchat board member Mitch Lasky helped broker the negotiations.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917700/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=12j_yTTKJSA:nu_7YsDP1RA:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=12j_yTTKJSA:nu_7YsDP1RA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=12j_yTTKJSA:nu_7YsDP1RA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=12j_yTTKJSA:nu_7YsDP1RA:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=12j_yTTKJSA:nu_7YsDP1RA:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=12j_yTTKJSA:nu_7YsDP1RA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=12j_yTTKJSA:nu_7YsDP1RA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=12j_yTTKJSA:nu_7YsDP1RA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/12j_yTTKJSA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/tencent-snapchat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/snapchat-still.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Tencent%20Was%20Already%20A%20Covert%20Investor%20In%20Snapchat%26%238217%3Bs%20Last%26nbsp%3BRound</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/snapchat-still.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/snapchat-still.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">snapchat-still</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c4dad53149dd9c712936e1b27c1c1e9f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimmaicutler</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/tencent-snapchat/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Pinterest, Stripe And MakerBot Investor Shana Fisher Joins A16Z As A Board Partner</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/HtbR8nL4M9I/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/pinterest-stripe-and-makerbot-investor-shana-fisher-joins-a16z-as-a-board-partner/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leena Rao]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917853</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/134222v1-max-250x250.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="134222v1-max-250x250" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/shana-fisher">Shana Fisher</a> is joining Andreessen Horowitz as a board partner, according to a <a target="_blank" href="http://bhorowitz.com/2013/11/20/the-shana-fisher-competitive-advantage/">blog post published</a> by A16Z founder Ben Horowitz today.

As Horowitz explains in his post, Fisher tends to keep a low profile in the VC world, but she's made some savvy bets early on a number of hot new technologies and companies, including Pinterest, Stripe, Makerbot, Vine, FiftyThree, and Refinery29. A16Z has previously backed Stripe, Pinterest and a few other of Fisher's investments.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917853&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/134222v1-max-250x250.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="134222v1-max-250x250" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/shana-fisher">Shana Fisher</a> is joining Andreessen Horowitz as a board partner, according to a <a target="_blank" href="http://bhorowitz.com/2013/11/20/the-shana-fisher-competitive-advantage/">blog post published</a> by A16Z founder Ben Horowitz today.</p>
<p>As Horowitz explains in his post, Fisher tends to keep a low profile in the VC world, but she's made some savvy bets early on a number of hot new technologies and companies, including Pinterest, Stripe, Makerbot, Vine, FiftyThree, and Refinery29. A16Z has previously backed Stripe, Pinterest and a few other of Fisher's investments.</p>
<p>Fisher, who is based in New York, started her career at Microsoft and went on to become a Vice President of Technology and Media M&amp;A at Allen &amp; Company. Following Allen &amp; Co, she led strategic planning and M&amp;A at IAC before founding her own early stage VC firm, High Line Venture Partners. You can read more about Fisher in this recent <a target="_blank" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/shana-fisher-star-investor-2013-11">Business Insider profile.</a></p>
<p>The board partner role seems to be expanding at A16Z&#8211;former Windows President Steven Sinofsky <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/08/22/former-windows-president-steven-sinofsky-joins-andreessen-horowitz/">joined Andreessen Horowitz</a> as a board partner in August. At the time, he explained to <a target="_blank" href="http://allthingsd.com/20130822/former-windows-head-sinofsky-joins-andreessen-horowitz-as-board-partner/">AllThingsD</a> that his role as board partner would be to represent the firm on the boards of portfolio companies, but he would not be considered a full-time member of the firm.</p>
<p>Other board partners include Zillow CEO Spencer Rascoff, Blake Krikorian, John Jack, and Rod Johnson. We're assuming Fisher's role will be similar, and she'll continue to make investments on behalf of High Line.</p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917853/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HtbR8nL4M9I:0QhY_QgGYFQ:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HtbR8nL4M9I:0QhY_QgGYFQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HtbR8nL4M9I:0QhY_QgGYFQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HtbR8nL4M9I:0QhY_QgGYFQ:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=HtbR8nL4M9I:0QhY_QgGYFQ:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HtbR8nL4M9I:0QhY_QgGYFQ:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=HtbR8nL4M9I:0QhY_QgGYFQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=HtbR8nL4M9I:0QhY_QgGYFQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/HtbR8nL4M9I" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/pinterest-stripe-and-makerbot-investor-shana-fisher-joins-a16z-as-a-board-partner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/134222v1-max-250x250.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Pinterest%2C%20Stripe%20And%20MakerBot%20Investor%20Shana%20Fisher%20Joins%20A16Z%20As%20A%20Board%26nbsp%3BPartner</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/134222v1-max-250x250.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/134222v1-max-250x250.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">134222v1-max-250x250</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bbce6c3c48f821c81c019600a5589ae6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">leena</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/pinterest-stripe-and-makerbot-investor-shana-fisher-joins-a16z-as-a-board-partner/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-Driving Cars Not Ready Until At Least 2020, Says Nissan To Congress</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/7_8B3EtklWI/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/self-driving-cars-congress-2020/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 18:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gregory Ferenstein]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=917862</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/8190954243_099f534ebb_z.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="8190954243_099f534ebb_z" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Humans will still be driving cars &#8220;for the foreseeable future,&#8221; said a Senior General Motors official at a congressional hearing on robotic cars. Nissan has vowed to put them on the road in 2020, but Carnegie Mellon&#8217;s Raj Rajkumar says humans will still need to assist the car for probably another decade. &#8220;Only sometime in the 2020s will a fully autonomous system that does not require a human to be in the driver’s seat become feasible.” It&#8217;s hard to overstate how much of a gift self-driving cars will be to society. Director of the Michigan Department of Transportation, Kirk Steudle, estimated that they could prevent many of the 32,000+ traffic accidents and 2.2 million injuries annually. To speed up testing, Google flexed its considerable political muscle to get its own robotic cars legalized in California. For our readers who want to procrastinate at work, the The New Yorker has a nice long read of the design process of Google&#8217;s self-driving cars. Not every lawmaker followed carmakers down the techno-optimists gravy train. “First, it&#8217;s hard for me to fathom a car in New York City being without a driver,” said Rep. Sires, who expressed skepticism about automated cars. “I mean, it&#8217;s hard enough with a driver. So, you know, trying to visualize this is very difficult.” Probably the boldest pronouncement came from GM&#8217;s VP of Sustainable and Global Regulatory affairs. “I think it&#8217;s going to create jobs ultimately,” he argued. That may be true, but it&#8217;s also going completely gut the taxi industry and the inflated car industry based on individual ownership. Despite technical challenges getting cars on the road by 2020, Senior Manager of Technology Planning at Nissan Andy Christensen, said &#8220;The timeframe is challenging, but we believe achievable.&#8221; [Image Credit: Flickr User jurvetson]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&#038;blog=24588526&#038;post=917862&#038;subd=tctechcrunch2011&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="210" height="158" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/8190954243_099f534ebb_z.jpg?w=210&amp;h=158&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-river-article-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="8190954243_099f534ebb_z" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Humans will still be driving cars &#8220;for the foreseeable future,&#8221; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.detroitnews.com/article/20131119/AUTO01/311190072#ixzz2lC5duWxC">said</a> a Senior General Motors official at a congressional hearing on robotic cars. Nissan has vowed to put them on the road in 2020, but Carnegie Mellon's Raj Rajkumar says humans will still need to assist the car for probably another decade. &#8220;Only sometime in the 2020s will a fully autonomous system that does not require a human to be in the driver's seat become feasible."</p>
<p>It's hard to overstate how much of a gift self-driving cars will be to society. Director of the Michigan Department of Transportation, Kirk Steudle, estimated that they could prevent many of the 32,000+ traffic accidents and 2.2 million injuries annually.</p>
<p>To speed up testing, Google <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/09/24/how-googles-powerful-lobby-legalized-driverless-cars-in-california/">flexed</a> its considerable political muscle to get its own robotic cars legalized in California. For our readers who want to procrastinate at work, the The New Yorker has a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2013/11/25/131125fa_fact_bilger?currentPage=all">nice long read</a> of the design process of Google's self-driving cars.</p>
<p>Not every lawmaker followed carmakers down the techno-optimists gravy train. "First, it's hard for me to fathom a car in New York City being without a driver," said Rep. Sires, who expressed skepticism about automated cars. "I mean, it's hard enough with a driver. So, you know, trying to visualize this is very difficult."</p>
<p>Probably the boldest pronouncement came from GM's VP of Sustainable and Global Regulatory affairs. "I think it's going to create jobs ultimately," he argued. That may be true, but it's also going completely gut the taxi industry and the inflated car industry based on individual ownership.</p>
<p>Despite technical challenges getting cars on the road by 2020, Senior Manager of Technology Planning at Nissan Andy Christensen, said &#8220;The timeframe is challenging, but we believe achievable.&#8221;</p>
<p>[<em>Image Credit: Flickr User <a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/jurvetson/8190954243/sizes/z/in/photolist-dtNMk2-87P2XP-7HfQVq-eBWbNx-dQ9THk-dgx5FJ-8hoi5X-bBhSJ4-a7axcK-ceKNfU-bA2Umn-dUzZ2v-cnuExU-8oBFAB-7SpsgC-dfb6aH-a97Qe4-apK7YK-daq3BZ-chEjh3-7AMB2P-goRU4A-dppxXW-d1p5wS-d5bXvS-f3pej9-csUc7h-cKsCHw-bpcUw6-9uSFg7-focKZC-gubA4C-fp342M-cEtrZw-dMCVAz-brxoKP-bP7Kyx-d7zx9U-9Awwzb-deiZRC-d2erAb-fNDsBU-7TTe42-fMUiHL-aMsuCk-g6K6Gv-cJzVwS-fMUaWf-fNDfcu-fNDWF1-fPPqP7/">jurvetson</a></em>]<em><br />
</em></p><br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/917862/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7_8B3EtklWI:EbFibWIJq6k:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7_8B3EtklWI:EbFibWIJq6k:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7_8B3EtklWI:EbFibWIJq6k:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7_8B3EtklWI:EbFibWIJq6k:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=7_8B3EtklWI:EbFibWIJq6k:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7_8B3EtklWI:EbFibWIJq6k:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=7_8B3EtklWI:EbFibWIJq6k:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7_8B3EtklWI:EbFibWIJq6k:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/7_8B3EtklWI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/self-driving-cars-congress-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/8190954243_099f534ebb_z.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">Self-Driving%20Cars%20Not%20Ready%20Until%20At%20Least%202020%2C%20Says%20Nissan%20To%26nbsp%3BCongress</media:title></media:content>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/8190954243_099f534ebb_z.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/8190954243_099f534ebb_z.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">8190954243_099f534ebb_z</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36fb0b62cd32125bebf1806040529d3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ferenstein</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/20/self-driving-cars-congress-2020/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
