<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='http://feeds.theguardian.com/xsl/eng/rss.xsl'?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>World news and comment from the Guardian | theguardian.com</title><link>http://www.theguardian.com/world</link><description>Latest news and features from theguardian.com, the world's leading liberal voice</description><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. 2013</copyright><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 01:15:49 GMT</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 01:15:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><image><title>World news and comment from the Guardian | theguardian.com</title><url>http://static.guim.co.uk/images/theguardian-rss-logo.png</url><link>http://www.theguardian.com/world</link></image><item><title>Omens good for Iran nuclear deal at second bite</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ec0d66/sc/20/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0C20A130Cnov0C210Ciran0Enuclear0Etalks0Egeneva0Eprogress/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/2453?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Airan-nuclear-talks-geneva-progress%3A2000795&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Iran+%28News%29%2CNuclear+power+%28Environment%29%2CJohn+Kerry%2CUS+news%2CNuclear+weapons+%28News%29%2CMiddle+East+and+North+Africa+%28News%29+MENA%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEnergy%2CUSA+HSBC&amp;c6=Julian+Borger%2CSaeed+Kamali+Dehghan&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F21+01%3A08&amp;c8=2000795&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Omens+good+for+Iran+nuclear+deal+at+second+bite&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FIran" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Foreign ministers ready to fly to Geneva as diplomats make further progress on draft agreement over uranium enrichment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foreign ministers from six major powers are poised to fly to Geneva by the end of the week if nuclear talks with Iran lead to an agreement, western officials said on Wednesday night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new round of negotiations over the future of Iran's nuclear programme got under way on Wednesday, bringing together the Iranian foreign minister, Mohammad Javad Zarif, the EU foreign policy chief, Catherine Ashton, and top diplomats from the US, UK, France, Germany, Russia and China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officials involved in the talks – the third session since the election of a reformist Iranian president, Hassan Rouhani – said they were going well, overcoming the disappointment of the previous round, attended by US secretary of state, John Kerry, the British foreign secretary, William Hague, their French counterpart, Laurent Fabius, and other foreign ministers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those talks appeared to come close to clinching a historic deal but the talks broke up in early hours of 10 November, amid some acrimony over who was responsible for the failure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time, amid talk of progress, hotel rooms were being cleared for Friday in case the ministers returned to Geneva and advance security teams were making contingency preparations. Kerry's spokeswoman, Jen Psaki, said he had yet to make a decision about attending.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"He's open to going if it would continue to help narrow the gaps. He has not made a decision at this point to go, but obviously, we're in close touch with the negotiating team and will make a decision, clearly, in the next 36 hours," Psaki said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The negotiators still have to overcome the obstacles that stymied the previous Geneva session, but the differences appear to be narrowing. Zarif has signalled that Tehran might no longer insist on hammering out wording in the interim agreement that explicitly guarantees that Iran has the right to enrich uranium. Officials say there could instead be references to Iran's right to have a peaceful nuclear programme under the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty, a statement that each side could interpret in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other major sticking point from the last round, the fate of Iran's heavy water reactor under construction in Arak, there is also discussion of possible compromise language which would not suspend all construction work but would halt the most sensitive element of that work, the manufacture of fuel rods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, a senior western diplomat said there was still some way to go. The negotiators are working on the draft text of a joint statement that would detail an interim deal which would slow down, and in some areas halt or roll back, the Iranian nuclear programme, while granting limited western sanctions relief. The stopgap deal, which would last six months, would buy time for deeper negotiations aimed at a more enduring settlement to the decade-long deadlock.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Lots of progress was made last time. But considerable gaps remain and we have to narrow the gaps. Some issues really need to be clarified," the senior western diplomat said. "I sensed a real commitment … from both sides. Will it happen? We will see. But as always, the devil is in the details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"There are very technical issues at stake; it is important to have clear understanding on technical elements in order to ensure a robust and viable agreement. This needs to be done in a proper way – we will take the time we need."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A senior US official said: "We have all agreed that the document that was on the table at the end of our session last time would be our basis on discussion to go forward here and I certainly expect that we will be talking about the text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Time is not unlimited, but we are making very good progress and people have arrived back here with a commitment to do the hard work necessary to try a reach a common agreement. This is tough. There's a lot at stake, and Iran is not the only country in the room."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The assessment of Zarif's deputy, Abbas Araqchi, was rather more downbeat, indicating that some trust had been lost at the last round when the Iranians thought they had been close to a deal but the western position, at France's prompting, toughened at the 11th hour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Because of the misunderstandings and problems that occurred at the previous round of talks, we haven't yet returned to the same position [that we had]," Araqchi said, according to the Mehr news agency. "Some issues need to be clarified and trust needs to be restored once again before we enter the phase of drafting or writing the document."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cautious approach mirrored the tone set by Iran's supreme leader, Ali Khamenei, who said he had set strict parameters for his country's negotiating team. "We do insist that we will not step back one iota from our rights," Khamenei told a rally of volunteer militiamen, the Basij. "We do not intervene in the details of these talks. There are certain red lines and limits. These have to be observed. They are instructed to abide by those limits."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/iran"&gt;Iran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/environment/nuclearpower"&gt;Nuclear power&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/john-kerry"&gt;John Kerry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/nuclear-weapons"&gt;Nuclear weapons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/middleeast"&gt;Middle East and North Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/julianborger"&gt;Julian Borger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/saeedkamalidehghan"&gt;Saeed Kamali Dehghan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ec0d66/sc/20/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/sc/20/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/sc/20/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/sc/20/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/sc/20/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/sc/20/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/sc/20/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264631897/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ec0d66/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/environment">Nuclear power</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Middle East and North Africa</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Iran</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Nuclear weapons</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">John Kerry</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 01:08:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/21/iran-nuclear-talks-geneva-progress</guid><dc:creator>Julian Borger, Saeed Kamali Dehghan</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T01:08:21Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>423009081</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Iran, Nuclear power, John Kerry, United States, Nuclear weapons, Middle East and North Africa, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/21/1384996035338/Ashton-Javad-Zarif-Geneva-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Wang Siwei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>EU foreign policy chief Catherine Ashton with Iranian foreign minister Mohammad Javad-Zarif at the Palace of Nations. Photograph: Wang Siwei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/21/1384996041602/Ashton-Javad-Zarif-Geneva-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Wang Siwei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>EU foreign policy chief Catherine Ashton with Iranian foreign minister Mohammad Javad-Zarif at the Palace of Nations. Photograph: Wang Siwei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Tanya Plibersek: 'We can't let problems like this fester' – video</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb90b6/sc/1/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0Cvideo0C20A130Cnov0C210Cindonesia0Espying0Etanya0Eplibersek0Evideo/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tanya Plibersek says Labor will support any moves the government thinks are necessary to repair the relationship with Indonesia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb90b6/sc/1/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/sc/1/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/sc/1/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/sc/1/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/sc/1/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/sc/1/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/sc/1/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264630401/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb90b6/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Australian politics</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Canberra</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Editorial</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Indonesia</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Australia</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:33:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2013/nov/21/indonesia-spying-tanya-plibersek-video</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:33:54Z</dc:date><dc:type>Video</dc:type><dc:identifier>423007224</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Australia, Australian politics, Indonesia, Canberra</media:keywords><media:group><media:content fileSize="18067478" lang="" type="video/mp4" url="http://cdn.theguardian.tv/mainwebsite/2013/11/21/131121doors_FromGAus-16x9.mp4" /><media:content fileSize="15754429" lang="" type="video/3gpp:small" url="http://cdn.theguardian.tv/3gp/small/2013/11/21/131121doors_FromGAus_3gpSml16x9.3gp" /><media:content fileSize="29060319" lang="" type="video/3gpp:large" url="http://cdn.theguardian.tv/3gp/large/2013/11/21/131121doors_FromGAus_3gpLg16x9.3gp" /><media:content lang="" type="video/m3u8" url="http://cdn.theguardian.tv/ad/2013/11/21/131121doors_FromGAus/131121doors_FromGAus.m3u8" /></media:group><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/21/1384992519736/Tanya-Plibersek-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">AAP</media:credit><media:description>Deputy leader of the Opposition and shadow foreign minister Tanya Plibersek, talking in Canberra Photograph: AAP</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>UK won't see mass Romanian and Bulgarian immigration, minister says</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e6c47a/sc/25/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cuk0Enews0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cuk0Eimmigration0Eromania0Ebulgaria0Emark0Eharper/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/32942?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Auk-immigration-romania-bulgaria-mark-harper%3A2000416&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Immigration+and+asylum+%28UK+news%29%2CUK+news%2CPolitics%2CRomania+%28News%29%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CBulgaria+%28News%29&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Alan+Travis&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+02%3A23&amp;c8=2000416&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=UK+won%27t+see+mass+Romanian+and+Bulgarian+immigration%2C+minister+says&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FImmigration+and+asylum" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Mark Harper says migrants are likely to go to Germany, Italy and Spain rather than Britain when restrictions are lifted on January 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There will be no mass migration of Romanians and Bulgarians, coming to the UK for work in the new year when labour market restrictions are lifted, the immigration minister has said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first official assessment of the likely flow of Romanians and Bulgarians to Britain when the curbs are removed on 1 January, the minister, Mark Harper, said the situation this time would not replicate the mass arrival of Poles to the UK 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said the government was not complacent about the arrival of new migrants but said it would be different this time and suggested that people were more likely to go to Germany, Italy and Spain than Britain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harper also criticised Tory rightwingers who have been demanding that the seven-year "transitional controls" on Romanians and Bulgarians be extended after January. He told a Home Office press briefing: "It is simply not legally possible."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He called it "a fool's errand" to try to predict the numbers that would go to the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The former home secretary Jack Straw had said last week, he added, that a "spectacular mistake" was made in 2004 when academic estimates suggested that only 15,000 Polish and other east European migrants at that time would go to Britain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harper said he had every intention of avoiding a similar mistake this time. "There is a big difference with 2004 when we were the only major country not to have transitional controls and all the other big countries did. Anybody who wanted to work here legally came to the UK."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said there were now eight other countries also removing their controls. "We are therefore not in the same position as previously, when we were the only country that was an option for those wishing to migrate. There are now a range of other European countries in the eurozone, including Germany, which is an economic powerhouse that is generating jobs and creating economic growth."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original estimate by University College, London, which calculated that 15,000 Poles and others would arrive each year, was based on an assumption that all the other EU countries would open their borders when former communist states joined in 2004.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the event, only Britain, Ireland and Sweden opened their borders immediately to allow migrants to work. The rest of the EU, including Germany, imposed the seven-year transitional controls, which came to an end only two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harper said there were also other countries which already had significant populations of Romanians and Bulgarians, including Italy and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eight countries, besides the UK, due to open their borders to Romanian and Bulgarian labour migrants are Austria, Belgium, Germany, Ireland, Luxembourg, Malta, the Netherlands and France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than three million Romanians went to work abroad when Romania joined the EU in 2007; the majority went toItaly and Spain, which have already opened their labour markets to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The comparisons are different. That doesn't mean that we don't have concerns," said the immigration minister, pointing to the tightening of restrictions on EU migrants, including aspects such as unemployment benefits and social housing, alongside enforcement action being intensified against employers who use the migrant labour market to undercut wage rates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harper criticised rightwing Tory MPs who have been pressing him to extend the transitional controls on Romanians and Bulgarians, telling them it was not legally possible under the European accession treaties. He said Britain's domestic courts would rule that an extension of controls would not comply with the treaties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harper's assessment came as the chief inspector of borders and immigration, John Vine, published a critical report showing that only one in four smugglers caught by Border Force officers are being fined or prosecuted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vine also criticises the searching priorities of the Border Force and HM Revenues and Customs by highlighting that 68% of freight consignments targeted for checks at the border are actually undergoing a physical examination while 43,000 low-risk cargoes were being checked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report on the state of customs and border checks on the 311m tonnes of freight coming into Britain each also confirms previous warnings that immigration staff have been switched from looking for drugs and smuggled tobacco to carry out 100% passport checks on passengers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vine's report says that only 2,971 out of 11,839 seizures of smuggled goods made by Border Force officials – one in four – were being referred to HMRC for financial penalty or possible prosecution because of a breakdown of communication: "I also found that large quantities of cigarettes and alcohol were not being investigated or prosecuted," said Vine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harper responded by saying that work was already underway to ensure that more cases were referred to prosecution but added that there had been a shift in focus to prosecuting cases where larger quantities were involved and there was a reasonable chance of prosecution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/uk/immigration"&gt;Immigration and asylum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/romania"&gt;Romania&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/bulgaria"&gt;Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/alantravis"&gt;Alan Travis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e6c47a/sc/25/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/sc/25/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/sc/25/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/sc/25/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/sc/25/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/sc/25/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/sc/25/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264726740/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e6c47a/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">Immigration and asylum</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Romania</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Bulgaria</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:33:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2013/nov/20/uk-immigration-romania-bulgaria-mark-harper</guid><dc:creator>Alan Travis</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:33:39Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422959852</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Immigration and asylum, UK news, Politics, Romania, Europe, World news, Bulgaria</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384956373588/UK-Border-Control-006.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Steve Parsons/PA Wire/Press Association Images</media:credit><media:description>Border Control: immigration minister Mark Harper has said there will not be a mass arrival of Romanians and Bulgarians when they are free to work in Britain. Photograph: Steve Parsons/PA Wire/Press Association Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384956380557/UK-Border-Control-011.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Steve Parsons/PA Wire/Press Association Images</media:credit><media:description>Border Control: immigration minister Mark Harper has said there will not be a mass arrival of Romanians and Bulgarians when they are free to work in Britain. Photograph: Steve Parsons/PA Wire/Press Association Images</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Libération shooting: man arrested</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ea25b7/sc/11/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cparis0Earrest0Eshooting0Enewspaper0Eliberation/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/16206?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aparis-arrest-shooting-newspaper-liberation%3A2000729&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Paris+%28News%29%2CFrance%2CWorld+news%2CGun+crime+%28News%29&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Kim+Willsher&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+08%3A22&amp;c8=2000729&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Police+arrest+man+suspected+of+Paris+shooting+attacks&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FParis" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Man bearing 'strong resemblance' to shooter found in car park after apparently trying to kill himself with an overdose&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;French police have arrested a man they suspect to be the gunman who spread panic across Paris for three days after shooting and critically injuring a young man at the offices of the newspaper Libération on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man was discovered in a car in an underground car park at Bois-Colombes in the Paris suburb of Hauts-de-Seine at about 7pm French time (6pm GMT) on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was said to bear a very strong resemblance to a man in photographs taken from security cameras. The rifle-toting man shot a young photographer's assistant at Libération. He had previously threatened a senior editor at BFM TV on Friday evening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agnes Thibault Lecuivre, a spokeswoman for the French prosecutor's office, said that a suspect had been arrested on Wednesday evening. It is believed that the man may be behind two other recent incidents in the capital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, detectives were reportedly unable to question the man because he was "semi-conscious", having taken a quantity of medical drugs in a suspected attempt to kill himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was taken into police custody, but detectives said he was sleepy and comatose and not in a fit state to be questioned or read his rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police union official Christophe Crepin said the man appeared heavily medicated when he was detained. "My colleagues noticed he was not very lucid. They deduced that he had taken medicines, because of the capsules nearby," Crepin told the Associated Press.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police received several hundred calls after issuing photographs of the suspect on Tuesday. As the city-wide manhunt dragged on for a third day, police were under pressure to find the attacker described as a lone gunman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police told journalists on Wednesday night that they could not confirm that the arrested man was the shooting suspect until they had received the results of DNA tests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man has been transferred to a Paris hospital where he is under armed guard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A man, described as between 35 and 45, stocky and European, fired twice after walking into the Libération offices at about 10.15am on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He strolled into the entrance hall and fired twice, injuring a 23-year-old in the back, thorax and abdomen. The victim, who was taken to hospital with life-threatening injuries, was said on Wednesday to be making a good recovery yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gunman then travelled to the Paris business district, La Défense, where he shot at the headquarters of the French bank Societé Générale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, he hijacked a car ordering the terrified driver to take him to the Champs-Elysées where he was last seen disappearing into a Metro station.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police said the DNA of the man, who told the driver of the hijacked car that he had recently been released from prison, had not shown up on their national database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, DNA tests were carried out on bullet casings the gunman had thrown to the ground at BFM TV, where he told the editor he threatened: "Next time, I won't miss", and on traces in the vehicle car-jacked at La Défense. The tests showed that the same man was responsible both attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/paris"&gt;Paris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/france"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/gun-crime"&gt;Gun crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/kim-willsher"&gt;Kim Willsher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ea25b7/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/sc/11/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/sc/11/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/sc/11/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/sc/11/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/sc/11/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/sc/11/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264748247/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea25b7/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Paris</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">France</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:19:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/20/paris-arrest-shooting-newspaper-liberation</guid><dc:creator>Kim Willsher</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:23:41Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422992788</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Paris, France, World news, Gun crime</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384978838886/Paris-police-hunt-gunman--004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Davide Del Giudice/Demotix/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>French police in Paris during the search for the gunman. Photograph: Davide Del Giudice/Demotix/Corbis</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384978846711/Paris-police-hunt-gunman--009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Davide Del Giudice/Demotix/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>French police in Paris during the search for the gunman. Photograph: Davide Del Giudice/Demotix/Corbis</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Kipper Williams on Ikea France's spying allegations</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb88ce/sc/11/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cbusiness0Ccartoon0C20A130Cnov0C210Ckipper0Ewilliams0Eikea0Efrance/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Executives accused of spying on employees and even disgruntled customers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb88ce/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/sc/11/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/sc/11/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/sc/11/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/sc/11/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/sc/11/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/sc/11/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264628804/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88ce/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Editorial</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Retail industry</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">France</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Business</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Ikea</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:02:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/business/cartoon/2013/nov/21/kipper-williams-ikea-france</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>Business</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:02:01Z</dc:date><dc:type>Cartoon</dc:type><dc:identifier>422988998</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Ikea, Business, France, Retail industry, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384973817356/Kipper-Williams-cartoon-2-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Kipper Williams cartoon 21 November 2013 Photograph: Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="560" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384973818584/Kipper-Williams-cartoon-2-002.jpg" /></item><item><title>Foreign Office warning over drugs offence risks abroad</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb88dc/sc/25/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Csociety0C20A130Cnov0C210Cforeign0Eoffice0Edrugs0Erisks0Eabroad/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/89895?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aforeign-office-drugs-risks-abroad%3A2000673&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Drugs+illegal+%28Society%29%2CSociety%2CUK+news%2CWorld+news%2CTravel+safety+advice&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CCommunities+Society&amp;c6=Haroon+Siddique&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F21+12%3A02&amp;c8=2000673&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Foreign+Office+warning+over+drugs+offence+risks+abroad&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FDrugs" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;FCO teams up with charity Prisoners Abroad to highlight harsh penalties and stark conditions that Britons can face&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 850 British people are locked up in overseas prisons for drug-related offences, the Foreign Office has revealed as it launches a campaign to warn of the consequences of the crime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With 32% of British detentions abroad over the past six months for drug offences, the Foreign Office has teamed up with the charity &lt;a href="http://www.prisonersabroad.org.uk/" title=""&gt;Prisoners Abroad&lt;/a&gt; to highlight the harsh penalties and stark conditions that Britons can face, often for drugs offences that would carry relatively light penalties in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark Simmonds, minister for consular affairs, said: "This campaign is not about making excuses for people not aware of the law or passing judgements on foreign laws, I just want to make sure people are aware of the consequences. We can't interfere with other countries' legal systems nor can we get people out of prison and people need to understand that."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2012-13, 669 British nationals were arrested for drug-related offences, with the highest number in the US (159), followed by Spain (103).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among countries with tough regimes are two countries which are popular with gap year students: Peru, where more than 30 British nationals are currently in prison for drugs offences, and Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the United Arab Emirates, possession of even the smallest amount of illegal drugs, which can be evidenced by presence in the bloodstream, can lead to a minimum four-year jail sentence, whereas it might warrant a caution in the UK. Suspects can be detained for months without trial in some countries and some drugs offences can carry the death penalty in 33 countries or territories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prisoners Abroad says it is supporting 80 British prisoners between the ages of 18 and 30 held in foreign countries for drugs offences, two thirds of whom are still awaiting trial, with the rest serving sentences from a year to nearly 39 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The charity's chief executive, Pauline Crowe, said: "In many countries, men and women find themselves without access to food, clean water and the most basic of medical care. We urge people to consider the unsanitary conditions, overcrowded cells and the constant threat of disease before they get involved in drugs. They may have to live through these conditions for many, many years."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terry Daniels, 40, is one of two British nationals who have described their experiences of being imprisoned abroad for drugs offences in a Foreign Office video. She was sentenced to 10 years in prison when she was 24 after her boss, who she was travelling with, was stopped in Gran Canaria carrying four kilograms of cocaine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smith now gives talks in schools about the dangers of getting involved in drugs. "I think people think 'The Foreign Office will get me out. It's only a small bit of drugs,'" she said. "That's not how it works."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/society/drugs"&gt;Drugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/travel/travel-safety-advice"&gt;Travel safety advice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/haroonsiddique"&gt;Haroon Siddique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb88dc/sc/25/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/sc/25/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/sc/25/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/sc/25/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/sc/25/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/sc/25/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/sc/25/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264628803/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88dc/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/society">Drugs</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/travel">Travel safety advice</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:02:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/society/2013/nov/21/foreign-office-drugs-risks-abroad</guid><dc:creator>Haroon Siddique</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:36:19Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422984611</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Drugs, Society, UK news, World news, Travel safety advice</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384972810845/Terry-Daniels-in-still-fr-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">FCO</media:credit><media:description>Terry Daniels in a still from a film made by the Foreign Office, which is warning Britons about drug penalties and prison conditions abroad. Photograph: FCO</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384972818404/Terry-Daniels-in-still-fr-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">FCO</media:credit><media:description>Terry Daniels in a still from a film made by the Foreign Office, which is warning Britons about drug penalties and prison conditions abroad. Photograph: FCO</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Healthcare in Bangladesh soars despite widespread poverty, study shows</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb88d2/sc/46/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cglobal0Edevelopment0C20A130Cnov0C210Cbangladesh0Ehealthcare0Epoverty0Elancet0Estudy/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/8180?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Abangladesh-healthcare-poverty-lancet-study%3A2000630&amp;ch=Global+development&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Global+development%2CBangladesh+%28News%29%2CHealth+%28Society%29%2CWorld+news%2CSociety%2CGender+%28News%29&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CHealth+Society&amp;c6=Mark+Tran&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F21+12%3A02&amp;c8=2000630&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Healthcare+in+Bangladesh+soars+despite+widespread+poverty%2C+study+shows&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FGlobal+development%2FBangladesh" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Bangladeshi women hold key to success as infant mortality plunges and life expectancy climbs to 68.3 years, says Lancet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The empowerment of women and the reach of NGOs have contributed to Bangladesh's remarkable success in healthcare, which has included significant improvements in the survival of under-fives, immunisation coverage and tuberculosis control, &lt;a href="http://www.thelancet.com/series/bangladesh" title=""&gt;according to the Lancet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The achievements are in spite of low spending on healthcare, a weak health system and widespread poverty. Bangladesh's health success has come despite its low gross domestic product of $101.9bn. The nation of 153 million people ranks in the lowest income group of countries, on a par with neighbours Nepal and Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, Bangladesh's life expectancy is superior to that of other countries in the region, except Nepal. Bangladesh's infant mortality, under-fives mortality and maternal mortality rates are also better than other countries in the region. Bangladesh is ahead of Pakistan in all education and health indicators. But there are caveats. Despite improved survival rates, nearly half of children in the country have &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2012/feb/15/bangladesh-child-malnutrition-stunted-growth" title=""&gt;chronic malnutrition&lt;/a&gt;, a problem &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jul/16/amartya-sen-india-dirty-fighter" title=""&gt;shared with India&lt;/a&gt;, which also has a high prevalence of child and maternal malnutrition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Over the past 40 years, Bangladesh has outperformed its Asian neighbours, convincingly defying the expert view that reducing poverty and increasing health resources are the key drivers of better population health," said the report's co-leader, Professor Mushtaque Chowdhury, from Brac, a Bangladeshi NGO. "Since 1980 maternal mortality has dropped by 75%, while infant mortality has more than halved since 1990, and life expectancy has increased to 68.3 years – surpassing neighbouring India and Pakistan."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Progress in infant, child and maternal mortality has been particularly striking, with an unprecedented reversal in the number of deaths among girls compared with boys. Maternal mortality was reduced from 574 deaths per 100,000 livebirths in 1991 to 194 deaths in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tuberculosis treatment is another success. Through mass deployment of community health workers, the number of people cured rose from less than 50% to more than 90% – among the highest in the world. Another is contraceptive use. By recruiting female health workers to deliver door-to-door family planning services, Bangladesh has achieved high (62%) contraceptive prevalence and a dramatic fall in birth rates, from an average 6.3 births per woman in 1971 to 2.3 in 2010 – a rate unparalleled in other countries with similar levels of development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all health indicators are positive, particularly child malnutrition. The rates of underweight in children from the poorest families fell from 59% in 2004 to 50% in 2010. Even in the wealthiest quintile, 21% of children were underweight in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data underlines the complexity of malnutrition, where factors range from poverty and hunger, low rates of breastfeeding, inadequate care and complementary feeding, and recurrent infections. Paradoxically, there is a rising incidence of obesity, a phenomenon noted elsewhere in poorer countries, including &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2007/jun/05/china.schoolsworldwide" title=""&gt;China&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2010/nov/23/obesity-india-affluent-affliction" title=""&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lancet attributes Bangladesh's success to a "pluralistic" health system pulling in government and NGOs that emphasised the role of women in delivering action on family planning, immunisation, oral rehydration therapy, tuberculosis and vitamin A supplementation. The role of gender equity, including the widespread education of girls, was noted in the report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Perhaps the most powerful strategy for health was the country's distinct acknowledgment and support of women to national development," said the report. "Educational policies that favoured girls caused near-universal primary education and removed gender disparity in educational access … women were brought to the forefront of development work as leaders, implementers and receivers of services."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report cites the importance of NGOs such as &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/global-development/poverty-matters/2012/feb/13/brac-lifts-ultra-poor-out-poverty" title=""&gt;Brac&lt;/a&gt;, Grameen and Bangladesh Diabetic Samity in contributing to the improved health of poor people in rural areas. "NGOs as a group have innovated to address issues of poverty, unemployment, health, education and the environment, and in many cases the government and NGOs have worked together to achieve a common goal," it said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opinion is mixed on the role of foreign aid, which was about 6% of GDP between 1970 and 1990, dropping to 2% in 2005. However, the Lancet notes that external assistance was helpful in funding NGOs, which attracted up to 18% of total aid commitment in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, the report said that despite annual economic growth of 6%, persistent poverty would continue to limit health progress. More than 30% of the population are classified as extremely poor, and inequality has widened. Corruption and political fragmentation – with politics dominated by two irreconcilable parties – pose particular challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rapid urbanisation, with about a third of city dwellers living in slums without basic infrastructure and social services, and changes to lifestyle are increasing the risk of non-communicable diseases, including cardiovascular and metabolic diseases such as diabetes and cancers. Climate change might increase the frequency, severity and effect of natural disasters, threatening the health and resilience of society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The Bangladesh health system has been shaped to address the first generation of poverty-linked infections, and nutritional and maternity-related diseases," the Lancet said. "But given the epidemiological transition, the health system will have to be adjusted to grapple with chronic non-communicable diseases. For the fragile and evolving Bangladesh health system, the global attention on universal health coverage has not been translated into substantive action."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/bangladesh"&gt;Bangladesh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/society/health"&gt;Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/gender"&gt;Gender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/marktran"&gt;Mark Tran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb88d2/sc/46/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/sc/46/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/sc/46/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/sc/46/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/sc/46/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/sc/46/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/sc/46/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264628802/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb88d2/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/society">Health</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Bangladesh</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Gender</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/global-development">Global development</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:02:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2013/nov/21/bangladesh-healthcare-poverty-lancet-study</guid><dc:creator>Mark Tran</dc:creator><dc:subject>Global development</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:02:00Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422981065</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Global development, Bangladesh, Health, World news, Society, Gender</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Environment/Pix/columnists/2013/11/20/1384963623435/MDG--Bangladesh-healthy-a-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Francois Werli/Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Laughing children on a beach in South Bangladesh, 19 January 2011. Photograph: Francois Werli/Alamy</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Environment/Pix/columnists/2013/11/20/1384963630675/MDG--Bangladesh-healthy-a-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Francois Werli/Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Bangladesh’s falling infant and maternal mortality rates have helped the country's health indicators outperform its neighbours. Photograph: François Werli/Alamy</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Spying: the secret of success is in keeping your success secret | John Blaxland</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb5dd6/sc/39/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Ccommentisfree0C20A130Cnov0C210Cspying0Ethe0Esecret0Eof0Esuccess0Eis0Ein0Ekeeping0Eyour0Esuccess0Esecret/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Blaxland for The Conversation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The Indonesian foreign minister has&amp;nbsp;fulminated&amp;nbsp;about Australia's alleged spying activities &amp;ndash; but it is important to have a broader perspective on such revelations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/john-blaxland"&gt;John Blaxland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb5dd6/sc/39/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/sc/39/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/sc/39/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/sc/39/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/sc/39/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/sc/39/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/sc/39/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264596299/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb5dd6/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Comment</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Australian politics</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">NSA</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Surveillance</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Indonesia</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Liberal party</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Australia</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 23:20:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/nov/21/spying-the-secret-of-success-is-in-keeping-your-success-secret</guid><dc:creator>John Blaxland</dc:creator><dc:subject>Comment is free</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-20T23:24:46Z</dc:date><dc:type>Resource Content</dc:type><dc:identifier>423004399</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Surveillance, Australia, Australian politics, NSA, Indonesia, Liberal party</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/6/1383719681180/ed945b5b-5328-4b25-a543-8a482b020039-140x84.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Oliver Berg/ Oliver Berg/dpa/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>Binary code on a computer screen in Cologne, Germany, 5 November 2013. Photograph: Oliver Berg/dpa/Corbis</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>US and Afghanistan reach troop deal</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb8145/sc/39/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cus0Eafghanistan0Ereach0Edeal0Epostwar0Etroops/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Security Agreement ensures rump US force will continue to train, advise and equip roughly 350,000 Afghan soldiers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/spencerackerman"&gt;Spencer Ackerman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/emma-graham-harrison"&gt;Emma Graham-Harrison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eb8145/sc/39/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/sc/39/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/sc/39/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/sc/39/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/sc/39/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/sc/39/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/sc/39/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264627160/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eb8145/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Drones</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">US foreign policy</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Taliban</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">US military</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Afghanistan</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Hamid Karzai</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Obama administration</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">John Kerry</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 22:32:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/20/us-afghanistan-reach-deal-postwar-troops</guid><dc:creator>Spencer Ackerman, Emma Graham-Harrison</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-20T22:35:21Z</dc:date><dc:type>Resource Content</dc:type><dc:identifier>422999651</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Afghanistan, US military, United States, US foreign policy, John Kerry, Obama administration, Hamid Karzai, Taliban, Drones</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/12/1384288610152/d4f53e17-288f-4bed-b9c9-3a8ed2ab6f6f-140x84.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Wang Siwei/REX/Wang Siwei/REX</media:credit><media:description>John Kerry represented the US in talks with Iran in Geneva. Photograph: Wang Siwei/Rex</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Fukushima: coming clean | Editorial</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eac763/sc/39/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Ccommentisfree0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cfukushima0Eclean0Eeditorial/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/32998?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Afukushima-clean-editorial%3A2000767&amp;ch=Comment+is+free&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Fukushima+%28environment%29%2CWorld+news%2CJapan+%28News%29%2CNuclear+power+%28Environment%29%2CJapan+disaster+%28News%29%2CEnvironment%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEnergy%2CEthical+Living&amp;c6=Editorial+%28Guardian%29&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+10%3A06&amp;c8=2000767&amp;c9=Blog&amp;c10=Comment%2CEditorial&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c25=Comment+is+free&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Fukushima%3A+coming+clean&amp;c66=Comment+is+free&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FComment+is+free%2FComment+is+free%2Fblog%2FComment+is+free" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Is the unthinkable being thought as Britain plans for a new generation of reactors?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like Chernobyl, Three Mile Island or any other major nuclear accident, Fukushima Daiichi will be with us for decades to come. The entire plant is being decommissioned, a clean-up they reckon could take 40 years. After a disaster of these proportions, when three reactors suffered meltdowns after being hit by a giant tsunami, nothing its operator does or says today is taken at face value in Japan. The ability of the Tokyo Electric Power Company (Tepco) to handle the build-up of toxic water used to contain the melted cores is being questioned as never before, after a string of water and radiation leaks and one incident in which six men were doused with contaminated water. The embattled company faces &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/environment/2013/oct/15/fukushima-nuclear-power-plant-cleanup" title=""&gt;plummeting morale&lt;/a&gt;, a shortage of skilled labour, insufficient funds – all exacerbated, according to some, by a refusal to accept outside help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For all this, it is worth reading what Naomi Hirose, Tepco's latest president, had to say &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/environment/2013/nov/19/uk-government-new-plant-fukushima-nuclear-disaster-warning" title=""&gt;in an interview with the Guardian&lt;/a&gt;. What happened at Fukushima, he said, was a lesson to the world: "Try to examine all the possibilities no matter how small they are, and don't think any single counter-measure is foolproof." In hindsight, one tiny detail, such as waterproof seals on doors, would have saved everything. Is the unthinkable being thought as Britain plans for a new generation of reactors? Fukushima prompted the UK's &lt;a href="http://www.nuleaf.org.uk/nuleaf/DisplayArticle.asp?ID=6342" title=""&gt;Office for Nuclear Regulation&lt;/a&gt; to conduct a safety review in which Mike Weightman, its chief inspector, concluded there were no fundamental safety weaknesses, although his report identified &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/environment/2011/oct/11/nuclear-industry-review-uk?guni=Article:in%20body%20link" title=""&gt;38 areas for improvement&lt;/a&gt;. Is the review, as the independent nuclear analyst John Large maintains, a whitewash? Would UK reactors, as he contends, not survive an hour without power? Documents released under freedom of information rules showed that all eight coastal nuclear locations in the UK, including Hinkley Point, were at risk of flooding and coastal erosion, which would worsen with climate change. The point here is not whether we need nuclear power. It is whether the nuclear industry in Britain is learning from disasters. Is it coming clean about all the risks associated with the venture?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pressure to produce the answer that confirms the consensus view is intense. Fukushima prompted Japan to close all 50 nuclear power plants. Little surprise that at the UN climate talks in Warsaw, Japan, which is the world's fifth largest emitter of greenhouse gas, &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2013/nov/15/japan-scaling-back-cut-greenhouse-gases" title=""&gt;slashed plans to reduce emissions&lt;/a&gt; from 25% to 3.8% on 2005 figures. Hiroshi Minami, Japan's chief negotiator, said that with no nuclear power, Japan has to lower its "ambition level" on greenhouse gases. In the short term, Japan is trapped, as are we all, in a vicious circle of greenhouse gas dependency and worsening climate change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/environment/fukushima"&gt;Fukushima&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/japan"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/environment/nuclearpower"&gt;Nuclear power&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/japan-earthquake-and-tsunami"&gt;Japan disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/editorial"&gt;Editorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eac763/sc/39/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/environment">Nuclear power</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Comment</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Japan</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Japan disaster</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/environment">Environment</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/environment">Fukushima</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Editorials</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 22:06:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/nov/20/fukushima-clean-editorial</guid><dc:creator>Editorial</dc:creator><dc:subject>Comment is free</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:40Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>423000753</dc:identifier></item><item><title>Graphene producer's shares jump by 40% in market debut</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eab161/sc/21/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cbusiness0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Capplied0Egraphene0Ematerials0Eagm0Eshares0Emarket0Edebut/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/1472?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aapplied-graphene-materials-agm-shares-market-debut%3A2000762&amp;ch=Business&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Stock+markets%2CBusiness%2CChemistry+%28Science%29%2CUK+news%2CSmall+business+%28Business%29%2CWorld+news%2CShares+%28UK+consumer%29%2CInvestments+%28Money+-+UK+consumer%29%2CMoney%2CScience&amp;c5=Personal+Finance%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CBusiness+Markets%2CSME%2CInvestments+%26+Savings&amp;c6=Juliette+Garside&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+09%3A56&amp;c8=2000762&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Graphene+producer%27s+shares+jump+by+40%25+in+market+debut&amp;c66=Business&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FBusiness%2FBusiness%2FStock+markets" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Shareholders pile in to buy a slice of Applied Graphene Materials, which has found a way to mass produce graphene&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A British firm which has found a way to produce industrial quantities of graphene, the wonder material expected to revolutionise the fields of medicine and manufacturing, saw its share price rise 40% during its stock market debut on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shareholders piled in to buy a slice of Applied Graphene Materials (AGM), which is based in Cleveland and was spun out of Durham University, in a float that was more than two times oversubscribed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphene, a substance isolated by Nobel prize-winning scientists at the University of Manchester in 2004, is a one-molecule-thick layer of graphite that is 20 times stronger than diamond and conducts electricity 20 times better than copper. It has already been used in tennis rackets and future applications range from aircraft bodies to membranes used in DNA sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphene is difficult to make in large quantities, but AGM, which raised £11m by selling a 42% stake, has found a way to mass produce the material in powder and is working with companies including Dyson and Procter &amp; Gamble to develop commercial uses for the material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This funding will allow us to begin the next phase of development and to strengthen relationships with our partners," said chief executive John Mabbitt. "Applied Graphene Materials is now well positioned to meet the growing global appetite for graphene as a wonder material of the 21st century."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The float on London's Aim market for smaller companies saw shares pop from the initial placing price of 155p to 216p by the close of the first day's trading, valuing the company at £36m. AGM is forecast to become profitable in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Founder and technical director Karl Coleman, professor of inorganic chemistry at Durham University, retains a 10% stake, having reduced his holding from 24% before the float. Early backer IP Group, which invests in patent-based businesses, has reinvested and retains a 20% stake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AGM will use the capital raised on Aim to expand the capacity of its Teesside production facility from one tonne a year to eight over the next 18 months. The company's 10-strong workforce will also increase, with engineers and scientists recruited to develop commercial applications for its products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most graphene production relies on natural supplies of graphite, which has to be mined, but AGM has found a way to produce it using carbon atoms sourced from ethanol. Its product can then added to resins, plastics, oils and lubricants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dyson wants to use graphene in the plastic casing for its vacuum cleaners, because of its strength, and because its ability to conduct electricity reduces static, which in turn helps the machine suck in more dust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added to paints, graphene could help protect the hulls of boats from rust and, as a dry lubricant, reduce drag as the ship moves through water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the UK pioneered the discovery of graphene, Asian companies have made the greatest efforts to commercialise it, with electronics giant Samsung leading the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We [the British] are good with the initial materials, but other people are better at seeing applications ... We have to be careful with graphene, otherwise it is one of those things that we just let go," said Mabbitt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/business/stock-markets"&gt;Stock markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/science/chemistry"&gt;Chemistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/business/small-business"&gt;Small business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/money/shares"&gt;Shares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/money/moneyinvestments"&gt;Investments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/juliette-garside"&gt;Juliette Garside&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eab161/sc/21/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/sc/21/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/sc/21/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/sc/21/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/sc/21/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/sc/21/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/sc/21/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264656755/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eab161/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Stock markets</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Small business</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/money">Money</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/money">Investments</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/science">Chemistry</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/money">Shares</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Business</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/science">Science</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 21:56:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/business/2013/nov/20/applied-graphene-materials-agm-shares-market-debut</guid><dc:creator>Juliette Garside</dc:creator><dc:subject>Business</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:48Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422999046</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Stock markets, Business, Chemistry, UK news, Small business, World news, Shares, Investments, Money, Science</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384984410482/Graphene-is-already-used--004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Shaun Botterill/Getty Images for HEAD</media:credit><media:description>Graphene is already used in tennis rackets, with future applications including aircraft bodies and membranes for DNA sequencing. Photograph: Shaun Botterill/Getty Images for HEAD</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384984419635/Graphene-is-already-used--009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Shaun Botterill/Getty Images for HEAD</media:credit><media:description>Graphene is already used in tennis rackets, with future applications including aircraft bodies and membranes for DNA sequencing. Photograph: Shaun Botterill/Getty Images for HEAD</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>JFK's assassination wasn't the end of anything, it just felt that way | Martin Kettle</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eaabeb/sc/38/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Ccommentisfree0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cjkf0Easassination0Ehistory0Evictims0Enorthern0Eireland/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/16126?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Ajkf-asassination-history-victims-northern-ireland%3A2000743&amp;ch=Comment+is+free&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=John+F+Kennedy+%28News%29+JFK%2CKennedys+%28News%29%2CNorthern+Ireland+%28News%29%2CUS+news%2CWorld+news%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Martin+Kettle&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+09%3A30&amp;c8=2000743&amp;c9=Blog&amp;c10=Comment&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c25=Comment+is+free&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=JFK%27s+assassination+wasn%27t+the+end+of+anything%2C+it+just+felt+that+way&amp;c66=Comment+is+free&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FComment+is+free%2FComment+is+free%2Fblog%2FComment+is+free" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Every generation has its Kennedy moments. From 9/11 to Iraq, history moves on&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;History may not be bunk, as Henry Ford famously claimed it was. But it is hard not to feel, as the &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/15/jfk-death-conspiracy-theories-50-years" title=""&gt;50th anniversary of the Kennedy assassination&lt;/a&gt; nears and the &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2013/nov/20/northern-ireland-attorney-general-troubles-prosecutions" title=""&gt;people of Northern Ireland fret once again&lt;/a&gt; this week about their divided past, that history is no longer what it used to be either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an impressionable teenager, I never needed convincing about the significance of the events in Dallas. I was a sixth-form Dealey Plaza obsessive – though to this day I can't watch the &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/film/2013/nov/14/abraham-zapruder-film-kennedy-killing-parkland" title=""&gt;Zapruder film&lt;/a&gt; of the killing. I longed for Bobby Kennedy to take his brother's place in the White House. I lived for many years with the belief that the killing of John F Kennedy was the day the world's innocence died, not just mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, it wasn't really the end of anything. It just felt that way in the first fierce shock of it all. But then other stuff happened and the world went on spinning. And here we are. At a distance of 50 years, it is getting harder to judge how significant Kennedy's murder really was. Candace Allen wrote in the Guardian that &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/19/john-f-kennedy-assassination-racial-equality-jfk" title=""&gt;his death may, on balance, have helped the civil rights cause&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe so. But Stephen King, in &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/11/22/63" title=""&gt;11/22/63&lt;/a&gt; – his time-travel Kennedy assassination novel – foresees Kennedy's survival heralding a violently dystopic 21st-century America. That could be true too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who knows? The real truth is that no more than one in five human beings on the planet can remember the assassination of President Kennedy. For the rest of you, that day in Dallas is something your parents or grandparents sometimes go on about. You have to be well over 55 to recall the shooting. So, in a big sense, what happened on 22 November 1963 doesn't matter any more. Collectively, we are losing JFK to history at last. And in a way, that's fine. Let it go. We have today's problems to deal with now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even so, it is worth reflecting on the relatively low-key way the Kennedy anniversary is being marked. Every generation has its Kennedy moments. Some of them are massive, like the world war that marked my parents for the rest of their lives. Others are briefer shocks. Some are even moments to cheer not weep: the fall of the Berlin Wall; the ousting of Margaret Thatcher. The people who witnessed them will be marked by them in some way or another till they die.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the important thing is that the process never ends. These big moments matter most when they occur. From then on they are in decline. As the decades pass they all resonate less and less. And always something new comes along – like 9/11 or the London Olympics – which settles another layer of experience over the jumbled sediment that history has untidily laid down beforehand. There is never, ever, any going back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This matters. For one thing, it is a reminder that history never stops. History flows on, the world changes, and different questions are posed in new forms until the end of time. That's why it is a dangerous delusion to believe that any single event in the past should hold the present or the future permanently hostage. The 9/11 attacks exemplify this. An angry, even warlike response made sense at the time. But then came Iraq, which became part of a new incarnation of the world's problem. And now even Iraq is receding too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A second thing to remember is that the dilution of supposedly shared memory never stops either. That process is sleepless too. No one under 55 remembers the Kennedy killing. But no one under 45 remembers pre-Thatcher Britain either, which is why the current Conservative obsession with union power feels like a diversion driven by the past, when most of today's employees have no memory of unions at all, overmighty or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And no one under the age of 30 remembers Thatcher in power, or the cold war. No one under 20 recalls when New Labour captured the moment. First-time voters in 2015, born in 1997, won't even recall 9/11 or Iraq. That's not to pretend that appeals to the spirit of the past – whether it's to &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/scotland/history/articles/battle_of_bannockburn/" title=""&gt;1314&lt;/a&gt; for Scots, &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/history/events/battle_of_the_boyne" title=""&gt;1690&lt;/a&gt; for Northern Ireland unionists, &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/history/british/easterrising/profiles/po17.shtml" title=""&gt;1916&lt;/a&gt; for Irish republicans, 1940 for the Tories or &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2001/mar/14/past.education" title=""&gt;1945&lt;/a&gt; for Labour, never mind 1966 for English football, fail to stir any response at all. But their experienced meaning inexorably declines over time and is replaced with a construction, even perhaps in the case of the Holocaust, no matter how hard anyone tries to keep the rawness alive. In the end, the political question is never, "What then?" It is and should always be, "What now?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of this is to say history doesn't matter. Look at the ongoing &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/nov/17/chilcot-inquiry-tony-blair-bush" title=""&gt;row over the Chilcot inquiry&lt;/a&gt; into the Iraq war. Look too at yesterday's response to the suggestion by Northern Ireland's maverick attorney general, John Larkin, that &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2012/oct/26/northern-ireland-abortion-larkin" title=""&gt;historic Troubles-related investigations should be shut down&lt;/a&gt; to help draw a line under the past. Logically Larkin is right. These cases re-open and inflame wounds better left to close. The next generation has even less interest in re-opening them than the current one has. They will never all be solved equitably or to everyone's satisfaction. But the victims' generation can't let go, like the Iraq generation. So this is not yet the time for this particular compromise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Northern Ireland remains a place where it is often premature to cast off the past completely. So, in another part of the forest, is Gibraltar. But these things are not set in stone. The Irish Republic increasingly shows how it can be done, and there is no disputing that, for all its contradictions and faults, modern Ireland is better for it than either Ulster or the Rock. Each case is different, but not every injustice of history needs to be tidily accounted for in the international criminal court. The Danes invaded and pillaged parts of England centuries ago; but no modern Danish apology is now required. Life would be intolerable if we could not sometimes bury the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The German Marxist Walter Benjamin once conjured the tremendous image – derived from a painting by Klee – of the &lt;a href="http://www.marxists.org/reference/archive/benjamin/1940/history.htm" title=""&gt;Angel of History&lt;/a&gt;, its face turned always towards a past it cannot control, its wings open and forced backwards by a storm that drives it irresistibly into a future it cannot see. History is a mess. Bad things have happened. But there is no going back. There is only the imperfect future and the hope, which is sometimes no more than a hope, that we can do better next time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/john-f-kennedy"&gt;John F Kennedy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/kennedys"&gt;The Kennedys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/uk/northernireland"&gt;Northern Ireland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/martinkettle"&gt;Martin Kettle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33eaabeb/sc/38/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/sc/38/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/sc/38/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/sc/38/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/sc/38/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/sc/38/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/sc/38/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264655621/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33eaabeb/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Comment</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">Northern Ireland</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">The Kennedys</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">John F Kennedy</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 21:30:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/nov/20/jkf-asassination-history-victims-northern-ireland</guid><dc:creator>Martin Kettle</dc:creator><dc:subject>Comment is free</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:53Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422994469</dc:identifier><media:keywords>John F Kennedy, The Kennedys, Northern Ireland, United States, World news, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384980908317/Viking-kettle-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Mary Evans Picture Library / Ala/Alamy</media:credit><media:description>'The Danes invaded and pillaged parts of England centuries ago; but no modern Danish apology is now required. Life would be intolerable if we could not sometimes bury the past.' Photograph: Mary Evans Picture Library / Ala/Alamy</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384980914728/Viking-kettle-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Mary Evans Picture Library / Ala/Alamy</media:credit><media:description>'The Danes invaded and pillaged parts of England centuries ago; but no modern Danish apology is now required. Life would be intolerable if we could not sometimes bury the past.' Photograph: Mary Evans Picture Library / Ala/Alamy</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Orthodox economists have failed their own market test | Seumas Milne</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ea096e/sc/25/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Ccommentisfree0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Corthodox0Eeconomists0Efailed0Emarket0Etest/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/97152?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aorthodox-economists-failed-market-test%3A2000733&amp;ch=Comment+is+free&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Economics+%28Business%29%2CUniversity+teaching%2CFinancial+crisis+%28Business%29%2CStudents%2CBusiness%2CHigher+education+%28Universities+etc.%29%2CEducation%2CWorld+news%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Credit+Crunch%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CBusiness+Markets%2CEducation+Weekly+Education%2CStudents+Education%2CHigher+Education&amp;c6=Seumas+Milne&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+09%3A00&amp;c8=2000733&amp;c9=Blog&amp;c10=Comment&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c25=Comment+is+free&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Orthodox+economists+have+failed+their+own+market+test&amp;c66=Comment+is+free&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FComment+is+free%2FComment+is+free%2Fblog%2FComment+is+free" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Students are demanding alternatives to a free-market dogma with a disastrous record. That's something we all need&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From any rational point of view, orthodox economics is in serious trouble. Its champions not only failed to foresee the greatest crash for 80 years, but insisted such crises were a thing of the past. More than that, some of its leading lights played a key role in designing the disastrous financial derivatives that helped trigger the meltdown in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plenty were &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/education/2012/may/21/heist-century-university-corruption" title=""&gt;paid propagandists for the banks and hedge funds&lt;/a&gt; that tipped us off their speculative cliff. Acclaimed figures in a discipline that claims to be scientific hailed a &lt;a href="http://www.federalreserve.gov/Boarddocs/Speeches/2004/20040220/" title=""&gt;"great moderation"&lt;/a&gt; of market volatility in the runup to an explosion of unprecedented volatility. Others, such as the Nobel prizewinner Robert Lucas, insisted that economics had solved the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/01/05/opinion/05krugman.html?_r=1&amp;" title=""&gt;"central problem of depression prevention"&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any other profession that had proved so spectacularly wrong and caused such devastation would surely be in disgrace. You might even imagine the free-market economists who dominate our universities and advise governments and banks would be rethinking their theories and considering alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After all, the large majority of economists who &lt;a href="http://rwer.wordpress.com/2010/05/13/keen-roubini-and-baker-win-revere-award-for-economics-2/" title=""&gt;predicted the crisis&lt;/a&gt; rejected the dominant neoclassical thinking: from Dean Baker and Steve Keen to Ann Pettifor, Paul Krugman and David Harvey. Whether Keynesians, &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/education/2013/nov/18/post-keynesians-comeback" title=""&gt;post-Keynesians&lt;/a&gt; or Marxists, none accepted the neoliberal ideology that had held sway for 30 years; and all understood that, contrary to orthodoxy, deregulated markets don't tend towards equilibrium but deepen the economy's tendency to systemic crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alan Greenspan, the former chairman of the US Federal Reserve and high priest of deregulation, at least had the honesty to admit his view of the world had been proved "not right". The same cannot be said for others. Eugene Fama, architect of the "efficient markets hypothesis" underpinning financial deregulation, concedes &lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/johncassidy/2010/01/interview-with-eugene-fama.html" title=""&gt;he doesn't know what "causes recessions"&lt;/a&gt; – but insists his theory has been vindicated anyway. Most mainstream economists have carried on as if nothing had happened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of their students, though, have had enough. A revolt against the orthodoxy has been smouldering for years and now seems to have gone critical. Fed up with parallel universe theories that have little to say about the world they're interested in, &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/business/2013/oct/24/students-post-crash-economics" title=""&gt;students at Manchester University have set up a post-crash economics society&lt;/a&gt; with 800 members, demanding an end to monolithic neoclassical courses and the introduction of a pluralist curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They want other schools of economic thought taught in parallel, from Keynesian to more radical theories – with a better record on predicting and connecting with the real world economy – along with green and feminist economics. The campaign is spreading fast: to Cambridge, Essex, the London School of Economics and a dozen other campuses, and linking up with university groups in &lt;a href="http://rethinkingecon.wordpress.com/2013/06/26/a-global-revolt-in-economics/" title=""&gt;France, Germany, Slovenia and Chile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of the Manchester society's founders, &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/oct/28/economics-students-neoclassical-theory" title=""&gt;Zach Ward-Perkins&lt;/a&gt;, explains, he and a fellow student agreed after a year of orthodoxy: "There must be more to it than this." Neoclassical economics is after all built on a conception of the economy as the sum of the atomised actions of millions of utility-maximising individuals, where markets are stable, information is perfect, capital and labour are equals – and the trade cycle is bolted on as an afterthought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But even if it struggles to say anything meaningful about crises, inequality or ownership, the mathematical modelling erected on its half-baked intellectual foundations give it a veneer of scientific rigour, valued by students aiming for well-paid City jobs. Neoclassical economics has also provided the underpinning for the diet of deregulated markets, privatisation, low taxes on the wealthy and free trade we were told for 30 years was now the only route to prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its supporters have an "almost religious mentality", as Ha-Joon Chang – one of the last surviving independent economists at Keynes's Cambridge – puts it. Although claiming to favour competition, the neoclassicals won't tolerate any themselves. Forty years ago, &lt;a href="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/19/1384874895914/In-the-shadow-of-Keynes-S-001.jpg" title=""&gt;most economics departments were Keynesian&lt;/a&gt; and neoclassical economics was derided. That all &lt;a href="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/19/1384874829485/The-revolution-of-rationa-001.jpg" title=""&gt;changed with the Thatcher and Reagan ascendancy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In institutions supposed to foster debate, &lt;a href="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/19/1384874958145/The-prophets-who-lost-the-001.jpg" title=""&gt;non-neoclassical economists&lt;/a&gt; have been systematically purged from economics faculties. Some have found refuge in business schools, development studies and geography departments. In the US, corporate funding has been key. In Britain, peer review through the "research excellence framework" – which allocates public research funding – has been the main mechanism for the ideological cleansing of economics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, the sharp increase in student fees and the marketisation of higher education is creating a pressure point for students out to overturn this intellectual monoculture. The free marketeers are now being market-tested, and the customers don't want their product. Some mainstream academics realise that they may have to compromise, and have been colonising &lt;a href="http://ineteconomics.org" title=""&gt;a Soros-funded project&lt;/a&gt; to overhaul the curriculum, hoping to limit the scale of change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But change it must. The free-market orthodoxy of the past three decades not only helped create the crisis we're living through, but gave credibility to policies that have led to &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/books/2010/aug/29/ha-joon-chang-23-things" title=""&gt;slower growth, deeper inequality, greater insecurity&lt;/a&gt; and environmental degradation all over the world. Its continued dominance after the crash, like the neoliberal model it underpins, is about power not credibility. If we are to escape this crisis, both will have to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SeumasMilne" title=""&gt;&lt;em&gt;@SeumasMilne&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/business/economics"&gt;Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/education/universityteaching"&gt;University teaching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/business/financial-crisis"&gt;Financial crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/education/students"&gt;Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/education/higher-education"&gt;Higher education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/seumasmilne"&gt;Seumas Milne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ea096e/sc/25/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/sc/25/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/sc/25/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/sc/25/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/sc/25/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/sc/25/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/sc/25/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264654373/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea096e/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Comment</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Economics</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/education">Students</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/education">Higher education</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/education">University teaching</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/education">Education</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Financial crisis</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Business</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 21:00:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/nov/20/orthodox-economists-failed-market-test</guid><dc:creator>Seumas Milne</dc:creator><dc:subject>Comment is free</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:52Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422993171</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Economics, University teaching, Financial crisis, Students, Business, Higher education, Education, World news, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384979334476/seumas-economist-20-nov-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Sean Smith/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Ha-Joon Chang, one of the last surviving independent economists at Keynes's Cambridge: 'The supporters of neoclassical economics have an almost religious mentality.' Photograph: Sean Smith for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384979343573/seumas-economist-20-nov-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Sean Smith/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Ha-Joon Chang, one of the last surviving independent economists at Keynes's Cambridge: 'The supporters of neoclassical economics have an almost religious mentality.' Photograph: Sean Smith for the Guardian</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Overseeing bulk surveillance by intelligence agencies</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ea0983/sc/11/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Coversight0Ebulk0Esurveillance0Eintelligence0Eagencies/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/89727?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aoversight-bulk-surveillance-intelligence-agencies%3A2000609&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=NSA%2CUS+news%2CUS+national+security+defence+defense%2CWorld+news%2CNSA+files%2CData+protection+%28Govt.%2Findustrial+use+of+data%29&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CTechnology+Gadgets&amp;c6=&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+09%3A00&amp;c8=2000609&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Letter&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Overseeing+bulk+surveillance+by+intelligence+agencies&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FNSA" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I share Lord Falconer's&amp;nbsp; view that the framework for intelligence oversight is not "fit for purpose" (&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/17/threat-nsa-leaks-snowden-files" title=""&gt;Report&lt;/a&gt;, 18 November), but the former lord chancellor does not&amp;nbsp;seem to appreciate that "bulk surveillance" was legalised by the Interception of Communications Act 1985. As well as warrants in relation to named persons or premises, section 3 provided for warrants where the minister certified "the descriptions of intercepted material the examination of which he considers necessary… ". This was the legal basis for the Echelon system of trawling through satellite communications before the internet, exposed during the 1990s. This same provision was carried forward into section 8 of the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000. The chances of persuading governments and their intelligence agencies to give up this broad surveillance power are remote, but its exercise must be subject to greater oversight than hitherto.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Gill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Honorary senior research fellow, University of Liverpool&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/nsa"&gt;NSA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/us-national-security"&gt;US national security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/the-nsa-files"&gt;The NSA files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/data-protection"&gt;Data protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ea0983/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/sc/11/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/sc/11/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/sc/11/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/sc/11/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/sc/11/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/sc/11/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264654372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0983/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/technology">Data protection</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">The NSA files</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">US national security</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">NSA</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Letters</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/20/oversight-bulk-surveillance-intelligence-agencies</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:22Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422979743</dc:identifier></item><item><title>Barack Obama awards Bill Clinton and Oprah Winfrey with medal of freedom - video</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ea0009/sc/7/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0Cvideo0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cbarack0Eobama0Ebill0Eclinton0Eoprah0Ewinfrey0Emedal0Eof0Efreedom0Evideo/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The US president, Barack Obama, pays tribute to Bill Clinton and Oprah Winfrey at the medal of honour ceremony at the White House&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33ea0009/sc/7/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/sc/7/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/sc/7/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/sc/7/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/sc/7/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/sc/7/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/sc/7/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264652372/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33ea0009/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Barack Obama</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">US politics</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Bill Clinton</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio">Oprah Winfrey</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">John F Kennedy</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 20:14:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2013/nov/20/barack-obama-bill-clinton-oprah-winfrey-medal-of-freedom-video</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-20T20:14:54Z</dc:date><dc:type>Video</dc:type><dc:identifier>422992715</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Barack Obama, Bill Clinton, Oprah Winfrey, US politics, John F Kennedy, United States, World news</media:keywords><media:group><media:content fileSize="12284462" lang="" type="video/mp4" url="http://cdn.theguardian.tv/mainwebsite/2013/11/20/131120ObamaMedals-16x9.mp4" /><media:content fileSize="10723869" lang="" type="video/3gpp:small" url="http://cdn.theguardian.tv/3gp/small/2013/11/20/131120ObamaMedals_3gpSml16x9.3gp" /><media:content fileSize="19844819" lang="" type="video/3gpp:large" url="http://cdn.theguardian.tv/3gp/large/2013/11/20/131120ObamaMedals_3gpLg16x9.3gp" /><media:content lang="" type="video/m3u8" url="http://cdn.theguardian.tv/ad/2013/11/20/131120ObamaMedals/131120ObamaMedals.m3u8" /></media:group><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/11/20/1384978214513/President-Obama-Awards-Pr-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alex Wong/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>President Obama Awards Presidential Medal Of Freedom to Oprah winfrey Photograph: Alex Wong/Getty Images</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>How safe are the world's cities for cyclists?</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9fba9/sc/10/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Clifeandstyle0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Chow0Esafe0Eare0Eworlds0Ecities0Efor0Ecyclists/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/86304?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Ahow-safe-are-worlds-cities-for-cyclists%3A2000691&amp;ch=Life+and+style&amp;c3=G2&amp;c4=Cycling+%28Life+and+style%29%2CRoad+safety+%28News%29%2CFitness+%28Life+and+style%29%2CLife+and+style%2CLondon+%28News%29%2CUK+news%2CSweden%2CIndia+%28News%29%2CGermany%2CChina+%28News%29%2CNetherlands+%28News%29%2CParis+%28News%29%2CLos+Angeles+%28US+city%29&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CTriathalon%2CHealth%2CUnclassifed+Contributors&amp;c6=Richard+Orange%2CPhilip+Oltermann%2CJonathan+Kaiman%2CKim+Willsher%2CShaun+Walker%2CLizzy+Davies%2CPatrick+Kingsley%2CMatt+Seaton%2CHarriet+Sherwood%2CRory+Carroll%2CDavid+Byrne+%28Contributor%29&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+07%3A51&amp;c8=2000691&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Feature&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=How+safe+are+the+world%27s+cities+for+cyclists%3F&amp;c66=Life+and+style&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FLife+and+style%2FLife+and+style%2FCycling" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;The deaths of six cyclists in the past two weeks has highlighted the dangers of taking to London's busy streets. But what is&amp;nbsp;it like to cycle in other major cities around the world? From Amsterdam to Delhi, our writers report from the bike lanes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Malmö&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I arrived in Malmö two years ago, it was the free bicycle pumps, installed in convenient places on cycle paths, which showed me that, when it&amp;nbsp;comes to cycling in Sweden, Malmö leads the way. Sweden's third-largest city is laced with 500km (310 miles) of cycle lanes, more even than in Copenhagen, a short hop across the &lt;a href="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2012/12/19/1355946284040/The-Bridge-013.jpg" title=""&gt;Öresunds Bridge&lt;/a&gt;. About a quarter of all journeys in the city are already made by bike. That is an estimated 100,000 trips a day for the its 307,000 inhabitants. Stockholmers, by contrast, use bikes for fewer than 10% of trips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I take my daughter to day care in the morning on the back of my bike, the cycle lanes are packed with parents and commuters. Almost all my friends own &lt;a href="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/7/25/1374747234421/children-being-carried-in-001.jpg" title=""&gt;cargo bikes&lt;/a&gt;, which they use to ferry their young families to day care, or to do the weekly shop. Remarkably, in the 10 years from 2003 to 2012, the city has seen only 16 cyclists killed in an accident involving a car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Olle Evenäs, a traffic planner for Malmö, puts this down to the way the city has built its cycle lanes. "In Malmö we have two-way cycle lanes, every single track, which isn't the case in Copenhagen. We never have painted lanes as cycle tracks; we always have a dedicated surface which is separated from the car traffic by a divider and up a level from car traffic."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The law-abiding nature of the people also helps cut down on fatalities. For Swedes, cycling in the wrong direction on a cycle path or, worse still, on a pavement intended for pedestrians, elicits the sort of outrage people in the UK reserve for those dumping their rubbish on the pavement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city continues to try to cut car use, aiming to increase cycling's share of journeys to 30% by 2018. To do this it is spending almost 20m Swedish kroner a year (£19m) on various cycling programmes, with at least 400m kroner earmarked for 2012-19. "This is the money we know we have for sure, but we are going to be spending even more than that," says Evenäs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Orange&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Delhi&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Size is power on India's roads and in the&amp;nbsp;caste system of transport, cyclists rank just a notch above pedestrians and stray animals. Buses and SUVs rarely, if ever, give way to lesser mortals. Indeed, pedestrians attempting to cross a road here, even with children in tow, are invariably honked&amp;nbsp;at while drivers speed towards&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By and large, cycling is not a lifestyle choice for the middle classes. Rather, it&amp;nbsp;is the default mode of transport for those who cannot afford anything else.&amp;nbsp;Labourers, deliverymen and semi-skilled workers such as plumbers and carpenters use bicycles. They are India's struggling masses, not its moneyed elite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2012, according to India's &lt;a href="http://ncrb.nic.in/" title=""&gt;National Crime Records Bureau&lt;/a&gt;, a total of 168,301 people died on its roads. In New Delhi, that includes 78 cyclists and 501 pedestrians. There are nominal cycle lanes on some of the capital's main thoroughfares, but with seven million cars jostling for space, those lanes are often cannibalised by motorised rickshaws and scooters, leaving no safe space for bicyclists. Cyclists rarely wear helmets and there are no viable emergency services to ferry accident victims to&amp;nbsp;hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, some intrepid middle-class Indian and foreign expatriate cyclists have begun to brave Delhi's roads. Recognisable by their expensive bicycles, helmets and high-visibility vests, they can sometimes be spotted along the quieter avenues of colonial New Delhi. One company, &lt;a href="http://www.delhibycycle.com" title=""&gt;Delhi by Cycle&lt;/a&gt;, has even set up two-wheeled tours through the narrow, twisting lanes of the old city. But they start before dawn, before cars, motorbikes, cycle rickshaws, pushcarts, cows&amp;nbsp;and the ever-present crush of pedestrians appear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If cycling in London is dangerous, Delhi is like having a near-death experience every single time.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anu Anand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Berlin&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many ways, Berlin is a cyclists' paradise. Most major roads have clearly marked cycling lanes, either on the pavement or on the road itself. The age&amp;nbsp;range of cyclists is broader than in London: with old ladies and kids sharing lanes with bike couriers in Lycra, road behaviour tends to be less aggressive. Some major junctions even have a special set of traffic lights for cyclists, allowing them a head start ahead of&amp;nbsp;motorists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That doesn't mean there are no problems. Fifteen cyclists died in 2012, seven of them through collisions with lorries; 4,533 more were injured over the same period. According to the German Cycling Club (ADFC), one of the most common causes of accidents are cars turning into side streets at high speed and cutting off cyclists in the lanes to&amp;nbsp;their right. Berlin's many tram lines can also be a hazard: the track grooves are perfect for trapping the wheel of your average city bike.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In spite of being notoriously cash-strapped, Berlin has taken steps to make cycling safer. This month, the city authorities launched an online survey in order to&amp;nbsp;help identify trouble spots. On &lt;a href="https://radsicherheit.berlin.de" title=""&gt;radsicherheit.berlin.de&lt;/a&gt;, users can mark&amp;nbsp;dangerous junctions, blocked paths and road potholes, as well as recording "near-misses" that they didn't log with the police at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Berlin also expects its cyclists to&amp;nbsp;stick to the rules more than London does. One reason for this is self-policing: try going down a cycling path on the wrong side of the road, even in an alternative district such as Kreuzberg, and you will soon be bellowed at by other cyclists or by pedestrians. Cycling offences are not just punished with on-the-spot fines: any fine over €45 (£37.50) also comes with points that show up on your driving licence (which means that, in theory, you can end up with points on your licence before you have even passed your driving test).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, unlike Britain, Germany has a drink-drive limit for cyclists: a blood alcohol content of 0.16%, though some regions have recently tried to lower the limit to the same as that for cars (0.05%). This also explains the German word for a shandy: &lt;em&gt;Radler&lt;/em&gt; or "cyclist", because it&amp;nbsp;just about keeps you sober enough to&amp;nbsp;stay on your bike.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philip Oltermann&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Beijing&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beijing was once a city of bikes. Now it's a city of traffic. There are more than 5m cars in Beijing, and they have transformed its once-generous thoroughfares into a noxious, honking mass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cycling helps me rise above the noise. I bike 5km (3 miles) to work every day, weaving through Ming dynasty-era alleyways, gliding past shadowy government offices, darting among flatbed tricycles hauling mysterious metal tanks. The Chinese capital is notorious for its air pollution, and my commute isn't always pleasant. But when the smog lifts and the city snaps into focus, it's the highlight of my day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with the freedom comes a fair amount of risk. According to official statistics, cyclists were involved in &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3595633/" title=""&gt;more than 10,000&lt;/a&gt; of China's 67,759 traffic accident-related deaths in 2009. Scooters blast through red lights; cars park on the pavements. Nobody wears a helmet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last winter, I was riding to work when I collided with an auto-rickshaw. They are the sharks of the city's bike lanes – vault-sized motorised boxes that are almost as powerful as small cars, but are not required to play by the same rules. It was on the wrong side of the road. I veered left; the driver veered right; I hit the side of the carriage and fell over. The driver, a middle-aged man with oily hair, decided to play the defensive – he was clearly from the countryside, and if the accident was serious, my medical bills could have wiped out his savings. He pointed his finger at me, yelling. A crowd began to gather. I shot him a middle finger and pedaled away, my right knee bleeding, my handlebars askew.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2010, the Beijing government announced hopes that by 2015, nearly a&amp;nbsp;fourth of the city's residents would use cycling as their primary mode of transportation. It doesn't seem likely. The city is too much of a sprawl, its traffic too unruly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are other reasons, too. On Monday night, I returned to a restaurant where I had parked my one-speed Giant overnight, only to find it missing. A passerby saw me looking, and asked how long I'd left it outside. "Too long, I&amp;nbsp;guess," I said. "You should&amp;nbsp;know better," she replied. "This&amp;nbsp;is China."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Kaiman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Amsterdam&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the course of my 11 years of daily biking in Amsterdam, I have never worn the helmet I brought with me from the US. No one needs a helmet here. Instead of putting the onus on the cyclists to protect themselves, in Amsterdam the onus is on society to provide a safe environment to ride in. Here, everyone bikes: the young, the old, the tourists. It usually takes me less than an hour to spot three pregnant cyclists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had never realised how stressed I&amp;nbsp;was while biking in America until I biked with relative ease in Amsterdam. Despite the decades-old reputation of Amsterdam's cyclists for being "traffic anarchists" – riding through red lights, biking without lights at night, and so on – it is a chaos that works incredibly well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most motorists here are also cyclists, which enables them to better anticipate the behaviour of cyclists in traffic. Driving instructors teach new motorists to use their right hand to open their door, which forces the driver to turn, putting them in a better position to see if a cyclist is approaching from behind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amsterdam is by no means perfect. Cycling fatalities do occur – estimates say about six a year - but on nothing like the scale that they do in the British capital. And the Dutch do not rest on their laurels with the infrastructure they have created over the past 30 years. I&amp;nbsp;am always pleasantly amazed by how the city continues to be improved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pete Jordan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Paris &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paris is extremely proud of the fact it was the first capital to introduce a city-wide free bicycle scheme. Known as &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/travel/2008/oct/18/cyclingholidays-ethicalholidays-paris" title=""&gt;Vélib'&lt;/a&gt;, a combination of the words &lt;em&gt;vélo&lt;/em&gt; (bike) and &lt;em&gt;liberté&lt;/em&gt; (freedom), it was introduced in 2007 by Socialist mayor Bertrand Delanoë. Now approaching retirement, Delanoë considers it one of the great triumphs of his term in office. By 2012, when Vélib' was celebrating its fifth birthday, there were around 23,000 of the heavy grey bicycles in circulation, more than double the number when it was launched. There are now 1,700 bicycle "stations" – 1,400&amp;nbsp;of them in Paris itself and 300 in&amp;nbsp;surrounding towns. In 2007, there were just 750. Under the Socialists, the French capital has installed 652km (405 miles) of dedicated cycle routes for the 224,000 Parisians who have signed up to Vélib', a figure that will rise to 700km by the end of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Launching several thousand bicycles onto the city's roads in 2007 caused widespread safety concerns, but they have proven largely unfounded. While cycling around the Arc de Triomphe can be a perilous exercise, with cars coming from all directions following the now largely outdated &lt;a href="http://www.vendee-guide.co.uk/priority-a-droite.htm" title=""&gt;"priorité à droite"&lt;/a&gt; rule, the number of accidents involving cyclists between 2007 and 2012 was relatively low: 12 have died, eight of them while using a Vélib'. More than 660 have been injured, according to police, though most of the injuries were reported as "not serious". In 2010, 43 people died in accidents on Paris's streets and boulevards: two cyclists, 18 pedestrians, 17 motorcyclists and scooter riders and six vehicle drivers or passengers, according to the Paris Préfecture de Police. In 2011, &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2013/nov/19/boris-johnson-london-cyclists-headphones" title=""&gt;not a single cyclist died&lt;/a&gt;. Accident investigators say because there are more cyclists around, other road users have become more used to them and are giving them "greater respect".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rules of the road – "I don't ride on the pavement, I respect traffic lights and stop signs, I don't carry passengers and I don't ignore no entry signs" – are posted on each Vélib' bike.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Willsher&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Moscow&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With 10-lane highways cutting through its centre, roads covered in snow and ice for much of the year, and drivers who – to put it charitably – do not always obey the letter of the law, Moscow has never been much of a city for cyclists. Those who can afford a car brave the legendary traffic jams, while those that cannot use the ruthlessly efficient metro system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, however, as the chaos&amp;nbsp;of post-communist wild capitalism has subsided and thoughts have turned in some quarters to issues such&amp;nbsp;as quality of life and urban planning, bicycles have become a more visible part of Moscow's fabric. This year, a local equivalent of Boris bikes was even introduced, with the Bank of&amp;nbsp;Moscow funding 1,000 bikes and 74&amp;nbsp;rental points across the centre of the&amp;nbsp;city. It was free to use them for up to half an hour, and just 60p for an hour after that, for those who paid an initial registration fee. The bikes have&amp;nbsp;been removed with the onset of winter, but over the summer season nearly 50,000 Muscovites registered for the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the bikes were still mainly used for cycling along Moscow's embankments, through its newly renovated parks and along the pedestrianised boulevard ring that runs through the centre. Actually using a bike as a means of getting from A to B along normal roads is still a matter for the brave and the foolhardy, and cyclists on the roads are a rare sight indeed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shaun Walker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rome&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With its fabled seven hills, cobbled streets and notoriously chaotic traffic, Rome is not an obvious cycling paradise. A bike-sharing scheme launched in 2008 has been an abject failure. And, for what it's worth, helmets and hi-vis have never been included in any Italian's definition of &lt;em&gt;bella figura&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the risks to both health and&amp;nbsp;image, however, many Romans are choosing to brave the roads and get on their bikes. For the first time in decades, more bikes were sold than cars in the recession-hit Italy of 2011, a trend reflected predominantly in the north but also on the traffic-clogged streets of the capital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of those who do brave it insist the city's off-putting image is unfair: it is hard for cars to speed around the narrow, winding streets of the historic centre, they say. Moreover, Roman motorists, whatever their other defects, are used to looking out for people on two-wheels - it's just that those wheels tend to belong to a Vespa or Piaggio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But tragedies, of course, do happen. Last year, five people died in accidents involving bicycles, according to the city authorities; one person the year before that; three in 2010, and four in 2009. In July, a 60-year-old man called Domenico Calabrò was fatally injured in a collision with a car on the city's south-eastern outskirts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man who now finds himself at the centre of the city's cycling future is the mayor, Ignazio Marino, who was elected in June and has repeatedly spoken of the need to make Rome a more bike-friendly capital. He says he is considering various projects in order to boost cycle use, including the creation of parking lots for 10,000 bikes, a new, more successful cycle-sharing scheme, and 20km more cycle paths to add to the patchy existing network. Marino is himself a keen cyclist, often seen whizzing around town, security staff in tow, on a white Lombardo. Even for him, however, it&amp;nbsp;hasn't been straight-forward: in&amp;nbsp;July,&amp;nbsp;he fell off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cycling activists are pleased that their new "first citizen" is a bike-lover, but are still waiting to see if he will keep his promises, says Fausto Bonafaccia, president of the BiciRoma association. "The cycle path situation is improper for a city like Rome, the capital of Italy, where vegetation, disjointedness and potholes represent daily obstacles for those who want to travel by bike," he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Road safety … does not meet the minimum standards befitting a civilised country and cyclists are always at risk of having an accident in&amp;nbsp;the Roman traffic."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lizzy Davies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Cairo &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tell a local that you cycle in Cairo, and more often than not you will be met with a wide-eyed stare. Driving a car is dangerous and frustrating enough, with 42 annual road deaths per 100,000 Egyptians, &lt;a href="http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_traffic/countrywork/egy/en/index.html" title=""&gt;according to the World Health Organisation&lt;/a&gt;. Britain has just 2.75.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cairo's roads are &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/programmes/from_our_own_correspondent/8029015.stm" title=""&gt;chaotic&lt;/a&gt;, with cars paying little attention to road markings, and gridlocked streets common by mid-afternoon. Lane discipline is not a recognised concept, drivers often reverse down multi-lane highways, and cars will not stop for pedestrians seeking to cross a road until they step out into the speeding traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this environment, there is little concept of cycling as a means of getting across the city. Needless to say, there are no cycle lanes. Many deliverymen do use bikes to pedal around their neighbourhoods – perhaps Cairo's most fearless road-users are the cycling bakers who careen through traffic jams balancing vast trays of bread on their heads. But very few commuters cycle, put off by the perceived danger and the&amp;nbsp;lack of infrastructure. For some professionals, bikes are associated with the working class, and so have a social stigma – while some female cyclists report harassment from passersby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the city's few energetic bike advocates say that cyclists are slowly on the rise. When the Cairo Cycling Club was founded five years ago, it had just four members. Now it organises weekly recreational &lt;a href="http://www.cairobike.com/group-rides" title=""&gt;group rides&lt;/a&gt; through quieter districts that have sometimes attracted hundreds of cyclists. In&amp;nbsp;two provincial cities near Cairo, the authorities are &lt;a href="http://stpegypt.org/images/NGO%20Fayoum%20workshop_apr2013.pdf" title=""&gt;planning to encourage more&amp;nbsp;cycling&lt;/a&gt; along some main roads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are no exact figures, either for the number of Cairene cyclists or the number of annual cycling-related fatalities. But Ahmed el-Dorghamy, one of Cairo's most vocal cycling proponents, says there are more than 20,000 users of Egyptian online cycling groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The idea we want to get across is that it's not just a sporting activity," he &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-21629907" title=""&gt;told the BBC&lt;/a&gt; last year. "It can also be a means of transport in some areas of Cairo."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Kingsley&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;New York&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you commute by bike in New York City, you are still regarded by colleagues as something of a daredevil. And if you don't wear a helmet, they frankly think you are reckless. Mind you, this is a country where they wear helmets for the game they call football (which, actually, does have a serious head-injury problem).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But perceptions lag behind reality. New York has become a much more cycle-friendly city over the past decade or so of the Bloomberg administration. Cyclist fatalities have held steady over that time: in a good year, perhaps just a dozen; in a bad year, double that number. But bike use has tripled since 2000 and, with several hundred miles of new bike lanes put in, it is still growing fast. So, according to the City's "cycling risk indicator", the danger of serious injury has plummeted by 73% (between 2000 and 2011).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And New York is truly a bikeable city. Manhattan and the other boroughs are reasonably flat, and car ownership is the lowest of any American city. The views can be spectacular, whether you are flying down one of the big avenues in a canyon of Gotham skyscrapers or taking the riverside bike path along the Hudson on the west side. Earlier this year, the city got the Citibike bike-share scheme, our equivalent of Boris bikes. Despite teething troubles, the five-month-old rollout is mostly judged a great success – not least because it has not yet resulted in a single fatality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not everything is rosy. &lt;a href="http://www.transalt.org" title=""&gt;Transportation Alternatives&lt;/a&gt;, NYC's leading pro-bike campaign, has worked hard recently to make more of an issue of how poorly fatal accidents involving pedestrians or cyclists are often investigated by the NYPD. Just last weekend, an article in the New York Times asked provocatively: "Is it OK to kill cyclists?" But I take heart simply from the fact that the question is being asked: the mindset is&amp;nbsp;changing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My main tip from the mean streets: just watch out for the yellow cabs – they never pull over to drop people off, and passengers will fling the doors open on either side.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matt Seaton&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;is the Guardian's former cycling columnist and is now an editor at the New York Times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tel Aviv&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is flat, sunny and boasts a sweeping promenade hugging long golden beaches. There are 120km of cycle paths threading throughout the city, 1,500 public bikes for hire at an hourly rate, and 3,000 bicycle parking slots. Welcome to Tel Aviv, cycling heaven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That, at least, is the city council's vision. As part of a plan to turn Tel Aviv into a car-free city, it has promoted two-wheel transport, with the introduction two years ago of Tel-O-Fun, an Israeli version of Boris bikes, available for hire at around £8 for two and a half hours. A network of cycle paths has been established along roads and through parks, and an annual city bike ride attracted 20,000 participants in September (though 42 cyclists were injured). Helmets are encouraged, but not a legal requirement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to a poll last year, 14% of residents say it's their main form of transport.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But not everyone is in heaven. "A lot of the cycle paths are just painted areas of the pavement, interrupted by bus stops and with pedestrians wandering over them," says Ruthie Pliskin, a PhD student who cycles to university every day. "Even the paved ones along the roads are often blocked by parked cars. They're very narrow, and sometimes it's not even clear which direction you are supposed to cycle."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the city council's efforts, Pliskin says cycling is still a dangerous activity in Tel Aviv. "But it has the potential to be a great cycling city – even if you do need eight showers a day in the summer."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harriet Sherwood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Los Angeles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drivers rule Los Angeles, yet on balance the city is surprisingly safe for cycling. An expanding network of bicycle lanes is slowly making parts of LA friendlier to two wheels, turning a once eccentric form of transport almost hip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;About two cyclists are killed in traffic-related collisions in LA county each month, out of a total population of 10 million. Per capita, that is a lot better than many other big population centres in the US and elsewhere. The bad news is that 3% of road accident fatalities are cyclists, way above the US's national figure of 1.7%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mayor Antonio Villaraigosa became evangelical after he fell and broke his arm swerving from a taxi that cut him off on Venice boulevard in 2010. Within two years the city built 123 miles of new bikeways, nearly eight times the rate of the previous 40 years. There are now more than 430 miles of bike paths across the city. Not all cheered. Hollywood complained that a bright green, 6ft-wide lane, which runs for 1.4 miles through downtown's historic core, ruined the area's utility as an Anytown, USA, location. Worse, camera lights reflected the green on to everything else, including actors' faces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;California's governor, Jerry Brown, rejected a law obliging motorists to give cyclists at least 3ft of room while passing, or slow down. But advocacy groups such as the LA County Bicycle Coalition, and rider packs known as Midnight Ridazz and Wolfpack Hustle, and programmes such as CicLAvia, appear to be slowly winning the argument. LA's new mayor, Eric Garcetti, has pledged to continue bike-friendly policies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You still need strong nerves to cycle here. About 22 cyclists a year are killed or badly hurt in LA's epidemic of hit-and-runs – there are 20,000 cases annually. Veterans warn that one of the most perilous places is Beverly Hills: few lanes and inconsiderate drivers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rory Carroll&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why I like cycling in New York City&lt;br /&gt;By David Byrne&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ride everyday in New York City unless it's pouring rain or snow or the roads are icy – and that's actually not often. I&amp;nbsp;now know where the protected bike lanes are and I will go a block or two out of my way to use them. The protected ones make a huge difference, though the occasional delivery or municipal vehicle parks in them. Even&amp;nbsp;the &lt;a href="http://bikingrules.org/biking/laneprimer" title=""&gt;non-protected lanes&lt;/a&gt; – the ones in green and white paint that run alongside the traffic – feel much more secure. Having used bikes in London, I'm used to a lack of road space being allocated to cyclists. But it is, yes, a little scary sometimes back in London.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We used to do scary quite well in NYC, but we've mostly gotten over it. One does have to beware of limo and hire-car drivers who feel they are carrying people more important than us, and watch out for New Jersey plates, as they've rarely seen cyclists and pedestrians where they come from. Bike delivery guys riding the wrong way are another hazard, but maybe they'll fall in line eventually as well. NYC is easy – it's dense and fairly flat. The new bike-share program needs to expand and is already hugely popular. I see men in suits using it, so for me that means the whole thing has passed the tipping point and resistance is futile – best now to figure out how to make it all work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• This article was amended on 20 November 2013. A reference to deaths in road traffic accidents in Moscow in 2012 was incorrect and has been removed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/cycling"&gt;Cycling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/road-safety"&gt;Road safety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/fitness"&gt;Fitness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/uk/london"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/sweden"&gt;Sweden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/india"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/germany"&gt;Germany&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/china"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/netherlands"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/paris"&gt;Paris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/los-angeles"&gt;Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/richard-orange"&gt;Richard Orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/philip-oltermann"&gt;Philip Oltermann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/jonathan-kaiman"&gt;Jonathan Kaiman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/kim-willsher"&gt;Kim Willsher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/shaun-walker"&gt;Shaun Walker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/lizzydavies"&gt;Lizzy Davies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/patrick-kingsley"&gt;Patrick Kingsley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/mattseaton"&gt;Matt Seaton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/harrietsherwood"&gt;Harriet Sherwood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/rorycarroll"&gt;Rory Carroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/david-byrne-contributor"&gt;David Byrne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9fba9/sc/10/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/sc/10/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/sc/10/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/sc/10/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/sc/10/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/sc/10/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/sc/10/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264651403/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fba9/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">India</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle">Cycling</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Germany</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Road safety</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle">Fitness</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Netherlands</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Sweden</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">China</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Los Angeles</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">London</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle">Life and style</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Paris</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:51:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2013/nov/20/how-safe-are-worlds-cities-for-cyclists</guid><dc:creator>Richard Orange, Philip Oltermann, Jonathan Kaiman, Kim Willsher, Shaun Walker, Lizzy Davies, Patrick Kingsley, Matt Seaton, Harriet Sherwood, Rory Carroll, David Byrne</dc:creator><dc:subject>Life and style</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:23Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422987343</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Cycling, Road safety, Fitness, Life and style, London, UK news, Sweden, India, Germany, China, Netherlands, Paris, Los Angeles</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384966972650/Malmo-cycling-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Malmo cycling Photograph: Alamy</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384966978996/Malmo-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Malmö, with its dedicated cycle paths and huge take-up, is something of a cycling heaven. Photograph: Alamy</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384966338403/Dehli-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Roberto Schmidt/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Cyclists in Delhi must compete with rickshaws and the city's seven million cars. Photograph: Roberto Schmidt/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384967224259/Berlin-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Adam Berry/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Cyclists are well-catered for in Berlin, but it still saw 15 cyclist deaths in 2012. Photograph: Adam Berry/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384967440031/Beijing-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Mark Ralston/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Beijing hopes to have a quarter of its residents cycling by 2015. Photograph: Mark Ralston/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384966426234/Amsterdam-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">David R. Frazier Photolibrary/Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Amsterdam has long had a reputation for 'traffic anarchy', but if it's chaos, it works extremely well. Photograph: David R. Frazier Photolibrary/Alamy</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384966250753/Paris-Cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Christopher Thomond/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Paris has taken its Vélib' scheme of hire bikes to its heart. Photograph: Christopher Thomond for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384968766910/Moscow-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Christian Petersen/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Moscow's bike-hire scheme works well in summer – but is mothballed for the harsh winter months. Photograph: Christian Petersen/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384968410377/Rome-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Filippo Monteforte/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Rome's cyclists hope that their bike-friendly mayor can deliver. Photograph: Filippo Monteforte/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384967366030/Cairo-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Carsten Koall/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Cairo's most fearless road users must be its bakery delivery cyclists. Photograph: Carsten Koall/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384966664206/New-York-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Joseph Mcnally/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>New York's busy streets might seem daunting, but things are improving for cyclists. Photograph: Joseph Mcnally/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/online/2013/11/20/1384967952693/Tel-Aviv-cycling-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Bloomberg via Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Tel Aviv's flat, wide-open spaces are ideal for cycling. Photograph: Bloomberg via Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384976861071/David-Byrne-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">PR</media:credit><media:description>David Byrne riding his bike in Ride, Rise, Roar.</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Latest Zimmerman arrest is a reminder of just how broken US justice system is | Michael P Jeffries</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9fbaf/sc/11/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Ccommentisfree0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cgeorge0Ezimmerman0Egirlfriend0Eassault0Ewhite0Einnocence/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/56743?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Ageorge-zimmerman-girlfriend-assault-white-innocence%3A2000715&amp;ch=Comment+is+free&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Race+issues+%28News%29%2CGeorge+Zimmerman%2CTrayvon+Martin%2CUS+news%2CCrime+%28US%29%2CFlorida+%28News%29&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CUS+Elections&amp;c6=Michael+P+Jeffries&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+07%3A49&amp;c8=2000715&amp;c9=Blog&amp;c10=Comment&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c25=Comment+is+free&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=US&amp;c65=Latest+Zimmerman+arrest+is+a+reminder+of+just+how+broken+US+justice+system+is&amp;c66=Comment+is+free&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FComment+is+free%2FComment+is+free%2Fblog%2FComment+is+free" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;There's a presumption of white innocence. It reflects a society rife with institutional racism and prejudice against people of color&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;George Zimmerman is a disturbed and&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/19/george-zimmerman-choke-girlfriend-court"&gt; dangerous man&lt;/a&gt;. He is a man with a prolonged history of violence and poor judgment, who is yet to demonstrate remorse for taking the life of an innocent 17-year-old boy. The police chief who oversees Zimmerman's former Florida town agreed with a concerned citizen who wrote that Zimmerman was "&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/sep/13/george-zimmerman-florida-police-chief"&gt;a Sandy Hook [or] Aurora waiting to happen&lt;/a&gt;". &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This past summer Zimmerman was&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/aug/01/george-zimmerman-speeding-dallas"&gt; pulled over for speeding twice&lt;/a&gt;, and he participated in what appears to be a&lt;a href="http://www.salon.com/2013/07/26/does_george_zimmermans_car_hero_story_add_up/"&gt; staged car crash rescue &lt;/a&gt;to repair his soiled public image. His recent&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/18/george-zimmerman-held-jail-alleged-assault-girlfriend"&gt; arrest and felony charge&lt;/a&gt; for assaulting his girlfriend and threatening her with a firearm was met with little surprise by those of us who were devastated by outcome of the Trayvon Martin murder trial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As evidence mounts that Zimmerman is a menace to society, his character will come under increasing attack. These too-little-too-late public condemnations may feel like vindication in light of the injustice of the Trayvon Martin tragedy. But left unchecked, shouts of "I told you so!" will drown out the most crucial lessons of the saga. Zimmerman's personal failings and poor character played undeniable roles in Martin's death. But the injustice of the Martin murder is not enabled or sustained by "bad guys" like Zimmerman. Rather, it is produced by a broken criminal punishment system that reflects a society rife with institutional racism and prejudice against people of color. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the murder trial, defense attorney Mark O'Mara explicitly told the jury, "&lt;a href="http://fox4kc.com/2013/07/13/jurors-deliberate-for-second-day-in-zimmerman-trial/"&gt;Do not give anybody the benefit of the doubt except for George Zimmerman&lt;/a&gt;." Indeed, Zimmerman was given the benefit of the doubt by the legal system at every turn, and it began long before the trial started. It took sustained protests by Martin's parents, neighbors, and prominent civil rights advocates merely for Martin's killer to be arrested and brought to court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The presumption of white innocence is interwoven with the perceptions of black and Hispanic criminality and threat. Law professors &lt;a href="http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/opinion/2013/07/2013728142158307153.html"&gt;Allie Rolnick and Priscilla Ocen explain&lt;/a&gt; that self-defense laws like "&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/jun/13/george-zimmerman-trial-stand-your-ground"&gt;Stand Your Ground&lt;/a&gt;" are based on the idea of "reasonable fear" of severe bodily damage. So Zimmerman's "not guilty" verdict cannot be separated from condemnation of Martin as fearsome, despite the fact that Zimmerman pursued Martin in a vehicle and confronted the boy with a loaded gun. These codependent biases of white innocence and black guilt were crystalized through comparisons between Zimmerman (who is Hispanic but was perceived as white) and Marissa Alexander, a young black woman who was sent to prison after her "Stand Your Ground" defense claim was denied. Alexander, who fired warning shots to scare off her allegedly abusive husband, had her case &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/26/justice/florida-stand-your-ground-domestic-violence/"&gt;reopened after the Zimmerman verdict&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The plague of racial prejudice is not speculation. Stereotypes of black criminality run rampant and are &lt;a href="http://www.stanford.edu/group/mcslab/cgi-bin/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Seeing-black.pdf"&gt;empirically documented&lt;/a&gt; (pdf). Implicit and explicit racial prejudice against blacks and Hispanics has &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2223977/Racial-prejudice-increased-51-cent-Americans-Obama-took-office-finds-AP-poll.html"&gt;increased since President Obama took office&lt;/a&gt; in 2008. But the most disastrous impact of prejudice is not social unpleasantness, it is its codification and reinforcement in institutions like the police system and the courts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New York City's "&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2013/sep/20/stop-and-frisk-nypd-video"&gt;Stop and Frisk&lt;/a&gt;" policy and Arizona's immigrant surveillance law are two ongoing legal battles that exemplify these trends. Despite Obama's heartfelt response to the Zimmerman verdict, little action has been taken by the federal government and racial profiling and mass incarceration of blacks and Hispanics continues unchecked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea that we can address Zimmerman's transgressions without talking about the interplay of race, gender, and class is often framed as a commitment to neutrality. Judge Debra Nelson, who presided over the Zimmerman trial, actually banned the phrase "&lt;a href="http://usnews.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/06/21/19076806-zimmerman-judge-prosecutors-can-use-profiled-at-trial"&gt;racial profiling&lt;/a&gt;" from being used during proceedings. But silence about race, gender, and class is not neutrality. Colorblindness and "postracialism" require the active denial of continued oppression of people of color and the racist stigma that follows young black men and boys like Martin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zimmerman's latest arrest presents another opportunity for "neutrality" to manifest as active denial. Zimmerman's history of domestic violence cannot be treated as unrelated to his current predicament. As Salamishah Tillet pointed out during the murder trial, previous abuses of women and children are often &lt;a href="http://www.thenation.com/blog/175270/domestic-violence-and-george-zimmermans-defense"&gt;precursors to repeat offenses&lt;/a&gt;, especially when left unchecked by the criminal punishment system. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have to guard against attributing the Martin tragedy solely to Zimmerman's behavior and taking satisfaction in his disgrace. The Martin murder and the plague of domestic violence against women and children should inspire anger and righteous discontent. But rather than exhausting ourselves with calls to lock Zimmerman up and throw away the key, our indignation needs to be channeled and used as fuel for a long and unglamorous fight. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have to reform immigration policy, ban racial profiling, and repeal sentencing laws that disproportionately penalize people of color. We also have change the ways we talk about criminal punishment, innocence, and white male privilege. Neutrality is a smokescreen for racism and sexism inscribed in law and on our bodies. So we have to talk truthfully about race, gender, and class in courts, legislative halls, schools, and in our homes if we are to move towards justice. Catching the bad guy will not stop the crime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• This commentary was amended on 20 November to correct that Trayvon Martin was 17 years old.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/race"&gt;Race issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/george-zimmerman"&gt;George Zimmerman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/trayvon-martin"&gt;Trayvon Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/us-crime"&gt;US crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/florida"&gt;Florida&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/michael-jeffries"&gt;Michael P Jeffries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9fbaf/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/sc/11/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/sc/11/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/sc/11/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/sc/11/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/sc/11/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/sc/11/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264651402/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9fbaf/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Comment</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Trayvon Martin</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Florida</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Race issues</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">US crime</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">George Zimmerman</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:49:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/nov/20/george-zimmerman-girlfriend-assault-white-innocence</guid><dc:creator>Michael P Jeffries</dc:creator><dc:subject>Comment is free</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-20T20:29:09Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422990389</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Race issues, George Zimmerman, Trayvon Martin, United States, US crime, Florida</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/11/18/1384804382333/George-Zimmerman-006.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Seminole County sheriff's office</media:credit><media:description>George Zimmerman. Photograph: Seminole County sheriff's office</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/19/1384891642262/0ab7cebd-5897-4730-9888-709962cecdff-460x276.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Joe Burbank/AP</media:credit><media:description>George Zimmerman listens to defense counsel Daniel Megaro at this week's hearing. Photograph: Joe Burbank/AP</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Ikea France executives under investigation amid spying accusations</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9cbc0/sc/25/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cbusiness0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cikea0Efrance0Eexecutives0Eformal0Einvestigation0Espying0Eaccusations/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/65367?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aikea-france-executives-formal-investigation-spying-accusations%3A2000650&amp;ch=Business&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Ikea+%28Business%29%2CRetail+industry+%28Business+sector%29%2CBusiness%2CFrance%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CBusiness+Markets&amp;c6=Kim+Willsher&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+07%3A33&amp;c8=2000650&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Ikea+France+executives+under+investigation+amid+spying+accusations&amp;c66=Business&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FBusiness%2FBusiness%2FIkea" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Head of Ikea France among those accused of employing private detectives to snoop on employees, particularly union activists, and even unhappy clients&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Three senior Ikea executives in France were put under investigation on Wednesday over allegations they spied on disgruntled customers and former staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The head of Ikea France is among those accused of employing a firm of private detectives to snoop on individual employees, particularly union activists, job applicants and even unhappy customers, and of fraudulently obtaining personal information from police files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A judge decided there was enough evidence to formally &lt;em&gt;mis en examen&lt;/em&gt; (the equivalent of being charged) Stefan Vanoverbeke, the chief executive of Ikea France, his predecessor Jean-Louis Baillo and chief financial officer Dariusz Rychert, who were arrested on Monday and held for questioning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under French law, the men had to be formally put under investigation within 24 hours or freed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since January, a total of 10 people have been arrested and put under investigation for "fraudulent use of personal information", including four police officers and Ikea's former head of security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The case is hugely damaging to the reputation of the flagship Swedish company famed for its family-friendly but infuriatingly difficult to assemble flat-pack furniture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The accused are said to have requested a range of personal data, including criminal records and confidential details about the targets' dealings with the police or courts, even as witnesses or victims. Scores of people were alleged to have been snooped on, including a union official.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the satirical magazine Le Canard Enchainé obtained and published emails allegedly between Ikea's management in France and Sûreté International suggesting the security company was obtaining information from the national police information system on behalf of Ikea. The magazine said Ikea agreed to pay Sûreté International €80 (£66) for each request for information and that up to 200 demands were made at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two unions have filed legal complaints against Ikea, accusing it of snooping on hundreds of people over a period of at least five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the claims is that Ikea asked investigators to find out if a customer, who was suing the company for €4,000 (£3,350), owned her own property or was known to the police. Other accusations centre on the tracing of car registration numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vanoverbek's lawyer, Alexis Gulbin, said his client denied involvement. "It was he who took corrective measures as soon as the problems were detected," Gulbin said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ikea France suspended and later fired the head of its risk management department last year along with three top-level executives, before publishing a new code of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement in 2012, Christophe Naudin, head of Sûreté International, told journalists last year it had "consultancy and security contracts" with Ikea, but flatly denied snooping for the firm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If found guilty of fraudulently using personal information, the accused face up to five years in prison and €300,000 in fines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/business/ikea"&gt;Ikea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/business/retail"&gt;Retail industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/france"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/kim-willsher"&gt;Kim Willsher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9cbc0/sc/25/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/sc/25/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/sc/25/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/sc/25/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/sc/25/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/sc/25/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/sc/25/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264617450/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9cbc0/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Retail industry</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">France</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Business</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Ikea</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:33:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/business/2013/nov/20/ikea-france-executives-formal-investigation-spying-accusations</guid><dc:creator>Kim Willsher</dc:creator><dc:subject>Business</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:54Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422982168</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Ikea, Retail industry, Business, France, Europe, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384969572976/The-entrance-of-an-IKEA-s-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Remy De La Mauviniere/AP</media:credit><media:description>The entrance of an IKEA store in Plaisir, west of Paris. A judge decided there was enough evidence to formally charge Stefan Vanoverbeke, the chief executive of Ikea France, his predecessor Jean-Louis Baillo and chief financial officer Dariusz Rychert. Photograph: Remy De La Mauviniere/AP</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384969580062/The-entrance-of-an-IKEA-s-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Remy De La Mauviniere/AP</media:credit><media:description>The entrance of an IKEA store in Plaisir, west of Paris. A judge decided there was enough evidence to formally charge Stefan Vanoverbeke, the chief executive of Ikea France, his predecessor Jean-Louis Baillo and chief financial officer Dariusz Rychert. Photograph: Remy De La Mauviniere/AP</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>EU backs move to boost numbers of female non-executive directors</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9ed58/sc/24/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Ceu0Efemale0Enonexecutive0Edirectors0Equotas0Ewomen/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/54339?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aeu-female-nonexecutive-directors-quotas-women%3A2000705&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=European+Union+EU+%28News%29%2CGender+%28News%29%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CBusiness&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CBusiness+Markets%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CPolicy+Society&amp;c6=Reuters&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+07%3A30&amp;c8=2000705&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=EU+backs+move+to+boost+numbers+of+female+non-executive+directors&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FEuropean+Union" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Legislators back rules demanding firms choose women when men are equally qualified – but stop short of quotas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European parliament has backed rules that would give women preference for non-executive posts at companies, after plans for a mandatory quota to get women into top jobs were scrapped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rules demand that companies give non-executive directorships to women where there is no male candidate who is better qualified, until they reach a target of four in 10 being women.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The parliament has made the first cracks in the glass ceiling that continues to bar female talent from the top jobs," said EU justice commissioner Viviane Reding, who launched the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the draft law envisages possible fines for firms that ignore selection rules, it has been softened from imposing a quota with a penalty. Nor do the rules help women aiming for top management roles, such as chief executive. They also exempt smaller companies and those that are not listed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only about 17% of non-executive board members in the EU's largest companies are women. In Britain, women hold 17.4% percent of directorships, up from 12.5% in 2010; only four CEOs at FTSE 100 companies are women.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If endorsed, the rules will take seven years to come into full force. Countries are now required to sign off on the law but are divided on whether pan-European rules on positive discrimination are necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Britain and Germany have argued against mandatory quotas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Men dominate boardrooms in the region, and many women who have risen through company ranks resent quotas because they can be seen as suggesting that women have not been promoted on merit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only Norway, which is not a member of the bloc, has enforced a 40% quota since 2009, although critics say this has been achieved in part thanks to a small number of women holding non-executive positions in multiple companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It is essential for listed companies to evolve so as to include highly skilled women in their decision-making processes," said Rodi Kratsa-Tsagaropoulou, a member of the parliament who is playing a central role in shaping the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/eu"&gt;European Union&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/gender"&gt;Gender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9ed58/sc/24/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/sc/24/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/sc/24/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/sc/24/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/sc/24/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/sc/24/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/sc/24/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264700334/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e9ed58/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">European Union</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Gender</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/business">Business</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:30:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/20/eu-female-nonexecutive-directors-quotas-women</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:48Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422989444</dc:identifier><media:keywords>European Union, Gender, Europe, World news, Business</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384975714348/Karren-Brady--006.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Linda Nylind</media:credit><media:description>Karren Brady: a non-executive director of Mothercare and Arcadia Group. Photograph: Linda Nylind</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384975722607/Karren-Brady--011.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Linda Nylind</media:credit><media:description>Karren Brady: a non-executive director of Mothercare and Arcadia Group. Photograph: Linda Nylind</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>How does the world holiday?</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e96bd1/sc/10/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cuk0Enews0Cshortcuts0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cwhich0Ecountry0Emost0Eannual0Eleave/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/14678?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Awhich-country-most-annual-leave%3A2000634&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=G2&amp;c4=UK+news%2CUS+news%2CWork-life+balance%2CLife+and+style%2CWork+and+careers%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CFamily+and+Relationships&amp;c6=Paula+Cocozza&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+07%3A18&amp;c8=2000634&amp;c9=Blog&amp;c10=Blogpost%2CFeature%2CNews&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c25=Shortcuts&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=How+does+the+world+holiday%3F&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FUnited+States" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Americans aren't using their holiday entitlement, says a new survey. Maybe they should move to Hong Kong, where you get just 14 days. And where's best for those who like lots of time off?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Americans are slacking when it comes to slacking off: they are not taking all their holiday entitlement. It is not as if they get much to start with – just 14 days – but, on average, employees in the US took only 10 of them in the past year. This is clearly why &lt;a href="http://viewfinder.expedia.com/features/2013-vacation-deprivation-study" title=""&gt;Expedia's annual survey&lt;/a&gt; of holiday habits is&amp;nbsp;troublingly entitled Vacation Deprivation study. So how do other countries compare?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/holiday-entitlement-rights" title=""&gt;Statutory holiday leave is 5.6 weeks a year&lt;/a&gt;, though that can include the eight bank holidays. Somehow, being the only country to include a decimal point in its calculation seems a bit grudging, even though the entitlement itself is quite generous (28 days if you work a five-day week).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Australia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The website &lt;a href="http://www.workingin-australia.com/jobs/job-tools/annual-leave#.UoyYy78Zvlc" title=""&gt;Working in Australia&lt;/a&gt; claims the country "is kind to its employees when it comes to annual leave". They also call it "recreation leave", which sounds promising. Standard entitlement is four weeks a year, but long-service leave is awarded after 10 years with the same company – after 15 years, you could be up to 13 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panama&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A hefty &lt;a href="http://www.terralex.org/publication/p80128a914f" title=""&gt;30 days' leave is standard&lt;/a&gt;. In practice, you are looking at a six-week holiday or two three-week holidays. Six weeks off sounds great, but think how hideous it would be going back to work afterwards, knowing that there were 10 and a half months until the next break. Hold on, though. By law, in addition to their annual salary, &lt;a href="http://www.acc.com/legalresources/quickcounsel/nerip.cfm" title=""&gt;Panamanians are paid for&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;"13th month".&lt;/a&gt; Since they clearly&amp;nbsp;don't have to work for it, that must feel like a kind of holiday, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jersey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not much island life here. Employees are entitled to just &lt;a href="http://www.jacs.org.je/legislation/the-employment-law-(jersey)-2003/minimum-rest-periods-and-annual-leave/" title=""&gt;two weeks&lt;/a&gt;' paid annual leave a year, plus bank holidays. (This is slightly less than you get in New Jersey, which is &lt;a href="http://www.state.nj.us/csc/about/about/title4a/ch6_1.html#2" title=""&gt;12 working days&lt;/a&gt;.) Many workers, such as &lt;a href="http://www.gov.je/Working/WorkingForTheStates/NursingJersey/Pages/WorkingNurseJersey.aspx" title=""&gt;nurses&lt;/a&gt;, get more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://" title=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work for a year and you have earned seven days' holiday to be taken the next year. After the end of your second year, you can earn an extra day for every year of service. This incentive stops after nine years, when you reach your maximum of 14 days' holiday. If that feels excessive, you can sell up to four days back to your employer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regularly tops the polls for best &lt;a href="http://www.hsp.com/blog/2012/4/why-everyone-wants-work-france" title=""&gt;provision of annual leave&lt;/a&gt;. Employees get 25 days' holiday. Plus 11 public holidays. Then there is RTT which stands for réduction de temps de travail. Even to a non-speaker of French, the words "reduction" and "travail" stand out. This can amount to an additional 10 days a year. The Expedia research found that, unlike their US counterparts, French workers took all the vacation available to them in the past year. But did it make them happy? Nine out of 10 French respondents described themselves as strongly or somewhat vacation-deprived. Apparently, they need a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/money/work-life-balance"&gt;Work-life balance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/money/work-and-careers"&gt;Work &amp; careers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/paulacocozza"&gt;Paula Cocozza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e96bd1/sc/10/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/sc/10/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/sc/10/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/sc/10/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/sc/10/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/sc/10/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/sc/10/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264649888/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e96bd1/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Blogposts</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle">Life and style</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/money">Work-life balance</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/money">Work &amp; careers</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:18:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/shortcuts/2013/nov/20/which-country-most-annual-leave</guid><dc:creator>Paula Cocozza</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:27Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422981448</dc:identifier><media:keywords>UK news, United States, Work-life balance, Life and style, Work &amp; careers, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384971826960/Holiday-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Getting away from it all … easier in some countries than others. Photograph: Alamy</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384971833102/Holiday-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Getting away from it all … easier in some countries than others. Photograph: Alamy</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Diane Disney Miller obituary</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e954ad/sc/38/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cfilm0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cdiane0Edisney0Emiller/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/36896?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Adiane-disney-miller%3A2000581&amp;ch=Film&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Walt+Disney+Company%2CFilm%2CUS+news%2CCulture%2CAnimation+%28Film+genre%29&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CBusiness+Markets%2CFilm+Reviews&amp;c6=Brian+Sibley&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+07%3A11&amp;c8=2000581&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Obituary&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Diane+Disney+Miller+obituary&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FFilm%2FWalt+Disney+Company" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Daughter of Walt, she played a key role in safeguarding the Disney legacy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Diane Disney Miller was born, the Los Angeles Times announced: "Mickey Mouse has a daughter." It was a testament to the fame of her father, &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/theguardian/2011/dec/16/from-the-archive-walt-disney-dies-1966" title=""&gt;Walt Disney&lt;/a&gt;, and the cartoon star on whose popularity one of the great entertainment empires of the world would be built. For Diane, who has died aged 79 as a result of complications following a fall, this might have been the prelude to a life of celebrity, but her parents shielded her from all that. There was a family story that when, as a child, Diane discovered from school friends that she had a famous father, she asked him, "Are you Walt Disney? &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; Walt Disney?" and, on being told that he was, asked for his autograph. Diane, who tended to dismiss this as a piece of embellishment, personally eschewed the limelight for almost 60 years until increasingly negative publicity about her father prompted her to publicly defend his reputation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early 1940s, with her adopted sister, Sharon, and their mother, Lillian, she was instrumental in drawing her father's attention to a much-loved book, Mary Poppins. It was an introduction that initiated Disney's 20-year quest to secure the film rights to PL Travers's character and is key to the plot of the film Saving Mr Banks, starring Emma Thompson and Tom Hanks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diane's other significant contribution to her father's career was providing the impetus and inspiration for the creation of Disneyland, the beginning of what is now a worldwide theme-park business. "In taking my sister and I to playgrounds," she once said, "he realised there was nothing for grown-ups to do."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many years, her only brush with public life was upon the publication, in 1956, of the first biography of her father, previewed in the Saturday Evening Post as "My Dad Walt Disney: the intimate story of America's best-loved least-known genius told by his daughter." In truth, The Story of Walt Disney "by Diane Disney Miller as told to Pete Martin" was drawn largely from Disney's own interviews with the popular Hollywood biographer, but cast in the form of a daughter's memoir rather than as her father's autobiography, to provide the recently married Diane with a source of personal income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years earlier, as a result of a blind date, she had met and married Ron Miller, a professional athlete who later played football for the Los Angeles Rams and, on retiring from the game after an injury, joined his father-in-law's studio. During those years, the Millers had seven children and Diane led a very private life as a wife and mother.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following Walt Disney's death, Ron Miller was appointed company president and then chief executive, a role he held until being ousted in a very public corporate coup in 1984, whereupon the couple left Hollywood for San Francisco and the Napa Valley. They ran a winery and later started the successful Silverado Vineyards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was the publication, in 1993, of Marc Eliot's iconoclastic biography &lt;a href="http://articles.philly.com/1993-07-28/entertainment/25977975_1_hollywood-s-dark-prince-marc-eliot-disney-research" title="More about Walt Disney: Hollywoods Dark Prince"&gt;Walt Disney: Hollywood's Dark Prince&lt;/a&gt; that caused Diane and her mother to make a public stand, denouncing the book for its negative interpretation of Disney's personality and relationships, and challenging the accuracy of claims such as that Disney had acted as an FBI informant. It was the latest in a trend for revisionist readings of the Disney legend and when, a few years later, Diane and I made a radio series for the BBC about her father, she told me: "It's very important that Walt Disney the man is known for exactly who and what he was, and not some distortion."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As well as fearlessly championing her father's memory, she was instrumental in ensuring the realisation of the Walt Disney Concert Hall in Los Angeles as a legacy. It had been inaugurated with a gift of $50m from Disney's widow and had a visionary design by Frank Gehry. The venture became snared in a decade of delays, rising costs and an attempt to remove Gehry from the project, but Diane supported the designs and fought for the creation of the arts venue that would become home to the Los Angeles Philharmonic. With further substantial donations from the Disney family, the hall was completed in 2003. "I wanted something," said Diane, "that would bear my father's name, that would come from his wealth but not be commercial."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Becoming increasingly at ease with her public persona, Diane created the Disney Family Foundation, backed the making of the 2001 film documentary Walt: The Man Behind the Myth, contributed to programmes and publications about the work of her father and, most recently, oversaw the creation of the Disney Family Museum in San Francisco. A couple of years before its opening in 2009, I clambered about the dusty, debris-strewn shell of the building while she described to me how it would look when it was complete. In her excitement and enthusiasm, it was impossible not to see someone who was very much her father's daughter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diane is survived by her husband, their seven children, Christopher, Joanna, Tamara, Jennifer, Walter, Ronald and Patrick, and 13 grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;• &lt;/em&gt;Diane Disney Miller, philanthropist, born 18 December 1933; died 19 November 2013&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/film/walt-disney-company"&gt;Walt Disney Company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/film/animation"&gt;Animation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/brian-sibley"&gt;Brian Sibley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e954ad/sc/38/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/sc/38/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/sc/38/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/sc/38/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/sc/38/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/sc/38/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/sc/38/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264585593/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954ad/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">Obituaries</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/culture">Culture</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/film">Animation</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/film">Film</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/film">Walt Disney Company</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:11:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/film/2013/nov/20/diane-disney-miller</guid><dc:creator>Brian Sibley</dc:creator><dc:subject>Film</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-20T19:19:24Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422977240</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Walt Disney Company, Film, United States, Culture, Animation</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384968974111/Diane-Disney-left-with-he-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Daily Mail/Rex/Daily Mail/Rex</media:credit><media:description>Diane Disney, left, with her father, Walt, and sister, Sharon, with a model of Donald Duck in 1951. Photograph: Daily Mail/Rex</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384968980301/Diane-Disney-left-with-he-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Daily Mail/Rex/Daily Mail/Rex</media:credit><media:description>Diane Disney Miller, left, alongside her father, Walt, and sister, Sharon, with a model of Donald Duck in 1951. Photograph: Daily Mail/Rex</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Synod's vote for female bishops allows resistance to flourish another day</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e954b0/sc/11/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cchurch0Eengland0Efemale0Ebishops0Eresistance/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/53629?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Achurch-england-female-bishops-resistance%3A2000687&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Anglicanism+-+Church+of+England+%28News%29%2CReligion+%28News%29%2CChristianity+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CWomen+and+women%27s+interests%2CLife+and+style%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CWomen&amp;c6=Andrew+Brown&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+07%3A06&amp;c8=2000687&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Synod%27s+vote+for+female+bishops+allows+resistance+to+flourish+another+day&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FAnglicanism" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Supporters of female bishops have made obvious gains – but why do the opponents believe they've done well too?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overwhelming vote on Wednesday by the Church of England's &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/20/church-england-approves-female-bishops-plan" title=""&gt;General Synod in favour of the legislation for female bishops&lt;/a&gt; shows that it can learn from its mistakes just as a dinosaur that came up against an electric fence could learn after many years to stop leaning on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the deal is not yet done, it seems unlikely that the proposed legislation will fail between now and next summer. What is improbable is that both supporters and opponents think they have done better than they would have last November, when the house of laity failed by a tiny margin to achieve the two-thirds majority necessary to pass the legislation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supporters of female bishops have made obvious gains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prime minister David Cameron has let it be known that he will fast-track them into the House of Lords when they arrive. Female bishops will be bishops, legally and unequivocally. Women will be able to become archbishops and to hold any other post in the church once the legislation has been passed, and no one will be able to pretend they don't exist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what is it that opponents believe they have gained?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core of the resistance is the conservative evangelical block, who object on grounds of straightforward patriarchy; they believe the Bible mandates that women submit to male authority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems certain that one from this block will be promoted to bishop – at present there is not one of the Church's 112 bishops who shares their views. And they are confident that they can no more be forced to do anything they don't want by a female bishop than they can at present be compelled by a male one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Above all, the more politically savvy among them understand that this compromise allows them to live and flourish another day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The backlash against them after last &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/belief/2012/nov/20/women-bishops-debate-suicide-note" title=""&gt;November's fiasco&lt;/a&gt; was so strong that moves were made to unseat Dr Philip Giddings, a prominent conservative evangelical who is also chairman of the synod's house of laity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Guardian has seen Giddings' reflections on the legislation, intended for fellow evangelicals only. He is quite clear that without conceding on this issue his faction would have suffered horribly in the upcoming synod election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He writes: "The issues which will be (indeed already are being) brought before us in relating to marriage, family, human sexuality; and, even more critically, the uniqueness and sufficiency of Jesus Christ as Saviour and Lord. To sustain a biblically orthodox position for the Church of England on those issues we need to maximise our representation in future synods. To achieve that, we need to deal with the women bishops now and get it off the agenda."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What this means is that the synod will spend the next five years agreeing about female bishops, but wrangling interminably about gay people, whether clergy or laity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dinosaur will lumber across the paddock till it finds another electric fence to lean against.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/anglicanism"&gt;Anglicanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/religion"&gt;Religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/christianity"&gt;Christianity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/women"&gt;Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/andrewbrown"&gt;Andrew Brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e954b0/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/sc/11/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/sc/11/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/sc/11/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/sc/11/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/sc/11/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/sc/11/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264585592/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e954b0/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Anglicanism</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle">Women</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle">Life and style</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Christianity</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Religion</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:06:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/20/church-england-female-bishops-resistance</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Brown</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:33Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422986861</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Anglicanism, Religion, Christianity, World news, Women, Life and style, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384974005992/Reverend-Rosie-Harper-sta-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Peter Macdiarmid/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Reverend Rosie Harper stands in the doorway of the now unused 'Bishops Noes' voting lobby before speaking to the general Synod. Photograph: Peter Macdiarmid/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/11/20/1384974015817/Reverend-Rosie-Harper-sta-006.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Peter Macdiarmid/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Reverend Rosie Harper stands in the doorway of the now unused 'Bishops Noes' voting lobby before speaking to the General Synod. Photograph: Peter Macdiarmid/Getty Images</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Fifa wants 'fair conditions' quickly for Qatar's World Cup workers</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e8f1ae/sc/11/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cfootball0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cfifa0Eqatar0Eworld0Ecup0Esepp0Eblatter/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/17055?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Afifa-qatar-world-cup-sepp-blatter%3A2000639&amp;ch=Football&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Sepp+Blatter%2CFifa%2CWorld+Cup+2022+%28Football%29%2CFootball%2CQatar+%28News%29%2CSport&amp;c5=Football+World+Cup%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Owen+Gibson&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+05%3A53&amp;c8=2000639&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Fifa+wants+%27fair+conditions%27+quickly+for+Qatar%27s+World+Cup+workers&amp;c66=Sport&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FSport%2FFootball%2FSepp+Blatter" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;• Sepp Blatter admits abuse of migrant workers is 'unacceptable'&lt;br /&gt;• Union leader warns 2022 World Cup could move from Qatar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fifa has said "fair working conditions with a lasting effect must be introduced quickly in Qatar" after Sepp Blatter admitted that widespread abuse of migrant workers was "unacceptable" following a meeting with international union leaders in Zurich.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World football's governing body has come under pressure to act in the wake of a Guardian investigation that revealed the scale of the abuse of migrant workers in Qatar who are building the infrastructure for the 2022 World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blatter recently travelled to Doha to meet with the emir of Qatar, Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani, and subsequently gave a press conference in which he said the country's rulers were "on the right track" in dealing with the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But after meeting with Wolfgang Niersbach, president of the Confederation of German Trade Unions, and Michael Sommer, president of the International Trade Union Confederation, Fifa said that the trio had agreed that "fair working conditions must be introduced quickly, consistently and on a sustained basis in Qatar".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sommer said the trade union movement would not rest until conditions were "fundamentally transformed" but that Fifa made it clear they took their "responsibilities on social policy seriously". He added: "Fifa recognises that its international significance brings a responsibility to influence decision-makers in Qatar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Qatar must guarantee the core labour standards of the International Labour Organisation, end discrimination and forced labour and allow freedom of association for its 1.3 million migrant workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The direction being taken by Fifa in this sense is welcome, and respects the concerns of people who live for the 'people's game'. We as trade unions maintain our demand: if Qatar does not respond properly, then consequences must follow, and the World Cup be taken from Qatar."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ITUC has warned that as many as 4,000 migrant workers could die before a ball is kicked in 2022, while a new in-depth Amnesty report last Sunday revealed wide-scale and endemic mistreatment of workers, many of whom are tied to their employer under the kafala system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blatter admitted that the situation was "unacceptable" but the Fifa president said publicity generated by the controversial decision to award the World Cup to Qatar in 2022 had helped draw attention to the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Economic and political leaders must contribute to improving the unacceptable situation in Qatar. That is why I welcome the initiative shown by the DFB [German football federation] and ITUC because together we can achieve change," he said. "I am convinced Qatar is taking the situation very seriously. These very discussions about Qatar show what an important role football can play in generating publicity and thus bringing about change."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Human rights groups including Amnesty and Human Rights Watch are hopeful the international pressure building on the Qatari authorities will lead to concrete action. But they want to see meaningful practical steps, &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/football/2013/nov/14/zahir-belounis-letter-pep-guardiola-zinedine-zidane-qatar-trapped" title=""&gt;such as an end to the exit visa system that is also keeping French footballer Zahir Belounis trapped in the country&lt;/a&gt;, to prove their seriousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After meetings with Fifa as long ago as 2011 the Qatari government promised to take action but Amnesty's investigators still found widespread mistreatment of migrant workers by subcontractors effectively engaged in forced labour for major construction groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report, based on two recent investigations in Qatar and scores of interviews, found workers living in squalid, overcrowded accommodation exposed to sewage and sometimes without running water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It found that many workers, faced with mounting debts and unable to return home, have suffered "severe psychological distress", with some driven to the brink of suicide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Theo Zwanziger, the German Fifa executive committee member who helped to convene the talks at Fifa's $100m headquarters in Zurich, said: "The aim is to be in a position to report on concrete measures for Qatar at the executive committee meeting in March 2014. Large companies must be reminded of their duties in this area. The international community must also accept its responsibility."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zwanziger will be handed responsibility for ongoing dialogue with international trade union groups and human rights groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The awarding of the World Cup and the considerable public exposure gives us the opportunity to point out irregularities and to exact lasting change," said Niersbach. "If we succeed, then a lot will have been achieved. It was a matter of priority for us to quickly bring together the International Trade Union Confederation and Fifa as contractual partners for Qatar."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/football/sepp-blatter"&gt;Sepp Blatter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/football/fifa"&gt;Fifa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/football/world-cup-2022"&gt;World Cup 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/qatar"&gt;Qatar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/owengibson"&gt;Owen Gibson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e8f1ae/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/sc/11/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/sc/11/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/sc/11/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/sc/11/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/sc/11/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/sc/11/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264645026/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e8f1ae/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/football">Fifa</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/football">Sepp Blatter</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/football">Football</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/sport">Sport</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/football">World Cup 2022</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Qatar</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:06:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/football/2013/nov/20/fifa-qatar-world-cup-sepp-blatter</guid><dc:creator>Owen Gibson</dc:creator><dc:subject>Football</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:46:36Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422981638</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Sepp Blatter, Fifa, World Cup 2022, Football, Qatar, Sport</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Football/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384969719156/FIFA-President-Sepp-Blatt-006.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Arnd Wiegmann/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Fifa's president Sepp Blatter admitted that workers on Qatar's 2022 World Cup projects face 'unacceptable' conditions. Photograph: Arnd Wiegmann/Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Football/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384969725874/FIFA-President-Sepp-Blatt-011.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Arnd Wiegmann/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Fifa's president, Sepp Blatter, admitted that abuse of workers on Qatar's 2022 World Cup infrastructure was 'unacceptable'. Photograph: Arnd Wiegmann/Reuters</media:description></media:content></item><item><title>US and UK struck secret data pact</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9c3d2/sc/11/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Cus0Euk0Esecret0Edeal0Esurveillance0Epersonal0Edata/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/31369?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aus-uk-secret-deal-surveillance-personal-data%3A2000543&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=NSA+files%2CNSA%2CSurveillance+%28News%29%2CPrivacy+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CUS+foreign+policy%2CUK+news%2CCanada+%28News%29%2CNew+Zealand+%28News%29%2CAustralia+%28News%29%2CUS+news%2CData+protection+%28Govt.%2Findustrial+use+of+data%29%2CTechnology%2CGCHQ+%28News%29&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CTechnology+Gadgets%2CNorth+America+Travel&amp;c6=James+Ball&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+07%3A00&amp;c8=2000543&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=US&amp;c65=US+and+UK+struck+secret+deal+to+allow+NSA+to+%27unmask%27+Britons%27+personal+data&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FThe+NSA+files" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;• 2007 deal allows NSA to store previously restricted material&lt;br /&gt;• UK citizens not suspected of wrongdoing caught up in dragnet&lt;br /&gt;• Separate draft memo proposes US spying on 'Five-Eyes' allies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The phone, internet and email records of UK citizens not suspected of any wrongdoing have been analysed and stored by America's National Security Agency under a secret deal that was approved by British intelligence officials, according to documents from the whistleblower Edward Snowden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first explicit confirmation that UK citizens have been caught up in US mass surveillance programs, an NSA memo describes how in 2007 an agreement was reached that allowed the agency to "unmask" and hold on to personal data about Britons that had previously been off limits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The memo, published in a joint investigation by the Guardian &lt;a href="http://www.channel4.com/news/nsa-edward-snowden-america-britain-tony-blair"&gt;and Britain's Channel 4 News&lt;/a&gt;, says the material is being put in databases where it can be made available to other members of the US intelligence and military community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Britain and the US are the main two partners in the 'Five-Eyes' intelligence-sharing alliance, which also includes Australia, New Zealand and Canada. Until now, it had been generally understood that the citizens of each country were protected from surveillance by any of the others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the Snowden material reveals that:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• In 2007, the rules were changed to allow the NSA to analyse and retain any British citizens' mobile phone and fax numbers, emails and IP addresses swept up by its dragnet. Previously, this data had been stripped out of NSA databases – "minimized", in intelligence agency parlance – under rules agreed between the two countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• These communications were "incidentally collected" by the NSA, meaning the individuals were not the initial targets of surveillance operations and therefore were not suspected of wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The NSA has been using the UK data to conduct so-called "pattern of life" or "contact-chaining" analyses, under which the agency can look up to three "hops" away from a target of interest – examining the communications of a friend of a friend of a friend. &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/interactive/2013/oct/28/nsa-files-decoded-hops"&gt;Guardian analysis suggests&lt;/a&gt; three hops for a typical Facebook user could pull the data of more than 5 million people into the dragnet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• A separate draft memo, marked top-secret and dated from 2005, reveals a proposed NSA procedure for spying on the citizens of the UK and other Five-Eyes nations, even where the partner government has explicitly denied the US permission to do so. The memo makes clear that partner countries must not be informed about this surveillance, or even the procedure itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2007 briefing was sent out to all analysts in the NSA's Signals Intelligence Directorate (SID), which is responsible for collecting, processing, and sharing information gleaned from US surveillance programs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up to this point, the Americans had only been allowed to retain the details of British landline phone numbers that had been collected incidentally in any of their trawls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the memo explains there was a fundamental change in policy that allowed the US to look at and store vast amounts of personal data that would previously have been discarded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It states: "Sigint [signals intelligence] policy … and the UK Liaison Office here at NSAW [NSA Washington] worked together to come up with a new policy that expands the use of incidentally collected unminimized UK data in Sigint analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The new policy expands the previous memo issued in 2004 that only allowed the unminimizing of incidentally collected UK phone numbers for use in analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Now SID analysts can unminimize all incidentally collected UK contact identifiers, including IP and email addresses, fax and cell phone numbers, for use in analysis."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The memo also set out in more detail what the NSA could and could not do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The agency was, for example, still barred from making any UK citizen a target of surveillance programs that would look at the content of their communications without getting a warrant. However, they now:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• "Are authorized to unmask UK contact identifiers resulting from incidental collection."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• "May utilize the UK contact identifiers in Sigint development contact chaining analysis."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• "May retain unminimized UK contact identifiers incidentally collected under this authority within content and metadata stores and provided to follow-on USSS (US Sigint System) applications."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The document does not say whether the UK Liaison Office, which is operated by GCHQ, discussed this rule change with government ministers in London before granting approval, nor who within the intelligence agencies would have been responsible for the decision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Guardian contacted GCHQ and the Cabinet Office on Thursday November 7 to ask for clarification, but despite repeated requests since then, neither has been prepared to comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the signing in 1946 of the UKUSA Signals Intelligence Agreement, which first established the Five-Eyes partnership, it has been a convention that the allied intelligence agencies do not monitor one another's citizens without permission – an agreement often referred to publicly by officials across the Five-Eyes nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, a draft 2005 directive in the name of the NSA's director of signals intelligence reveals the NSA prepared policies enabling its staff to spy on Five-Eyes citizens, even where the partner country has refused permission to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The document, titled 'Collection, Processing and Dissemination of Allied Communications', has separate classifications from paragraph to paragraph. Some are cleared to be shared with America's allies, while others – marked "NF", for No Foreign – are to be kept strictly within the agency. The NSA refers to its Five-Eyes partners as "second party" countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The memo states that the Five-Eyes agreement "has evolved to include a common understanding that both governments will not target each other's citizens/persons".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the next sentence – classified as not to be shared with foreign partners – states that governments "reserved the right" to conduct intelligence operations against each other's citizens "when it is in the best interests of each nation".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Therefore," the draft memo continues, "under certain circumstances, it may be advisable and allowable to target second party persons and second party communications systems unilaterally, when it is in the best interests of the US and necessary for US national security."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The draft directive states who can approve the surveillance, and stresses the need for secrecy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"When sharing the planned targeting information with a second party would be contrary to US interests, or when the second party declines a collaboration proposal, the proposed targeting must be presented to the signals intelligence director for approval with justification for the criticality of the proposed collection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"If approved, any collection, processing and dissemination of the second party information must be maintained in NoForn channels."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The document does not reveal whether such operations had been authorized in the past, nor whether the NSA believes its Five-Eyes partners conduct operations against US citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other sections of the document, cleared for sharing with the UK and other partners, strike a different tone, emphasising that spying on each other's citizens is a collaborative affair that is most commonly achieved "when the proposed target is associated with a global problem such as weapons proliferation, terrorism, drug trafficking or organised crime activities."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It states, for example: "There are circumstances when targeting of second party persons and communications systems, with the full knowledge and co-operation of one or more second parties, is allowed when it is in the best interests of both nations."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The memo says the circumstances might include "targeting a UK citizen located in London using a British telephone system"; "targeting a UK person located in London using an internet service provider (ISP) in France; or "targeting a Pakistani person located in the UK using a UK ISP."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A spokeswoman for the NSA declined to answer questions from the Guardian on whether the draft directive had been implemented and, if so, when. The NSA and the White House also refused to comment on the agency's 2007 agreement with the UK to store and analyze data on British citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The British foreign secretary in 2005 was Jack Straw, and in 2007 it was Margaret Beckett. The Guardian approached both of them to ask if they knew about or sanctioned a change in policy. Both declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Five-Eyes nations have, so far, steered clear of the diplomatic upheavals, which have emerged as a result of revelations of the NSA spying on its allies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;France, Germany and Spain have all recently summoned their respective US ambassadors to discuss surveillance within their borders, while earlier this month the UK ambassador to Germany was invited to discuss alleged eavesdropping from the UK embassy in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/the-nsa-files"&gt;The NSA files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/nsa"&gt;NSA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/surveillance"&gt;Surveillance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/privacy"&gt;Privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/usforeignpolicy"&gt;US foreign policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/canada"&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/newzealand"&gt;New Zealand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/australia"&gt;Australia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/data-protection"&gt;Data protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/uk/gchq"&gt;GCHQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/profile/jamesball"&gt;James Ball&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e9c3d2/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/technology">Data protection</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">theguardian.com</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Privacy</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">US foreign policy</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">The NSA files</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/technology">Technology</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">NSA</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Surveillance</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Canada</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">New Zealand</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Australia</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:00:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/20/us-uk-secret-deal-surveillance-personal-data</guid><dc:creator>James Ball</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:09:04Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422973785</dc:identifier><media:keywords>The NSA files, NSA, Surveillance, Privacy, World news, US foreign policy, UK news, Canada, New Zealand, Australia, United States, Data protection, Technology, GCHQ</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/9/30/1380555063863/NSA-internet-network-cabl-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Felix Clay/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>NSA internet network cable. Photograph: Felix Clay for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="252" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/11/20/1384967660378/nsatear1460-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Guardian</media:credit><media:description>The memo explains that the US and UK 'worked together to come up with a new policy that expands the use of incidentally collected unminimized UK data.'</media:description></media:content><media:content height="497" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="900" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/11/20/1384967623196/nsatear900-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Guardian</media:credit></media:content><media:content height="309" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/11/20/1384967779141/nsatear2-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Guardian</media:credit></media:content><media:content height="180" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/11/20/1384967830162/NSAtear4-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Guardian</media:credit></media:content><media:content height="152" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/11/20/1384967804851/NSAtear3-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Guardian</media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Italian justice minister survives no-confidence vote</title><link>http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e94e90/sc/11/l/0L0Stheguardian0N0Cworld0C20A130Cnov0C20A0Citalian0Ejustice0Eminister0Econfidence0Evote/story01.htm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.theguardian.com/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.5/76324?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Article%3Aitalian-justice-minister-confidence-vote%3A2000688&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Italy+%28News%29%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Associated+Press+in+Rome&amp;c7=2013%2F11%2F20+06%3A41&amp;c8=2000688&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c64=UK&amp;c65=Italian+justice+minister+survives+no-confidence+vote&amp;c66=News&amp;c67=nextgen-compatible&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FItaly" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Anna Maria Cancellieri tells parliament she did not pull any strings to win release of family friend from jail&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Italy's justice minister survived a no-confidence vote on Wednesday after insisting she did not abuse her position to win the release of a family friend from jail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anna Maria Cancellieri has been under pressure to resign following revelations that she called court officials to tell them the friend, Giulia Lingresti, was in ill health. Cancellieri also acknowledges calling Lingresti's companion to express sympathy after her arrest for alleged false accounting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cancellieri has said she regrets the phone calls, but told parliament before Wednesday's vote that she had not pulled strings to win Lingresti's release. "There was no undue zeal or anomalies," she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cancellieri survived the vote by 405-154. She has the backing of the president, Giorgio Napolitano, and the prime minister, Enrico Letta, who sought to ensure centre-left MPs' support of Cancellieri by linking the confidence vote to the survival of his government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The motion was brought by the anti-establishment 5 Star Movement founded by the former comic Beppe Grillo, and had divided Letta's Democratic party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ligresti is the daughter of Salvatore Ligresti, an insurance magnate who is under house arrest on charges of false accounting and market manipulation. Cancellieri is a long-time friend of the Ligresti family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cancellieri said she called prison officials on 19 August, about a month after Giulia Lingresti was placed in pre-trial custody, to pass along information about the woman's health. But, Cancellieri said, "the situation was already known to the judges and the penitentiary officials". Ligresti was released to house arrest on 28 August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turin prosecutors have said they will not investigate Cancellieri for any wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/italy"&gt;Italy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com"&gt;theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.theguardian.com/c/34708/f/663879/s/33e94e90/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/sc/11/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/sc/11/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/sc/11/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/sc/11/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/sc/11/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/sc/11/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264584270/u/0/f/663879/c/34708/s/33e94e90/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.theguardian.com/world">Italy</category><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 18:41:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/nov/20/italian-justice-minister-confidence-vote</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-11-21T00:05:31Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>422986992</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Italy, Europe, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384972823693/Anna-Maria-Cancellieri-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Max Rossi/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Anna Maria Cancellieri, Italy's justice minister. Photograph: Max Rossi/Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/11/20/1384972830079/Anna-Maria-Cancellieri-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Max Rossi/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Anna Maria Cancellieri, Italy's justice minister. Photograph: Max Rossi/Reuters</media:description></media:content></item></channel></rss>
